<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>How to participate in the OGM Marketplace</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-participate-in-the-ogm-marketplace/348</link>
    <description>Welcome! **OGM Marketplace** is a place for OGM members to exchange goods and services, either for pay or for other consideration (including gratitude :slight_smile:).

The Marketplace is an experiment, starting in November 2020.  We&#39;ll see how it goes.  Please know that we may have to adjust how it works. You&#39;re invited to help!

Basically, though, if there is something you need, **create a new topic** in the [Goods Needed](https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/goods-needed/31) or [Help Needed](https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/help-needed/33) categories.  Or, if you have something to offer, **create a new topic**  in [Goods Offered](https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/goods-offered/32) or [Help Offered](https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/help-offered/34) categories.

Likewise, please feel free to go &quot;shopping&quot; in the any of the Marketplace categories.

When you&#39;ve had an interaction go well, post about your experience in [Reviews and Ratings](https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/reviews-and-ratings/35).  The more we talk about how the marketplace is working, the better it will be for everyone.

If you had an interaction that wasn&#39;t great, try resolving the problem in good faith first, and see &quot;Problem Resolution&quot; below.  After that, if you feel you must, post about your experience in &quot;Reviews and Ratings.&quot;  Remember that a bad experience with someone else reflects on you, too, not just on them.

## Ground Rules

* Be fair. Be nice. Be of good intent.
* Obey any and all laws that apply to you and your activities.
* If you have a problem or question you can&#39;t handle, ping @peterkaminski or @Jerry.
* Nobody likes a stale marketplace. It&#39;s expected that posts will be archived to an archive category after about a month.  It will be okay to repost to the live category, but consider what you might need to change or do differently so the request or offer succeeds instead of aging out.

## Payments and Deliveries

Handle payments and delivery of goods/services with the other party.  At this time, OGM doesn&#39;t handle or settle any payments, deliveries, or payment or delivery issues.

It&#39;s hoped that some day we&#39;ll have a [community currency](https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/community-payments-systems/352) to use in the Marketplace, but we don&#39;t yet.

## Problem Resolution

Work with the other party in good faith **first**.  Ask a friend or someone in the community to help.  If you still need help, ping @peterkaminski or @Jerry.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 19:13:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Using the Marketplace</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-participate-in-the-ogm-marketplace/348.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>How to participate in the OGM Marketplace</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Welcome! <strong>OGM Marketplace</strong> is a place for OGM members to exchange goods and services, either for pay or for other consideration (including gratitude <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:">).</p>
<p>The Marketplace is an experiment, starting in November 2020.  We’ll see how it goes.  Please know that we may have to adjust how it works. You’re invited to help!</p>
<p>Basically, though, if there is something you need, <strong>create a new topic</strong> in the <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/goods-needed/31">Goods Needed</a> or <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/help-needed/33">Help Needed</a> categories.  Or, if you have something to offer, <strong>create a new topic</strong>  in <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/goods-offered/32">Goods Offered</a> or <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/help-offered/34">Help Offered</a> categories.</p>
<p>Likewise, please feel free to go “shopping” in the any of the Marketplace categories.</p>
<p>When you’ve had an interaction go well, post about your experience in <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/ogm-marketplace/reviews-and-ratings/35">Reviews and Ratings</a>.  The more we talk about how the marketplace is working, the better it will be for everyone.</p>
<p>If you had an interaction that wasn’t great, try resolving the problem in good faith first, and see “Problem Resolution” below.  After that, if you feel you must, post about your experience in “Reviews and Ratings.”  Remember that a bad experience with someone else reflects on you, too, not just on them.</p>
<h2>Ground Rules</h2>
<ul>
<li>Be fair. Be nice. Be of good intent.</li>
<li>Obey any and all laws that apply to you and your activities.</li>
<li>If you have a problem or question you can’t handle, ping <a class="mention" href="/u/peterkaminski">@peterkaminski</a> or <a class="mention" href="/u/jerry">@Jerry</a>.</li>
<li>Nobody likes a stale marketplace. It’s expected that posts will be archived to an archive category after about a month.  It will be okay to repost to the live category, but consider what you might need to change or do differently so the request or offer succeeds instead of aging out.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Payments and Deliveries</h2>
<p>Handle payments and delivery of goods/services with the other party.  At this time, OGM doesn’t handle or settle any payments, deliveries, or payment or delivery issues.</p>
<p>It’s hoped that some day we’ll have a <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/community-payments-systems/352">community currency</a> to use in the Marketplace, but we don’t yet.</p>
<h2>Problem Resolution</h2>
<p>Work with the other party in good faith <strong>first</strong>.  Ask a friend or someone in the community to help.  If you still need help, ping <a class="mention" href="/u/peterkaminski">@peterkaminski</a> or <a class="mention" href="/u/jerry">@Jerry</a>.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-participate-in-the-ogm-marketplace/348/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-participate-in-the-ogm-marketplace/348/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 16:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-348-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-participate-in-the-ogm-marketplace/348.rss">How to participate in the OGM Marketplace</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
