<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Inside the Beltway</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inside-the-beltway/500</link>
    <description>As many of you know, I work in and around the Federal government, so I will try to post news and things of interest here.

Probably the most impactful and least understood process is the Budget, I myself am only a novice after 25 years!

While the President&#39;s office makes a budget, it is more advisory and Congress takes it for input. There are different committees in the House and Senate that work on different aspects. 

Here is one good resource:
[Budget of the U.S. Government | USAGov](https://www.usa.gov/budget)

Different parts of the government are funded under different laws and they always have &quot;interesting&quot; names. The Defense budget is the *National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA) for FY2021*. Of course the Federal Fiscal Year for 2021 started in Oct 2020, so how is that possible that the government is running without a passed budget? They pass &quot;Continuing Resolutions&quot;. There was one that ran out Dec 11. Then they passed a 7 day which went to Dec 18 (Friday). Then they passed a two day to Sunday and another one day through today.

All the headlines were about the details of the $900 Billion relief package but no one even looks at the $1.4 Trillion budget, totally **$2.3 Trillion**.

It seems OGM could solve health, soil, and social justice with 2.3 Trillion USD!!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 01:00:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Knowledge Areas</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inside-the-beltway/500.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Inside the Beltway</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[RobOK]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>As many of you know, I work in and around the Federal government, so I will try to post news and things of interest here.</p>
<p>Probably the most impactful and least understood process is the Budget, I myself am only a novice after 25 years!</p>
<p>While the President’s office makes a budget, it is more advisory and Congress takes it for input. There are different committees in the House and Senate that work on different aspects.</p>
<p>Here is one good resource:<br>
<a href="https://www.usa.gov/budget">Budget of the U.S. Government | USAGov</a></p>
<p>Different parts of the government are funded under different laws and they always have “interesting” names. The Defense budget is the <em>National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA) for FY2021</em>. Of course the Federal Fiscal Year for 2021 started in Oct 2020, so how is that possible that the government is running without a passed budget? They pass “Continuing Resolutions”. There was one that ran out Dec 11. Then they passed a 7 day which went to Dec 18 (Friday). Then they passed a two day to Sunday and another one day through today.</p>
<p>All the headlines were about the details of the $900 Billion relief package but no one even looks at the $1.4 Trillion budget, totally <strong>$2.3 Trillion</strong>.</p>
<p>It seems OGM could solve health, soil, and social justice with 2.3 Trillion USD!!</p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inside-the-beltway/500/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inside-the-beltway/500/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 01:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-500-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inside-the-beltway/500.rss">Inside the Beltway</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
