<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Redesigning Everything - Open Global Mind Forum</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/actions-discussions/redesigning-everything/22</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Redesigning Everything&#39; category </description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 04:10:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/actions-discussions/redesigning-everything/22.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>The Environment and Education</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[GlennMII]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Redesigning Everything</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’d like to share something. I’ll try to be concise, which is a massive challenge for me. My two passions are the environment and education. We can’t live without the former, and we can’t save the planet (or ourselves) without vastly improving the latter. Our current economic, governance and political systems are not geared towards saving the environment or improving education except in the very specific ways in which it benefits businesses, often at the expense of the students, yet we keep voting the same people into office again and again, often with a choice of just 1 or 2 candidates from the same two parties that don’t really have our backs.<br>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/dcd2334f539da5c2307319a6807d8f4152b131b2.jpeg" data-download-href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/dcd2334f539da5c2307319a6807d8f4152b131b2" title="beautiful, lush scenery in the hills"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dcd2334f539da5c2307319a6807d8f4152b131b2_2_690x456.jpeg" alt="beautiful, lush scenery in the hills" data-base62-sha1="vvtoxC46bo0hMO8B8YyWByo24Om" width="690" height="456" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dcd2334f539da5c2307319a6807d8f4152b131b2_2_690x456.jpeg, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dcd2334f539da5c2307319a6807d8f4152b131b2_2_1035x684.jpeg 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/dcd2334f539da5c2307319a6807d8f4152b131b2.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dcd2334f539da5c2307319a6807d8f4152b131b2_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">beautiful, lush scenery in the hills</span><span class="informations">1280×846 290 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div></p>
<h1>Climate Change Disinformation</h1>
<p>For decades now, special interest groups, foundations, lobbyists, and ultra-rich individuals have worked to undermine the results of the scientific community by spreading false information about those results, to the point that people actually still question. There is no need for the question “Is it real?” - anthropomorphic climate change is undeniably real despite the dark money thrown at it to pull the plug on efforts to fix the environment - there are only questions like: “How much influence do our actions have on it?” and “What will be the most effective ways to turn the situation around?”</p>
<h1>Greenhouse Gases</h1>
<p>Don’t just talk about CO2 - it’s only a portion of the problem, along with methane (CH4), nitrous oxide (N2O) and water vapor. Together, the <a>greenhouse gases</a> we produce have continued to increase (but, perhaps NOT strangely, consumption of carbonated beverages hasn’t, and solutions haven’t been implemented in an effective, widespread way) in volume have caused the size and temperature of the band of heat across the globe to increase in size, which is altering not just weather patterns but also altering regional climates and the oceans, too. This almost entirely singular focus on climate change by CO2 isn’t helping - it has become an excuse.</p>
<h1>Coral Reefs</h1>
<p>I’ve had the fortune to do a bit of scuba diving and seen both dead and living coral reefs. This video will take you there and show you the wonder, and the sheer tragedy, that is unfolding, largely unknown, and has a major impact on not just the coral but all the creatures that depend on that ecosystem. Within the past several years, coral bleaching events have increased in frequency and scope, resulting in at least 50% of the coral reefs dying worldwide. Most of the Great Barrier Reef is now dead. That may not sound important, but you have to understand that reefs form the structure of complex ecosystems that, when the coral is dead, collapse. This means natural breakwaters fall apart, allowing your coastline to eventually be destroyed by the rough sea the reef used to protect you from, as well as the damage to adjacent ecosystems, and then there’s the risk of land inundation by those big waves. There’s also the fact that some fishing and pet animal industries rely on the reefs for what LIVES in the reefs, including selling corals, sponges and gorgons. Coral reefs also serve a function in sequestering carbon dioxide and producing oxygen, while simultaneously suppressing algae growth by eating it.<br>
</p><div class="onebox lazyYT lazyYT-container" data-youtube-id="aGGBGcjdjXA" data-youtube-title="Chasing Coral | FULL FEATURE | Netflix" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque">
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aGGBGcjdjXA" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">
    <img class="ytp-thumbnail-image" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/6ca161c51503ed1c1ca4b43e001f66486743e749.jpeg" title="Chasing Coral | FULL FEATURE | Netflix" width="690" height="388">
  </a>
</div>

<h1>The Big Challenges</h1>
<p>These are my “big issues.”</p>
<ul>
<li>I don’t see any real effort to decrease greenhouse gas emissions, and politicians at the highest levels are free to refuse to cooperate, like Trump did, even rolling back initiatives by previous president and pulling out of climate accords.</li>
<li>Deforestation deprives animals of homes, humans of new medicines, the world of oxygen and biodiversity, and other benefits, including protection from desertification (before which is the loss of the topsoil by sterilization and/or erosion) and the production of localized fog/precipitation.<br>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/deb91e007937db46fd5e66ce478fdeb09e9894c2.jpeg" data-download-href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/deb91e007937db46fd5e66ce478fdeb09e9894c2" title="grasslands turning into dead, cracked land"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/deb91e007937db46fd5e66ce478fdeb09e9894c2_2_666x500.jpeg" alt="grasslands turning into dead, cracked land" data-base62-sha1="vMiBPBNH0sFjFWpCezD1fL7Gqsi" width="666" height="500" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/deb91e007937db46fd5e66ce478fdeb09e9894c2_2_666x500.jpeg, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/deb91e007937db46fd5e66ce478fdeb09e9894c2_2_999x750.jpeg 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/deb91e007937db46fd5e66ce478fdeb09e9894c2.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/deb91e007937db46fd5e66ce478fdeb09e9894c2_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">grasslands turning into dead, cracked land</span><span class="informations">1280×960 594 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div>
</li>
<li>Oceanic degradation, including:
<ul>
<li>rising temperatures resulting in coral bleaching, deprive animals of homes, humans of new medicines, the world of oxygen, and other benefits;</li>
<li>the decrease in the availability of plankton and other creatures (like coral) that convert far more CO2 to oxygen than do plants;</li>
<li>run-off into the oceans and seas, primarily from deforestation and agriculture, is creating huge dead zones where dangerous algal and jellyfish blooms are replacing the once verdant array of ecosystems;</li>
<li>overfishing is causing the populations of fish, sharks, cetaceans, and turtles to be in great danger of collapse, if not extinction;</li>
<li>dredging destroys seabed ecosystems;</li>
<li>pollution (including plastics) and excessive land erosion kills off marine life, among other things;<br>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/f2907ee0f761a962a8327bc9a4dcc85a71490b25.jpeg" data-download-href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/f2907ee0f761a962a8327bc9a4dcc85a71490b25" title="bust of person in hazmat gas mask in front of air pollution sources"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/f2907ee0f761a962a8327bc9a4dcc85a71490b25_2_690x446.jpeg" alt="bust of person in hazmat gas mask in front of air pollution sources" data-base62-sha1="yBP7X8qUlgdKb9v3A3lL8NB64eN" width="690" height="446" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/f2907ee0f761a962a8327bc9a4dcc85a71490b25_2_690x446.jpeg, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/f2907ee0f761a962a8327bc9a4dcc85a71490b25_2_1035x669.jpeg 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/f2907ee0f761a962a8327bc9a4dcc85a71490b25.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/f2907ee0f761a962a8327bc9a4dcc85a71490b25_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">bust of person in hazmat gas mask in front of air pollution sources</span><span class="informations">1280×828 190 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div>
</li>
<li>land and coastal waters repurposing engineers and destroys valuable things like deltas, marshes, coral reefs, beds of kelp, fish and shellfish, and swamps into usable land while depriving the ecosystem of not just flora and fauna but a living “organ” that serves a vital function for the health of both the land and water in that area, while also impacting the people who rely most on those ecosystems being healthy; etc.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Pollution (air, land, water, biological, radioactive, light, sound, etc.) contributes to a whole host of problems, including:
<ul>
<li>constant exposure to contaminants, especially through food, the air, and water;</li>
<li>deforestation and ocean degradation, as well as the loss of living creatures and even entire species (especially if it exists in only one area);</li>
<li>decreased nutrition requiring more consumption; poorer sleeping patterns;</li>
<li>decreased crop yields;</li>
<li>decreased availability of clean water, land and air;</li>
<li>health issues like mutations, declining birth rates, increasing mortality, increases in asthma, allergies in general and to foods in specific; and more.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Food and food systems
<ul>
<li>are highly driven by profit, with fewer and fewer small farms and ranches and lots of massive, industrial companies taking everything to a higher level to increase production while squeezing the actual; producers on price;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>create a lot of waste (some countries waste in excess of half of all its food);</li>
<li>require a lot of resources, especially when we talk about animal products;</li>
<li>pollute (runoff, pesticides, herbicides, fungicides, noise, light, air, water and land);</li>
<li>potentially cause negative changes to a food source (via GMO)</li>
<li>damage health (diabetes, strokes, heart disease, hypertension and others are amongst the top killers, as well as food allergies, asthmatic reactions to pesticides, etc.);</li>
<li>create insecurity and stress (food deserts, lack of income to buy good food - “one little apple or one big bag of chips?”, lack of healthful choices, etc.);</li>
<li>preference of flavor over healthfulness, environmental degradation, ecosystems destruction, climatic changes, etc.</li>
<li>Climatic changes that include:
<ul>
<li>shifting weather patterns and even seasons;</li>
<li>unreliable rainfall (increase, decrease or shift);</li>
<li>higher local temperatures (urban heat islands resulting in more usage of energy to stay cool);<br>
<img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/cde9cf056c422f47524c8126300f3db317ece8b6.jpeg" alt="urban heat island effect graph" data-base62-sha1="tnAOtRHCR5llhz4j5yaudWDWAXY" width="650" height="427">
</li>
<li>increases in dangerous weather patterns;</li>
<li>changes in global air and water currents; etc.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Education continues to inadequately impress upon the youth of the world the importance of a healthy planet and, thus, a healthy local ecosystem. Cultures resist changes of bad habits (such as pooing and peeing in fish ponds or near clean water sources), giving the ages-old "It’s what we’ve always done. We’re fine. There’s nothing to change here and it’s odd, besides, to do it differently! This is only one aspect of what’s wrong with education, which would require a lot more writing.</li>
<li>Economics focused solely on the profit margin is increasingly driving businesses and countries in the direction that is OPPOSITE that which is necessary for long-term survival. Hyper-competition for market share, domination, and larger profits for companies and their investors throw not just employees under the bus, but also entire societies; mental and physical health; social structures that create a cohesive, supportive community; ecosystems; and, sometimes, countries, among others. In addition, this is pushing us more and more into the dystopian future of businesses overwhelming most (or all) governments. The economic demand for constant growth (the WTO’s policies) will make the planet’s death happen faster.<br>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/670014f2e3b1278a7a6eab6ac54489dfdc8d3b6a.jpeg" data-download-href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/670014f2e3b1278a7a6eab6ac54489dfdc8d3b6a" title="stock market shares chart with a climbing arrow, superimposed over a man standing and reading"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/670014f2e3b1278a7a6eab6ac54489dfdc8d3b6a_2_690x487.jpeg" alt="stock market shares chart with a climbing arrow, superimposed over a man standing and reading" data-base62-sha1="eHblZLIysuU1XMqmvHiYXoORwjo" width="690" height="487" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/670014f2e3b1278a7a6eab6ac54489dfdc8d3b6a_2_690x487.jpeg, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/670014f2e3b1278a7a6eab6ac54489dfdc8d3b6a_2_1035x730.jpeg 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/670014f2e3b1278a7a6eab6ac54489dfdc8d3b6a.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/670014f2e3b1278a7a6eab6ac54489dfdc8d3b6a_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">stock market shares chart with a climbing arrow, superimposed over a man standing and reading</span><span class="informations">1280×905 259 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div>
</li>
</ul>
<p>It is not enough to talk about CO2 trading, which largely benefits those who use it as a commodity to get rich. It is not enough, even, to talk about greenhouse gases. We must also make substantive and immediate changes to the way we make decisions and live. Too much freedom has major negative consequences and too few people understand, are educated enough to sort through all the lies to find the truth, and are ABLE financially to make a difference.  This means that financial safety is important so that people can focus more on how to preserve the planet that we all depend on.</p>
<p>We influence the environment AND climate because of the massive scale on which we work. Physics and maths both stand behind the idea that anthropomorphic climate change is real. If you’re trapped in an elevator for long enough, you’ll notice a change. Go to an expo when it’s empty and icy-cold because the ACs are running in the summertime, then see how hot it becomes when the expo is jam-packed. Pee in your swimming pool and you’ll feel a difference, too! <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/wink.png?v=9" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<p>We are the problem. In the past 13 years since Gore put out his hyperfocused but very awakening video, the changes we’ve made have mostly been superficial.</p>
<ul>
<li>Renewable energies cannot replace coal and gas, except nuclear. They are simply too costly and break down too quickly to be viable, plus most only work in certain areas.
<ul>
<li>Solar only works where there’s enough light each day, which is to say the part of the Earth that is near the Arctic and Antarctic have a negative energy production rate compared to those near the equator.</li>
<li>Wind only works where there is sufficient wind and many people don’t like to see them, so they have to be isolated but, preferably, not where birds migrate.</li>
<li>Hydro only works where there is a flow or tide, and damming causes a lot of ecological problems (see the loss of several species of salmon in the US as an example).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Major human sources of greenhouse gases have not been abated.</li>
<li>Deforestation in major rainforests from Brazil to Indonesia has gotten worse.</li>
<li>Plastic islands in the oceans, coastal dead zones, species loss are all getting worse</li>
</ul>
<p>Before I spend the next hour making a super-long list, I’d better stop myself! <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>We need smaller populations with stable economies, not larger ones economists insist on for economic growth. It is lunacy to think that the policies of the World Trade Organization (the WHO) will benefit the masses or the planet. The SARS-CoV-2 pandemic (it is NOT a CoViD-19 pandemic, that’s just the disease) has amply demonstrated how places are too dependent on tourism, the hospitality industry, and certain other industries to be sustainable in a crisis.</p>
<p>I suggest that the changes need to be social, environmental, economic and political (both governing systems and political ones), and the fastest way to make changes to those is through the global renovation of education. Would it sound right if I suggest that each of those 5 spheres will need their own think tanks and scientific/expert communities run on merit and kindness instead of diplomacy, connected with the overall goal of improving the future of humanity and the planet, by finding the best solutions for the problems, now and in the future, and then using education and media to broadcast it throughout the world?</p>
<p>I am very open to feedback because I have huge blind spots.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-environment-and-education/381">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-environment-and-education/381</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 04:10:09 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-381</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-environment-and-education/381.rss">The Environment and Education</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>QAnon as Alternate Reality Game</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Redesigning Everything</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>“An alternate reality game (ARG) is an interactive networked narrative that uses the real world as a platform and employs transmedia storytelling to deliver a story that may be altered by players’ ideas or actions.”</p>
<p>(There’s more interesting stuff to it, I recommend the whole “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alternate_reality_game">Alternate reality game</a>” Wikipedia article.)</p>
<p>People in the ARG community (Adrian and Dan Hon, and others in comments) note that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QAnon">QAnon</a> works like, or is, an ARG, perhaps a wild/unintentional one, perhaps not.</p>
<p>There’s some interesting (terrifying) confluence of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meme#Origins">Dawkins memetics</a>, <a href="https://mud.co.uk/richard/hcds.htm">Bartle player types</a>, cults, and dopamine cycles (particularly during the ennui/powerlessness of rise of fascist authoritarianism (and global pandemic!)).</p>
<p>One of the ARG folks’ concerns is that is “<a href="https://twitter.com/hondanhon/status/1281686386102263810">uncontrolled, undirected and unconstrained</a>” and starting to cross over into the real world (people getting elected, killed, etc.)  In controlled ARGs, they have noted the need to <a href="https://twitter.com/hondanhon/status/1281695294413918208">aggressively tamp down rogue actions by players</a>.</p>
<p>A key innovation (or mutation) of QAnon-as-ARG is that user-generated content, not just gamemaster-generated content, can become canon: “But <a href="https://twitter.com/hondanhon/status/1281696152119701504">QAnon ‘solved’ it by being able to co-opt all content</a> that already exists and, like I say above, encourages and allows you to *create <a href="https://twitter.com/hondanhon/status/1281699116846731264">new content* that counts and is fair play in-the-game</a>.”</p>
<p>This means that, unlike a regular ARG, it doesn’t consume all the game content and burn out; it just keeps growing.</p>
<p>In discussion, the ARG folks talk about the potential for co-opting or countering QAnon-as-ARG, with more ARG engineering.</p>
<p>I wonder, have the Hon brothers unintentionally created a meta-ARG, with the topic, “QAnon is an ARG”?</p>
<p>Other tweets from the conversation:</p>
<p>“<a href="https://twitter.com/harrisonpartch/status/1281937408846639104">Borges predicted this in a story.</a>”</p>
<p>“<a href="https://twitter.com/georgebaily/status/1281916053250023424">Connects with this idea of funnel/gravity-wells…</a>”</p>
<p>“<a href="https://twitter.com/ukieluke/status/1281891744624381952">Particularly insightful into how a common medium (internet) gives rise to parallel evolution of the formats, even commonality with wikis etc.</a>”</p>
<p>‘<a href="https://twitter.com/JohnnydaMook/status/1281861479558459393">This is great. QAnon is the “League of Extraordinary Gentleman” of conspiracy theories, all the classics in one package, fan edited in real time, as competitive performance art. A hydra.</a>’</p>
<p>'<a href="https://twitter.com/typhoonjim/status/1281817675350638593">… have you <em>met</em> Ingress lore followers? That “Great Awakening Map” is at least 25% stated Ingress plot points.</a>’ (see “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ingress_(video_game)">Ingress (video game)</a>”, Wikipedia)</p>
<p>“<a href="https://twitter.com/kathrynyu/status/1281792666947076102">… a lot of the modern ARGs (particularly the smaller scale ones I’ve done that are story driven) have clear mechanisms for players to know what’s in-game vs out-of-game, written codes of conduct, and explicitly tell players what’s off-limits.</a>”</p>
<p>“<a href="https://twitter.com/vpisteve/status/1281803123560857600">Yes, ARGs should always have some sort of invisible guard rails designed in, for the safety of both the game’s integrity and player safety. The whole ‘not knowing what’s real and what’s fiction’ thing sounds so cool at first, but if taken literally it’s just irresponsible design.’</a>”</p>
<p>Adrian and Dan Hon kicking off the discussion:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1281223340431204353.html">https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1281223340431204353.html</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/adrianhon/status/1281223340431204353">https://twitter.com/adrianhon/status/1281223340431204353</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1281685535686180864.html">https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1281685535686180864.html</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/hondanhon/status/1281685535686180864">https://twitter.com/hondanhon/status/1281685535686180864</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/qanon-as-alternate-reality-game/145">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/qanon-as-alternate-reality-game/145</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 14:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-145</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/qanon-as-alternate-reality-game/145.rss">QAnon as Alternate Reality Game</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Alternate-Reality-As-A-Service: &quot;Facebook is an ARG Platform&quot;</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Redesigning Everything</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>He’s not wrong.</p>
<p>We’re still exploring Alternative Reality Games (ARG) and how they might relate to OGM.  This blog post seems like a good thing to bookmark in that quest.</p>
<p><a href="http://exple.tive.org/blarg/2020/07/30/connections/">Connections</a>, by mhoye<br>
via Adrian Hon, <a href="https://twitter.com/adrianhon/status/1291033757110210560">Smart commentary by@mhoye on ARG+QAnon, referencing Umberto Eco, Baudrillard, and even better, the Majestic ARG’s tagline</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>And with an audience already wound up in this unfiltered, overpopulated hyperreality-as-service, you barely need to do any work at all to kickstart the sort of amazing, self-sustaining paranoia-fulfillment engine that would have put the last few centuries’ foil-hatted quasi-mystic conspiriographists’ jaws right on the floor. All you need is enough people in rough proximity who feel frightened and powerless, a compelling seed crystal – the antivax fraud, the QAnon clownshow, a thousand others, it barely matters as long as it’s got a sharp hook – and this cancerous hyperculture machine pretty much bootstraps itself…</p>
</blockquote>
            <p><small>5 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/alternate-reality-as-a-service-facebook-is-an-arg-platform/130">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/alternate-reality-as-a-service-facebook-is-an-arg-platform/130</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-130</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/alternate-reality-as-a-service-facebook-is-an-arg-platform/130.rss">Alternate-Reality-As-A-Service: &quot;Facebook is an ARG Platform&quot;</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Gamifying CoCreation</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[BillSeitz]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Redesigning Everything</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>A couple weeks back <a class="mention" href="/u/peterkaminski">@peterkaminski</a> posted jerrys-reteat some twitter threads around modeling QAnon as an ARG, which I then spread to the OGM list.</p>
<p>Adrian Hon was the start of that discussion - he’s created the “Zombie, Run!” fitness ARG and multiple other ARGs, plus wrote an interesting design-fiction book.<br>
<a href="http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/HistoryOfThe21stCenturyIn100Objects" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/HistoryOfThe21stCenturyIn100Objects</a></p>
<p>I excerpted many threads into one of my pages,<br>
<a href="http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/2020-07-11-HonsQanonAsArg" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/2020-07-11-HonsQanonAsArg</a><br>
connected it to others, including an old post of Adrian’s about the shortcomings of Serious/Persuasive Games, etc., which also linked to a post of his warning against just layering gamification on top of an unchanged core activity.<br>
<a href="http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/2010-03-15-HonGamesCantChangeWorld" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/2010-03-15-HonGamesCantChangeWorld</a></p>
<p>That included an old post by Jacob Falkovich (putanumonit), which included a fascinating line:<br>
<em>Imagine if we were trying to design a Community of people devoted to cooperation, based on everything we learned about competitive and cooperative games. How should we approach this? We would build a community dedicated to creating something new, a freshly baked pie. It would have to be a long-term project. It would have an important and purely collective reward at stake, like protecting against a common tragedy (Grand Challenge, Plausible Promise). It would involve a bunch of weirdos. It would be something like transhumanism.</em><br>
<a href="http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/2017-08-29-WinningIsForLosersZeroSumGirardCollege" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/2017-08-29-WinningIsForLosersZeroSumGirardCollege</a></p>
<p>Then this weekend Adrian wrote a follow-up post which included a similar line:<br>
<em>ARGs teach us that the search for knowledge and truth can be immensely rewarding, not in spite of their deliberately-fractured stories and near-impossible puzzles, but because of them. It’s hard to create these communities. They rely on software and tools that aren’t always free or easy to use. The beauty of ARGs and ARG-like communities isn’t their power to discover truth. It’s how they make the process of discovery so deeply rewarding.</em><br>
<a href="http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/2020-08-02-HonWhatArgsCanTeachUsAboutQanon" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://webseitz.fluxent.com/wiki/2020-08-02-HonWhatArgsCanTeachUsAboutQanon</a></p>
<p>Which, combined with some other ideas, leads me to a working theory: if we can create structures that people to work together to build intrinsically interesting/meaningful bits and/or atoms, not only does humanity get that benefit of that creation, but those people get the benefit of being constructively engaged co-creators of civilization/enlightenment.</p>
<p>I have no idea how to do that.</p>
<p>But I’m connecting it to lots of other stuff… for which I have a Miro board you can view and click through to my associated wiki pages…<br>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/b8ca75b294a0fcdb02034c9c2f4c62949f9b33fa.png" data-download-href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/b8ca75b294a0fcdb02034c9c2f4c62949f9b33fa" title="Screen Shot 2020-08-03 at 7.54.49 PM"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/b8ca75b294a0fcdb02034c9c2f4c62949f9b33fa_2_690x363.png" alt="Screen Shot 2020-08-03 at 7.54.49 PM" data-base62-sha1="qmJCBeyKL3v2yaoxikutWZLTaSC" width="690" height="363" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/b8ca75b294a0fcdb02034c9c2f4c62949f9b33fa_2_690x363.png, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/b8ca75b294a0fcdb02034c9c2f4c62949f9b33fa_2_1035x544.png 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/b8ca75b294a0fcdb02034c9c2f4c62949f9b33fa_2_1380x726.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/b8ca75b294a0fcdb02034c9c2f4c62949f9b33fa_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Screen Shot 2020-08-03 at 7.54.49 PM</span><span class="informations">1710×902 75.7 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div><br>
<a href="https://miro.com/app/board/o9J_koRvp58=/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://miro.com/app/board/o9J_koRvp58=/</a></p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/gamifying-cocreation/110">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/gamifying-cocreation/110</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 01:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-110</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/gamifying-cocreation/110.rss">Gamifying CoCreation</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Alternative Medicine</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IzDraves]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Redesigning Everything</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Haupt’s newsletter affirming conspiracy theories and questioning the use of masks to prevent Covid-19 was posted to the mailing list. I replied in anger suggesting that trying to find answers to scientific questions without using science was just guessing. Jerry suggested that it can be helpful to engage all types in the hopes of resolving differences, and linking to some parts of his Brain.  We can use this topic area to discuss things like whether getting your body in tip top shape is the solution to preventing illness, whether getting sick is about bad germs or bad terrain (or a bad soul, or some evil genius’ plan to get you sick), and more.</p>
<p>I’ll start us out with this link, which suggests that we cannot interpret alternative medicine “cures” until alternative medicine is tested scientifically the way  scientific medicine is.  I liked it: <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4924574/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4924574/</a></p>
            <p><small>18 posts - 8 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/alternative-medicine/103">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/alternative-medicine/103</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 17:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-103</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/alternative-medicine/103.rss">Alternative Medicine</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About the Redesigning Everything category</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Redesigning Everything</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>(Replace this first paragraph with a brief description of your new category. This guidance will appear in the category selection area, so try to keep it below 200 characters.)</p>
<p>Use the following paragraphs for a longer description, or to establish category guidelines or rules:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Why should people use this category? What is it for?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How exactly is this different than the other categories we already have?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What should topics in this category generally contain?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do we need this category? Can we merge with another category, or subcategory?</p>
</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/about-the-redesigning-everything-category/35">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/about-the-redesigning-everything-category/35</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 05:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-35</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/about-the-redesigning-everything-category/35.rss">About the Redesigning Everything category</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
