<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Discussions and Actions - Open Global Mind Forum</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/actions-discussions/19</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Discussions and Actions&#39; category Engage in conversations and spur/organize Actions around SUBJECTS of interest such as COVID, public health, regenerative agriculture, social justice, economics, etc.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 17:44:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/actions-discussions/19.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Bigger Impact Systems Thinking</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tony]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Systems Thinking</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Donella Meadows was a great systems thinker.   Her idea of leverage points is that intervening higher level aspects of a system (goals)  has a much bigger impact than does looking at the more detail (feedback loops).</p>
<p>Data Flow Diagrams prod one through goal intervention.   Any other technique do such?</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/bigger-impact-systems-thinking/639">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/bigger-impact-systems-thinking/639</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 17:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-639</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/bigger-impact-systems-thinking/639.rss">Bigger Impact Systems Thinking</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Swiss Re Institute Report on Climate Change - Inaction is NOT an Option</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[kenhomer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Discussions and Actions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Executive summary:</p>
<p>The world stands to lose close to 10% of total economic value by mid-century if climate change stays on the currently-anticipated trajectory, and the Paris Agreement and 2050 net-zero emissions targets are not met. Many emerging markets have most to gain if the world is able to rein in temperature gains. For example, action today to get back to the Paris temperature rise scenario would mean economies in southeast Asia could prevent around a quarter of the gross domestic product (GDP) loss by mid-century that they may otherwise suffer. Our analysis in this report is unique in explicitly simulating for the many uncertainties around the impacts of climate change. It shows that those economies most vulnerable to the potential physical risks of climate change stand to benefit most from keeping temperature rises in check. This includes some of the world’s most dynamic emerging economies, the engines of global growth in the years to come. The message from the analysis is clear: no action on climate change is not an option.</p>
<p>Recent scientific research indicates that current likely temperature-rise trajectories, supported by implementation of mitigation pledges, would entail 2.0–2.6°C global warming by mid-century. We use this as the baseline to simulate the impact of rising temperatures over time, while also modelling for the uncertainties around most severe possible physical outcomes. The result is that global GDP would be 11–14% less than in a world without climate change (ie, 0°C change). Under the same no climate change comparative, the Paris target too result in negative GDP impact, but less much so (–4.2%). We also consider a severe scenario in which temperatures rise by 3.2°C by mid-century, with society doing nothing to combat climate change. In this scenario, the global economy would be 18% smaller than in a world without warming, reinforcing the imperative of, if anything, more action on climate change.</p>
<p>In terms of exposure to severe weather risks resulting from climate change, south east Asia and Latin America will likely be most susceptible to dry conditions. Many countries in north and eastern Europe, meanwhile, are set to see more excess precipitation and flood events. Combining these observations with our GDP-impact analysis, our Climate Economics Index indicates that many advanced economies in the northern hemisphere are least vulnerable to the overall effects of climate change, being both less exposed to the associated risks and better resourced to cope. The US, Canada and Germany are among the top 10 least vulnerable. Of the major economies, China ranks lower, in part due to lesser adaptive capacity in place today relative to peers. However, with rising investment in green energy and increasing awareness of climate risks, we believe China is on course for rapid catch-up here.</p>
<p>In addition to physical, climate change also gives rise to transition risks. These can show in large shifts in asset values and higher cost of doing business as the world moves to a low-carbon economy. As a separate exercise, we use carbon-tax scenario analysis as a proxy to gauge the associated financial and economic impacts. We find that earnings in the utilities, materials and energy sectors would be the most impacted and lose between 40–80% of earnings per share by immediate imposition of a global carbon tax of USD 100 per metric ton. By region, revenue-weighted earnings would fall by about a fifth in Asia Pacific, and by 15% in the Americas and Europe. The scale of loss depends on the speed at which carbon taxes and mitigation actions are implemented, and the pace of technological adoption.</p>
<p>Climate risk is a systemic risk, one that can be managed with coordinated global policy action. There exists a unique opportunity to green our economies. The public and private sectors, including insurers as providers of risk transfer capacity, risk knowledge and long-term investment, can facilitate transition to a low-carbon economy. Increasing transparency, data and disclosure to price and transfer risks is needed. To this end we should see more policy action on carbon pricing coupled with incentivising nature based and carbon-offsetting solutions. International convergence on the taxonomy on counts for green and sustainable investments is also needed. As part of corporate reporting, institutions should also disclose their roadmaps on how they intend to reach the Paris and 2050 net-zero targets.</p>
<p>Full report:<a class="attachment" href="/uploads/short-url/5n96sQ9x3ZYecCo8s4lCfftSdnx.pdf">swiss-re-institute-expertise-publication-economics-of-climate-change.pdf</a> (1.9 MB)</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/swiss-re-institute-report-on-climate-change-inaction-is-not-an-option/620">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/swiss-re-institute-report-on-climate-change-inaction-is-not-an-option/620</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 17:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-620</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/swiss-re-institute-report-on-climate-change-inaction-is-not-an-option/620.rss">Swiss Re Institute Report on Climate Change - Inaction is NOT an Option</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>An OGM Wiki: Preview &amp; Planning</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>For a while now, OGM has needed better shared memory.  I’m going to make a bold assertion and say that a good platform would be a wiki – an OGM Wiki.</p>
<p>I’ve been holding off of even really suggesting such a thing because all the wiki platforms haven’t quite fit our needs.  But together with a few others – Bill, Charles, Vincent, and Jerry – I think we’ve come up with a platform architecture that will serve OGM well.</p>
<p>It’s minimally usable now, but it will become a lot more user-friendly in a month or two.  I don’t want to focus too much on the platform yet (unless you really want to geek out with us to help make it more user-friendly!).</p>
<p>But with the platform coming together, I think it’s a good time to talk start talking about the contents and operation of the wiki itself.  What would we use a wiki for?  What teams of volunteers do we need to make it a community asset?  How would we arrange information and knowledge in a wiki?  How would an OGM wiki interface with other communities’ knowledgebases?</p>
<p>Let’s explore those and any other questions in two pop-up OGM exploration calls I will host this week:</p>
<p>Tuesday 3/16, 10:30am PDT / 1:30pm EDT / 5:30pm UTC / 6:30pm CET<br>
Wednesday 3/17, 8:00am PDT / 11:00am EDT / 3:00pm UTC / 4:00pm CET</p>
<p><a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/j/81369085502">https://us02web.zoom.us/j/81369085502</a></p>
<p>We’ll record and share the meetings.  Don’t worry if you can’t make it this time, these are early explorations, and we’ll continue to do more over the coming weeks and months.</p>
            <p><small>11 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/an-ogm-wiki-preview-planning/607">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/an-ogm-wiki-preview-planning/607</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 05:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-607</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/an-ogm-wiki-preview-planning/607.rss">An OGM Wiki: Preview &amp; Planning</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>A Good Surface Sanitizer/Cleaner: Hypochlorous Acid</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey, so I recently discovered a great cleaning product, hypochlorous acid (HOCl).  You don’t know about it because A) it’s a generic, so there’s no brand name marketing behind it, and B) it dissociates pretty quickly into water and a tiny bit of salt, so classically it’s an industrial cleaner made on site.</p>
<p>(Or maybe you know about it already, and I am only now catching up. :-))</p>
<p>Anyway, this is not a marketing pitch, nor is it professional public health and safety advice, just a pointer.</p>
<p>It’s mainly for hard, non-porous surfaces, and it’s for sanitizing/disinfecting, and for cutting light grease or things like soap film/soap scum or the pink biofilm in the shower.  It is not particularly useful for heavily soiled / bulk debris; you should rinse/wipe/wash off soil/debris, first, then use the HOCl.</p>
<p>It smells like chlorine when you spray it, but not offensively so.  (My wife and I both like it; it smells “clean.”)  It’s related to bleach (hypochlorite), but it’s different (and better for disinfecting/sanitizing).</p>
<p>It’s mostly water, and reasonably safe around people and pets.  You wouldn’t drink it or indiscriminately soak your skin in it, but it’s actually used in wound care.  It can be used on food and food-contact surfaces as a no-rinse sanitizer.</p>
<p>It is included on the US EPA List N, of sanitizers effective against SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19):</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/01b7a0a131bec15c284387613a3d69d335952615.png" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.epa.gov/pesticide-registration/list-n-advanced-search-page-disinfectants-coronavirus-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener" title="06:03PM - 13 August 2020">US EPA – 13 Aug 20</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/89fb3cb8d9a4523beaf2c238efd0d761d9b4c34c.png" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h3><a href="https://www.epa.gov/pesticide-registration/list-n-advanced-search-page-disinfectants-coronavirus-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">List N Advanced Search Page: Disinfectants for Coronavirus (COVID-19) | US EPA</a></h3>

<p>Search EPA’s list n legacy search page of registered disinfectants for use against SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes the novel coronavirus (COVID-19).&nbsp;</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>To kill SARS-CoV-2 on a surface, you spray it on the surface (even food prep or fruit/vegetable surfaces) and leave it wet for 10 minutes.</p>
<p>(I believe that public health consensus is that surface sanitization is not particularly necessary with COVID-19, because it’s mostly airborne, and you should just wash your hands more often.  We still spray all our groceries when they’re delivered.  Partly, I think, it’s just a way of feeling like we have a little control in our uncertain times.  YMMV.)</p>
<p>You can buy it pre-made, or because it dissociates over time, you can buy a “generator” that makes it via electrolysis out of water and a tiny bit of salt and distilled vinegar.  (The acetic acid is for pH control; if the solution is acidic, you get hypochlorous acid; if the solution is basic, you get hypochlorite, which is more dangerous and not as effective.)</p>
<p>I started with a two-pack of spray bottles (happened to be CleanSmart brand), and then bought a small generator (Force of Nature).</p>
<p>I found three kinds of home generators (as opposed to industrial):</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The ~$300 kind, which I did not explore.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The ~$90-$120 fairly generic kind from Chinese manufacturers; I think these are probably pretty much the same as <span class="hashtag">#1</span>, with different packaging, manuals, and customer support.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Force of Nature, ~$50 + ~$1 per 12oz of HOCl.  They’re a US consumer-oriented company, and obtained an EPA registration for the hypochlorous acid their generator produces.  Partly because of the EPA registration and the need for precise formulation, or perhaps partly as a razor/razor blade model, they sell small ampoules of salt+vinegar that you use, 1 ampoule per 12 oz of solution.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>I was pretty close to buying a <span class="hashtag">#2</span> machine, but to do it right, you need to buy chlorine and pH test strips, which turns out to be sort of an ongoing expense like FoN’s ampoules.  Plus, you have to measure your salt and control the pH, and the base machine costs more than FoN… long story short, I appreciate FoN’s US consumer-oriented approach, and don’t find their supply cost onerous compared to the convenience.</p>
<p>Don’t buy FoN at Amazon, it’s expensive there.  Rather, if you buy one, buy direct from their website, and make sure you get a 15% or 20% coupon code. <a href="https://www.forceofnatureclean.com/">https://www.forceofnatureclean.com/</a></p>
<p>Again, not a marketing pitch, and not professional health and safety advice.  Do your own research, and/or contact your public health and safety officials.</p>
<p>This post is licensed under CC0/is public domain; please feel free to distribute as you wish.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-good-surface-sanitizer-cleaner-hypochlorous-acid/596">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-good-surface-sanitizer-cleaner-hypochlorous-acid/596</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-596</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-good-surface-sanitizer-cleaner-hypochlorous-acid/596.rss">A Good Surface Sanitizer/Cleaner: Hypochlorous Acid</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>White Supremacism and the Earth System</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[kenhomer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Discussions and Actions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Howdy,</p>
<p>On our last OGM call, new OGMember, Angel Acosta, put a link to the post below in the chat window. It’s important reading for OGMers everywhere:</p>
<p>[<a href="https://www.resilience.org/stories/2020-06-08/white-supremacism-and-the-earth-system/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.resilience.org/stories/2020-06-08/white-supremacism-and-the-earth-system/</a>]</p>
<p>Thank you Angel!</p>
<p>And I also recommend that you take a gander at Angel’s website to check out the work he is involved with:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.drangelacosta.com" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.drangelacosta.com</a></p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/white-supremacism-and-the-earth-system/587">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/white-supremacism-and-the-earth-system/587</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 01:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-587</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/white-supremacism-and-the-earth-system/587.rss">White Supremacism and the Earth System</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>OGM Q&amp;A: Currency Paradigms, Bitcoin, and more with Ingrid &amp; Pete</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Knowledge Areas</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Tuesday, Feb 23 – 90 minutes at 9:30am PST / 12:30pm EST / 18:30 CET</p>
<p>Join Ingrid Lantz and Peter Kaminski as we share questions and answers about how the currency paradigm is shifting, including topics such as fiat currency, reserve currencies, Bitcoin, Ethereum, altcoins, DeFi, community payment and exchange systems, blockchain applications, etc.</p>
<p>Zoom link: <a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/j/84672614466">https://us02web.zoom.us/j/84672614466</a></p>
<p>Forum topic for this Q&amp;A:</p>
<p>“OGM Q&amp;A: Currency Paradigms, Bitcoin, and more with Ingrid &amp; Pete”<br>
<em>you are here</em></p>
<p>Mattermost chat during this Q&amp;A:</p>
<p>“[ogm] Calls”<br>
<a href="https://chat.collectivesensecommons.org/agora/channels/ogm-calls" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://chat.collectivesensecommons.org/agora/channels/ogm-calls</a></p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/ogm-q-a-currency-paradigms-bitcoin-and-more-with-ingrid-pete/584">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/ogm-q-a-currency-paradigms-bitcoin-and-more-with-ingrid-pete/584</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 16:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-584</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/ogm-q-a-currency-paradigms-bitcoin-and-more-with-ingrid-pete/584.rss">OGM Q&amp;A: Currency Paradigms, Bitcoin, and more with Ingrid &amp; Pete</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Future Modeling Software</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Klaus]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Discussions and Actions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This looks interesting:</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/665e98010b7db9b82a17cbd5ce3f7a1a7a75c563.png" class="site-icon" width="100" height="109">
      <a href="https://www.knoweaux.com/futuremodeling" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">KNOWEAUX</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="" class="thumbnail" width="" height="">

<h3><a href="https://www.knoweaux.com/futuremodeling" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Future Modeling —  KNOWEAUX</a></h3>

<p>Future Modeling is the first standardized framework and active training capability to (re-)think and create desirable futures for instant application into future ready services and strategies.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            <p><small>4 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/future-modeling-software/583">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/future-modeling-software/583</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-583</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/future-modeling-software/583.rss">Future Modeling Software</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How to Start Doing Things NOW</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tony]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In order to make sense of complicated events (activities) we first need to understand what is meant by “complexity” .   For activity based systems (and any system that is goal oriented is activity based), complexity means tight coupling between the activities.  That is that there are so many inputs/outputs between the activities that we can not figure out what is going on.</p>
<p>In order to make sense of complex activities, we need to reduce the coupling between activities.   This can be done by repartitioning the activities based on following the natural flow which, if done correctly, greatly reduces the inputs/outputs between activities.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-start-doing-things-now/581">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-start-doing-things-now/581</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 14:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-581</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-start-doing-things-now/581.rss">How to Start Doing Things NOW</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How to Address the Major Systemic Problems</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tony]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Systems Thinking</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In order to make sense of complicated events (activities) we first need to understand what is meant by “complexity” .   For activity based systems , complexity means tight coupling between the activities.  That is that there are so many inputs/outputs between the activities that we can not figure out what is going on.</p>
<p>In order to make sense of complex activities, we need to reduce the coupling between activities (events).   This can be done by repartitioning the activities based on following the natural flow which, if done correctly, greatly reduces the inputs/outputs between activities.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-address-the-major-systemic-problems/580">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-address-the-major-systemic-problems/580</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 14:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-580</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-address-the-major-systemic-problems/580.rss">How to Address the Major Systemic Problems</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Good update on Covid variants here</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[kenhomer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Discussions and Actions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>WaPo is normally behind a paywall, but is making their Covid coverage freely accessible</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.washingtonpost.com/pf/resources/images/favicon.ico?d=203" class="site-icon" width="" height="">
      <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/interactive/2021/01/25/covid-variants/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Washington Post</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-apps/imrs.php?src=https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/FA3QTKXLWJCOFMFJ3GDM44YLRU.jpg&amp;w=1200" class="thumbnail" width="" height="">

<h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/interactive/2021/01/25/covid-variants/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">What you need to know about the coronavirus variants</a></h3>

<p>The U.K., South Africa and Brazil variants are highly transmissible and have sparked concerns that vaccines may be less effective against them.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/good-update-on-covid-variants-here/579">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/good-update-on-covid-variants-here/579</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 04:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-579</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/good-update-on-covid-variants-here/579.rss">Good update on Covid variants here</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>CORN IS A PLATFORM</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Knowledge Areas</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I wanted to post one of my favorite rants, from December 2018.  It’s related to US capitalism, finance, real estate, and “farming”.</p>
<p>In the following, “corn,” “maize,” and “soybeans” refer to the industrial varieties which humans don’t eat, but which make up most of what the US grows.  Think industrial feedstocks; not popcorn, corn on the cob, or edamame.</p>
<p>SwiftOnSecurity started:</p>
<aside class="onebox twitterstatus">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1074856487514726400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/1d1a0c9f3340fa28fb08f685c5c7d4b180320af9.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1074856487514726400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SwiftOnSecurity (SwiftOnSecurity)</a></h4>

<div class="tweet"> You live in a society whose every production industry is based around a government-subsidized chemical feedstock.

Corn is not a _food_.
Corn is a _platform_.<div class="quoted">
<a class="quoted-link" href="https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/972631797375950849" rel="noopener"><p class="quoted-title">SwiftOnSecurity <span>@SwiftOnSecurity</span></p></a><div>You’ve got government market subsidy, political weight of low-population states, energy insecurity, environmental issues, agribusiness consolidation, hyper-productivity despite decreasing labor, food basket dynamics in world wars, 20th century chemical revolution, obesity, etc</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="date">
  <a href="https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1074856487514726400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3:59 PM - 17 Dec 2018</a>
    <span class="like">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 512 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M462.3 62.6C407.5 15.9 326 24.3 275.7 76.2L256 96.5l-19.7-20.3C186.1 24.3 104.5 15.9 49.7 62.6c-62.8 53.6-66.1 149.8-9.9 207.9l193.5 199.8c12.5 12.9 32.8 12.9 45.3 0l193.5-199.8c56.3-58.1 53-154.3-9.8-207.9z"></path>
      </svg> 7.2K
    </span>
    <span class="retweet">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 640 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M629.657 343.598L528.971 444.284c-9.373 9.372-24.568 9.372-33.941 0L394.343 343.598c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941l10.823-10.823c9.562-9.562 25.133-9.34 34.419.492L480 342.118V160H292.451a24.005 24.005 0 0 1-16.971-7.029l-16-16C244.361 121.851 255.069 96 276.451 96H520c13.255 0 24 10.745 24 24v222.118l40.416-42.792c9.285-9.831 24.856-10.054 34.419-.492l10.823 10.823c9.372 9.372 9.372 24.569-.001 33.941zm-265.138 15.431A23.999 23.999 0 0 0 347.548 352H160V169.881l40.416 42.792c9.286 9.831 24.856 10.054 34.419.491l10.822-10.822c9.373-9.373 9.373-24.569 0-33.941L144.971 67.716c-9.373-9.373-24.569-9.373-33.941 0L10.343 168.402c-9.373 9.373-9.373 24.569 0 33.941l10.822 10.822c9.562 9.562 25.133 9.34 34.419-.491L96 169.881V392c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h243.549c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-16.001-16z"></path>
      </svg> 2.2K
    </span>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>(scroll up and down that thread for enough examples to make you sick)</p>
<p>And Dr. Taber picked up from there:</p>
<aside class="onebox twitterstatus">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/SarahTaber_bww/status/1074882589079597056" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/9ccc7e8e455bd194b9a97c3ff9ca0dd49b0af08e.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="624" height="351">

<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/SarahTaber_bww/status/1074882589079597056" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr Sarah Taber (SarahTaber_bww)</a></h4>

<div class="tweet"> Enter maize &amp; soybeans. Here's what they bring to table:

1) Short-lived enough to make use of Midwest growing season

2) Need lots of water- that cuts out competition from the US West

3) Humans can't eat them, but that's ok, they're just infinitely fungible starch &amp; protein. https://t.co/Gk4bemgYzJ<div class="quoted">
<a class="quoted-link" href="https://twitter.com/SarahTaber_bww/status/1074864735143804928" rel="noopener"><p class="quoted-title">Dr Sarah Taber <span>@SarahTaber_bww</span></p></a><div>GOD YES

SOMEONE FINALLY EXPLAINED IT https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1074856487514726400&nbsp;…</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="date">
  <a href="https://twitter.com/SarahTaber_bww/status/1074882589079597056" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8:22 PM - 17 Dec 2018</a>
    <span class="like">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 512 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M462.3 62.6C407.5 15.9 326 24.3 275.7 76.2L256 96.5l-19.7-20.3C186.1 24.3 104.5 15.9 49.7 62.6c-62.8 53.6-66.1 149.8-9.9 207.9l193.5 199.8c12.5 12.9 32.8 12.9 45.3 0l193.5-199.8c56.3-58.1 53-154.3-9.8-207.9z"></path>
      </svg> 809
    </span>
    <span class="retweet">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 640 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M629.657 343.598L528.971 444.284c-9.373 9.372-24.568 9.372-33.941 0L394.343 343.598c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941l10.823-10.823c9.562-9.562 25.133-9.34 34.419.492L480 342.118V160H292.451a24.005 24.005 0 0 1-16.971-7.029l-16-16C244.361 121.851 255.069 96 276.451 96H520c13.255 0 24 10.745 24 24v222.118l40.416-42.792c9.285-9.831 24.856-10.054 34.419-.492l10.823 10.823c9.372 9.372 9.372 24.569-.001 33.941zm-265.138 15.431A23.999 23.999 0 0 0 347.548 352H160V169.881l40.416 42.792c9.286 9.831 24.856 10.054 34.419.491l10.822-10.822c9.373-9.373 9.373-24.569 0-33.941L144.971 67.716c-9.373-9.373-24.569-9.373-33.941 0L10.343 168.402c-9.373 9.373-9.373 24.569 0 33.941l10.822 10.822c9.562 9.562 25.133 9.34 34.419-.491L96 169.881V392c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h243.549c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-16.001-16z"></path>
      </svg> 120
    </span>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<blockquote>
<p>Corn is a platform with both limitless purposes, and one purpose:</p>
<p>to turn rural land into a dependable &amp; infinitely fungible financial asset.</p>
<p>If you want to understand US agriculture, you gotta understand one thing.</p>
<p>It’s not even about making food.</p>
<p>It’s a real estate hustle.</p>
<p>Can I be honest for a second, as an ag person who’s done most of their work in CA &amp; the South?</p>
<p>Land in the Midwest … isn’t really good for much. Sure, the soil’s real nice, but the growing season is too short for most globally-traded cash crops.</p>
<p>Coffee.</p>
<p>Sugar.</p>
<p>Chocolate.</p>
<p>Cotton.</p>
<p>Tobacco.</p>
<p>Rice.</p>
<p>Palm oil.</p>
<p>The Midwest is exactly the kind of giant wet low-population area you’d want for cash crops. Except most of the big-money ones are tropical, &amp; Midwest has a 3-6 month growing season. You’re stuck with annual crops.</p>
<p>“Well what’s wrong w wheat, flax, oats, rye, hemp, &amp; other short-season cash crops?”</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Hemp ain’t been legal</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We can’t use an entire Midwest’s worth of oats &amp; rye</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Wheat &amp; flax grow nearly everywhere, including huge areas of arid US west. Too much competition to rely on.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Enter maize &amp; soybeans. Here’s what they bring to table:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Short-lived enough to make use of Midwest growing season</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Need lots of water- that cuts out competition from the US West</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Humans can’t eat them, but that’s ok, they’re just infinitely fungible starch &amp; protein.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>If you’re just growing raw sources of starch &amp; protein, you can just handle market gluts by inventing a new use. That’s harder to do with crops that make something less malleable like fiber, or (in case of wheat, oats, rye, &amp; most grains) a mid-yield mix of starch &amp; protein.</p>
<p>And boy do we get our market gluts on. Because for 3-6 months every year, the Midwest turns into a giant hot wet basin of plant growing power.</p>
<p>But: without a platform like corn &amp; soybeans, hot wet plains are just hot wet plains. They’re not a financial powerhouse. You couldn’t, say, include farmland as a securitized asset in investment funds.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2016/01/21/getting-your-plot-of-american-farmland-.html">https://www.cnbc.com/2016/01/21/getting-your-plot-of-american-farmland-.html</a></p>
<p>The Food Discourse™ really fixates on how corn is used after it’s grown. “Oh my God! It’s in everything!”</p>
<p>I’m more interested in what that means for those who possess the land to grow it &amp; what <em>that</em> means for our society. And <span class="mention">@SwiftOnSecurity</span> hit the nail on the head.</p>
<p>Part of the Food Discourse ™’s fascination with food manufacturing is that it’s fairly recent. It feels new &amp; foreign. And, you can <em>see</em> the size of the facilities and visualize the money that it takes to build and run them.</p>
<p>It’s a fairly new way to accumulate wealth. It’s visible. And it fits with our “wealth is capital is manufacturing &amp; Wall Street” mentality. So we fixate on it.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, most folks have no idea what the value of farmland is. Or that subsidies don’t go to the people growing the corn- they go to the people who <em>own the land it grows on.</em></p>
<p>Most folks have no idea that the big hustle in food isn’t food. It’s real estate.</p>
<p>That doesn’t fit with our image of how wealth works in a capitalist society.</p>
<p>Capitalism is supposed to mean new, modern, and scary! Farmland is ancient and wholesome! Farming is our one connection to more wholesome times!</p>
<p>Bullshit.</p>
<p>Farm landlords were grinding people to death for thousands of years before capitalism was ever invented.</p>
<p>Real estate’s always been the ideal asset. Can be used for food, minerals, or development- and you can collect rents pretty much infinitely w zero work.</p>
<p>But thanks to our focus on “bad stuff in our economy = modern = capitalism = industry” &amp; “agriculture = old = good,” we rarely see farmland as being an asset that can be traded globally.</p>
<p>AND <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> THAT’S <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> EXACTLY <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> HOW <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> THE <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> GOD <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> DAMN <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> LANDLORDS <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> WANT <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> IT</p>
<p>We’re busy fretting about agribusiness and food processing, meanwhile real live land barons are out here collecting rent &amp; subsidy checks on millions of acres and using it as low-risk ballast for their portfolios.</p>
<p>To be clear: Wall Street is part of this.</p>
<p>So are good ol’ boys.</p>
<p>Most rural counties are run by 2-3 families that quietly own a huge slice of the land. You want to know why rural areas are so fucked up? It ain’t the coastal elites. It’s the landlords right there in the county.</p>
<p>Rural landlords might collect their rent checks directly from their serfs, I mean neighbors in the county instead of a hedge fund office in Manhattan. But they’ve got the same job. Own land, futz around all day, profit.</p>
<p>Ever notice how most proposals to solve farm-related problems- not enough food, too much food, soil conservation, wildlife conservation, water shortages-</p>
<p>all seem to boil down to “throw money at land owners”?</p>
<p>Isn’t that weird?</p>
<p>The philosophy behind conservation payments is sometimes people own farmland that’s too fragile to farm.</p>
<p>But not farming loses money! Therefore, we must pay them not to farm it!</p>
<p>Is anybody asking why own “farmland” that can’t be farmed in the first place?</p>
<p>This is a problem that could be solved a lot of different ways. Trusts, land buybacks, tax writeoffs for donating to conservation, etc. These are all used to some extent.</p>
<p>But the big federal programs are all built around sending landowners a reliable subsidy check every year.</p>
<p>So … yeah. Sometimes rural land ownership is just an instrument for rich people to extort bribes from taxpayers. “Pay me or I’ll ruin your water.”</p>
<p>And sometimes you just monetize it on the corn platform.</p>
<p>Either way, it’s a huge asset class. In many ways it’s more influential &amp; politically powerful than the “industrial food” sector we’ve been taught to fear. But it’s invisible, distant, and quiet, monetizing the earth in ways few of us understand.</p>
<p>welp my soundcloud is at <a href="https://soundcloud.com/farm-to-taber-podcast">https://soundcloud.com/farm-to-taber-podcast</a> &amp; you can support grumpy, sciencey, intersectional, independent farm journalism at <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=5610560">https://www.patreon.com/user?u=5610560</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Bonus links, a musical cartoon, “Chudesnitsa”, praising the virtues of corn in agriculture, from Nikita Khrushchev’s USSR:</p>
<aside class="onebox twitterstatus">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/sovietvisuals/status/762223983139749889" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/aa0ae9b6ac9366cd4b2b4001e77890f99ea1a9a6.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="450" height="360">

<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/sovietvisuals/status/762223983139749889" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Soviet Visuals (sovietvisuals)</a></h4>

<div class="tweet"> 1955: massive corn campaign led by Nikita Khrushchev. 1957: this cartoon about corn comes out. ("Chudesnitsa") https://t.co/mO3IEjZblY</div>

<div class="date">
  <a href="https://twitter.com/sovietvisuals/status/762223983139749889" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2:48 AM - 7 Aug 2016</a>
    <span class="like">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 512 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M462.3 62.6C407.5 15.9 326 24.3 275.7 76.2L256 96.5l-19.7-20.3C186.1 24.3 104.5 15.9 49.7 62.6c-62.8 53.6-66.1 149.8-9.9 207.9l193.5 199.8c12.5 12.9 32.8 12.9 45.3 0l193.5-199.8c56.3-58.1 53-154.3-9.8-207.9z"></path>
      </svg> 1.9K
    </span>
    <span class="retweet">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 640 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M629.657 343.598L528.971 444.284c-9.373 9.372-24.568 9.372-33.941 0L394.343 343.598c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941l10.823-10.823c9.562-9.562 25.133-9.34 34.419.492L480 342.118V160H292.451a24.005 24.005 0 0 1-16.971-7.029l-16-16C244.361 121.851 255.069 96 276.451 96H520c13.255 0 24 10.745 24 24v222.118l40.416-42.792c9.285-9.831 24.856-10.054 34.419-.492l10.823 10.823c9.372 9.372 9.372 24.569-.001 33.941zm-265.138 15.431A23.999 23.999 0 0 0 347.548 352H160V169.881l40.416 42.792c9.286 9.831 24.856 10.054 34.419.491l10.822-10.822c9.373-9.373 9.373-24.569 0-33.941L144.971 67.716c-9.373-9.373-24.569-9.373-33.941 0L10.343 168.402c-9.373 9.373-9.373 24.569 0 33.941l10.822 10.822c9.562 9.562 25.133 9.34 34.419-.491L96 169.881V392c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h243.549c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-16.001-16z"></path>
      </svg> 873
    </span>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<div class="onebox lazyYT lazyYT-container" data-youtube-id="YTMu_FNvBAA" data-youtube-title="Чудесница (1957)" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque">
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YTMu_FNvBAA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <img class="ytp-thumbnail-image" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/30c123c03e23d670b1ce880f085d2476bc8fae9a.jpeg" title="Чудесница (1957)" width="480" height="360">
  </a>
</div>

<p><a href="https://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D0%A7%D1%83%D0%B4%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B0_(%D0%BC%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D1%82%D1%84%D0%B8%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BC)">Чудесница (мультфильм)</a> (Russian Wikipedia)</p>
<p>Pete</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 19:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-575</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575.rss">CORN IS A PLATFORM</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Tech Enabled Dis- and Mis-Information, Social Platforms and Geopolitics</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[kenhomer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Discussions and Actions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>From The Atlantic Council</p>
<p>In an age of hyper-connectivity and expansive digitization, social platforms play an outsized role in public life, serving as a sort of infrastructure for everything from academia and journalism, to public service and elections. Individuals across the world have unprecedented access to new information each day, and these social technologies are increasingly being relied upon by communities to organize and enact change. Many of these technologies were formed in the era of “techno-utopianism” — assuming a more connected and informed population would mean more open and democratic societies— but they have increasingly become the tools through which bad actors drive division. Whether through coordinated information operations or a simple retweet without verification, false or misleading information can spread rapidly and easily on social platforms, which, in turn, can undermine democratic processes or exacerbate public health crises.</p>
<p>With more than half the world’s population estimated to have gained access to the internet by 2018, better understanding the threats to the global information ecosystem is a matter of global stability.</p>
<p>Join our expert panelists for a wide-ranging discussion exploring the human, business, and technological incentives that have driven the growth of mis- and dis-information globally, and what a weaponized information space means for the world.</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/ac2f822d312dfdb6d4b94c216aa63287fe59cb17.png" class="site-icon" width="150" height="150">
      <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/event/tech-enabled-misinformation-geopolitics/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Atlantic Council</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/396;"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/5d04da4cd95c66ad29023a2b2c8eaea2b9cec0f6_2_690x396.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="396" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/5d04da4cd95c66ad29023a2b2c8eaea2b9cec0f6_2_690x396.jpeg, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/5d04da4cd95c66ad29023a2b2c8eaea2b9cec0f6_2_1035x594.jpeg 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/5d04da4cd95c66ad29023a2b2c8eaea2b9cec0f6_2_1380x792.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/5d04da4cd95c66ad29023a2b2c8eaea2b9cec0f6_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/event/tech-enabled-misinformation-geopolitics/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Tech-enabled dis- and misinformation, social platforms, and geopolitics -...</a></h3>

<p>Join us for this special GeoTech hour jointly produced by both the Atlantic Council's Digital Forensics Research Lab and GeoTech Center as we explore the impacts of tech on propagating misinformation at increasing velocity and volume as well as the...</p>

  <p><span class="label1">Est. reading time: 2 minutes</span>
    </p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/tech-enabled-dis-and-mis-information-social-platforms-and-geopolitics/574">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/tech-enabled-dis-and-mis-information-social-platforms-and-geopolitics/574</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 03:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-574</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/tech-enabled-dis-and-mis-information-social-platforms-and-geopolitics/574.rss">Tech Enabled Dis- and Mis-Information, Social Platforms and Geopolitics</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Emergent Event Sensemaking</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>A proto-guild is forming on mattermost around sensemaking of complicated emergent events, I think particularly where there are complex system dynamics and information overload:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://chat.collectivesensecommons.org/agora/channels/emergent-event-sensemaking">Emergent Event Sensemaking</a></li>
</ul>
<p>We’re focusing on the <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/r-wallstreetbets-vs-hedge-funds-gme/558">GameStop short squeeze</a> as a first exercise, but other examples might include 9/11, the 2008 mortage crash, Fukushima, COVID-19 responses, etc.</p>
<p>Stephan Kreutzer first proposed this in the Off-Topic channel, and he describes the idea well:</p>
<p>“there could be a systemic and continual approach, to quickly condense the flood of information/feeds into approximating working models for overview/navigating.”</p>
<p>So far the tools we are considering include:</p>
<ul>
<li>static 2D diagramming / flowcharts</li>
<li>interactive system dynamics modeling, with e.g. Insight Maker</li>
</ul>
<p>The efforts to guild-form may or may not go anywhere, we’ll see.  Everybody has busy lives, and we may not actually get the spark of the idea off the ground; but, you’re welcome to join in if it sounds interesting to see where it goes.</p>
            <p><small>19 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/emergent-event-sensemaking/567">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/emergent-event-sensemaking/567</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 15:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-567</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/emergent-event-sensemaking/567.rss">Emergent Event Sensemaking</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>CAUTION: Variants Ahead - B117 and other variants will explode soon in the US</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>(crossposted from my <a href="https://petescovid19.substack.com/p/caution-variants-ahead">COVID-19 newsletter</a>)</p>
<p>I wrote about <a href="https://petescovid19.substack.com/p/b117">B.1.1.7, the “UK variant” of SARS-CoV-2</a>, back in December, hoping that it wouldn’t end up being bad news.</p>
<p>Well, now we know, it is bad news — it is more infectious, on the order of 50% - 70% more.</p>
<p>“More infectious” just means that it spreads better, meaning more cases faster, meaning healthcare systems getting strained more quickly, and ultimately meaning, long-term damage to more bodies and more deaths.</p>
<p>Researchers are tracking the emergence of other meaningful variants. For all the variants, the questions are:</p>
<ul>
<li>does it spread better?</li>
<li>will the vaccines have reduced effectiveness, and might we need additional kinds of vaccines to respond?</li>
<li>will the symptoms and health outcomes it causes be worse?</li>
</ul>
<p>There is a possible “yes,” at least to some extent, for each of these questions, for different variants. For a few, we know for sure that they spread better.</p>
<p>That wouldn’t be a big deal for a small number of infections… but the problem is that this deal will be exponential.</p>
<p>Sometimes people just mean “bigger” when they say “exponential,” but the technical, mathematical definition of “exponential” means not only bigger, but getting bigger <em>as</em> it gets bigger.</p>
<p>IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT TO TAKE THESE NEW VARIANTS SERIOUSLY.</p>
<p>I could say a lot more, but I don’t think I can say it more clearly than that. So I’ll leave you with that, and some of the best reading I’ve come across on the subject, below.</p>
<p>We can meet the challenge of the new variants, but it will require doing all the things we’ve been doing, AND better than we have been. Masks, distance, hand hygiene, bubbles, travel restrictions, vaccine production, vaccine distribution, and actually getting a shot when it’s available to you.</p>
<p>IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT TO TAKE THESE NEW VARIANTS SERIOUSLY.</p>
<p>Okay, read some of these:</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/europe/uk-variant-covid-denmark/2021/01/22/ddfaf420-5453-11eb-acc5-92d2819a1ccb_story.html">Denmark’s coronavirus sequencing shows U.K. variant cases exploding</a></strong> (The Washington Post, 2021-01-22)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In a long Facebook post this month, Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen told people to imagine sitting in the top row of Copenhagen’s Parken Stadium, a soccer arena with a capacity of 38,000 people. A dripping tap is filling it up, one drop the first minute, two drops the second, four drops the third. At that rate, Frederiksen said, the park will be filled in 44 minutes. But it will seem almost empty for the first 42 minutes, she said.</p>
<p>“The point is, you only realize that the water has risen when it’s almost too late,” she wrote.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2021/01/27/double-mask-variants-guidance/">Time to double mask or upgrade masks as coronavirus variants emerge, experts say</a></strong> (The Washington Post, 2021-01-28)</p>
<p>(A lot of this article talks about expert confusion — should we recommend a medical-grade mask or not? Should we recommend double-masking? Countries in Europe are less wishy-washy, perhaps because they’re closer and more aware of how hard B117 hit the UK. Again, take the variants seriously, it’s time to have better masks when you’re around other people. Along with N95, you should research KN95, KF94, and FFP2.)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/19/well/live/covid-b117-variant-advice.html">What You Can Do to Avoid the New Coronavirus Variant Right Now</a></strong> (The New York Times, 2021-01-19)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/ezraklein/status/1354830708515037186">“This is the part of the horror film where safety seems in sight, but it is obvious, to those paying attention, that the monster is not dead, and that the worst may be yet to come. We cannot let ourselves be taken by surprise.”</a></strong> (Ezra Klein, 2021-01-28)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/DrEricDing/status/1354646619174678529">“WORRISOME MATH—#B117 variant is so crazy: what happens if there are just 10 cases now, &amp; new UK #B117 has 50% greater transmissibility?”</a></strong> (Eric Feigl-Ding, 2021-01-27)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2020/12/virus-mutation-catastrophe/617531/">The Mutated Virus Is a Ticking Time Bomb</a></strong> (The Atlantic, 2020-12-31)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/more/science-and-research/scientific-brief-emerging-variants.html">Emerging SARS-CoV-2 Variants</a></strong> (CDC, last updated 2021-01-28)</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/caution-variants-ahead-b117-and-other-variants-will-explode-soon-in-the-us/562">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/caution-variants-ahead-b117-and-other-variants-will-explode-soon-in-the-us/562</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 16:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-562</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/caution-variants-ahead-b117-and-other-variants-will-explode-soon-in-the-us/562.rss">CAUTION: Variants Ahead - B117 and other variants will explode soon in the US</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>On Racism - Some Resources</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[GlennMII]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Discussions and Actions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In the related thread, I wrote:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Suggested reading: “Come All You Brave Soldiers: Blacks in the Revolutionary War” by Clinton Cox, in combination with “Frederick Douglass” by David W. Blight, “Rush” (about a founding father, Benjamin Rush) by Stephen Fried, the Chelsea House Publishers series “The Indians of North America,”<br>
“The Year They Walked” by Beatrice Siegel, and “Sarny, A Life Remembered” by Gary Paulsen. In these books, you can see the treachery, hypocrisy and silver-tongued nature of Americans as they dealt with Indians and Blacks, including how Washington misused the Army to slaughter Indians in pursuit of getting prime real estate for himself, and how Blacks who fought in the Revolutionary War (and some in 1812) were re-enslaved, many of whom were never justly rewarded because the Continental Congress allowed slave owners to send a slave as their replacement.</p>
<p>So many heinous crimes by our over-glorified founders, whose motives were far more earthbound and selfish than we were taught.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you don’t have the time or inclination to read that much (Rush and Frederick Douglass are LONG, dense, thought-provoking books), and you’d just like to get a feel for what it might be like to be on the receiving end of racial discrimination, and all the fear, anger, confusion, frustration, etc. that produces, I suggest you watch <em>Blindspotting</em>.  You might also chuckle at the irony of the kitchen scene at the party which ironically makes Miles look like a fool before Collin realizes that it is Miles the other person speaks of and they all discuss with disdain. It is intense, with violence and swearing, and the speed-rapping can sometimes be hard to follow when it happens, but if you pay close attention you may find yourself, as I did, identifying with Collin, empathizing and, if you can allow it, shedding tears like I did. As events unfold, with the irresponsible behavior of Miles only adding to the jeopardy of Collin - who is struggling with guilt that magnifies over time - you can see that Collin is really struggling and then it all comes to a climax that is so unexpected and powerful that you hold your breath praying that it won’t all go sideways. The movie brings you to this intense moment after carefully escalating, and what comes after is…Well, you’ll have to watch.</p>
<p>You see - and you may well see, if you have been a victim of discrimination, as I have - through the shared experience of this film, in a way that many other films fail to capture so eloquently, what you may have been blind to <em><strong>in spite of your experiences</strong></em>.</p>
<p>To borrow from something my twelve-year old son wrote this week at school:<br>
"If we find division before we ignite the fire of reunion, we will fall into the bitter cold and evil of darkness before we can spark the hope and purpose that lights the fire of reunion, the fire that will bring us warmth and light from the dark of division, the division that will bring us defeat and submission.</p>
<p>If we find ourselves looking at each other and seeing an enemy, the enemy that we know of as division, the fire has already been extinguished by the unforgiving winds that were held at bay by the light of hope, purpose and union."</p>
<p>I may be brash, candid and willing to argue, but I know the pain, humiliation, anger, confusion, frustration, sadness, etc. of discrimination (not to Collin’s degree, though), and I was raised not to discriminate. I would be very happy if this whole problem that pits “races” against each other for no reason other than fear of that which is obvious different combined with the desire to conquer it would be erased from the world.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/on-racism-some-resources/561">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/on-racism-some-resources/561</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 04:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-561</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/on-racism-some-resources/561.rss">On Racism - Some Resources</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>A project to fight misinformation and model critical thinking: Gulli Bot</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[BentleyDavis]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’ve been working on misinformation for almost 10 years and I ask for your help on this as a project and some quests. My current plan is to create an online character that models and documents critical thinking on contentious issues named <a href="https://GulliBot.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Gulli Bot</a>.</p>
<p>Gulli is just a character powered by humans (no artificial intelligence or machine learning) but it does have a way of representing a debate in a very transparent and thorough way so people can quickly and easily understand the scope of all the claims about the issue.</p>
<p>The first topic is “<a href="https://gullibot.com/covid-vaccine/" rel="nofollow noopener">Should you take the COVID-19 vaccine?</a>” and I could use help is choosing popular issues to analyze and researching them.</p>
<p>Let me know if you would like more info or be interested in helping with this project.</p>
            <p><small>17 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-project-to-fight-misinformation-and-model-critical-thinking-gulli-bot/559">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-project-to-fight-misinformation-and-model-critical-thinking-gulli-bot/559</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 15:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-559</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-project-to-fight-misinformation-and-model-critical-thinking-gulli-bot/559.rss">A project to fight misinformation and model critical thinking: Gulli Bot</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>&quot;Underestimating the Challenges of Avoiding a Ghastly Future&quot;</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Clarion call roundup of where we are and where we’re going with climate change.  Sort of an Inconvenient Truth for 2021.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We report three major and confronting environmental issues that have received little attention and require urgent action. First, we review the evidence that future environmental conditions will be far more dangerous than currently believed. The scale of the threats to the biosphere and all its lifeforms—including humanity—is in fact so great that it is difficult to grasp for even well-informed experts. Second, we ask what political or economic system, or leadership, is prepared to handle the predicted disasters, or even capable of such action. Third, this dire situation places an extraordinary responsibility on scientists to speak out candidly and accurately when engaging with government, business, and the public. We especially draw attention to the lack of appreciation of the enormous challenges to creating a sustainable future.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Article for the general public:</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/585fee1a8040b36bda6a7356c78d13f3b31ff028.png" class="site-icon" width="192" height="192">
      <a href="https://theconversation.com/worried-about-earths-future-well-the-outlook-is-worse-than-even-scientists-can-grasp-153091" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Conversation</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/339;"><img src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/378461/original/file-20210113-21-rwemte.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;rect=8%2C491%2C5551%2C2775&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="339"></div>

<h3><a href="https://theconversation.com/worried-about-earths-future-well-the-outlook-is-worse-than-even-scientists-can-grasp-153091" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Worried about Earth's future? Well, the outlook is worse than even scientists...</a></h3>

<p>Humanity is destroying Earth’s ability to support complex life. But coming to grips with the magnitude of the problem is hard, even for experts.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>The report itself:</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://3718aeafc638f96f5bd6-d4a9ca15fc46ba40e71f94dec0aad28c.ssl.cf1.rackcdn.com/favicon_16x16.ico" class="site-icon" width="48" height="48">
      <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fcosc.2020.615419/full" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Frontiers</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:400/331;"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/18a01568ec49e1347a550e76fcdbeba09ca469de.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="400" height="331"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fcosc.2020.615419/full" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Underestimating the Challenges of Avoiding a Ghastly Future</a></h3>

<p>We report three major and confronting environmental issues that have received little attention and require urgent action. First, we review the evidence that future environmental conditions will be far more dangerous than currently believed. The scale...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/underestimating-the-challenges-of-avoiding-a-ghastly-future/539">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/underestimating-the-challenges-of-avoiding-a-ghastly-future/539</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 16:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-539</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/underestimating-the-challenges-of-avoiding-a-ghastly-future/539.rss">&quot;Underestimating the Challenges of Avoiding a Ghastly Future&quot;</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Anyone interested in a forming a book group for Sand Talk: How Indigenous Thinking Can Save the World?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[kenhomer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Discussions and Actions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I have long been interested in the question of what do we mean when we say someone is “indigenous”? According to <em>Sand Talk</em>:</p>
<p>“An indigenous person is a member of a community retaining memories of life lived sustainably on a land base, as part of that land base. Indigenous Knowledge is any application of those memories as living knowledge to improve present and future circumstances.”</p>
<p>I began reading the book: <em>Sand Talk</em> this week and I am really loving it. I’d love to have some folks to talk about the book with. Is anyone out there interested in maybe a weekly or bi-weekly call to share learnings and questions?</p>
<p>LMK!</p>
<p>Ken</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/anyone-interested-in-a-forming-a-book-group-for-sand-talk-how-indigenous-thinking-can-save-the-world/527">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/anyone-interested-in-a-forming-a-book-group-for-sand-talk-how-indigenous-thinking-can-save-the-world/527</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 04:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-527</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/anyone-interested-in-a-forming-a-book-group-for-sand-talk-how-indigenous-thinking-can-save-the-world/527.rss">Anyone interested in a forming a book group for Sand Talk: How Indigenous Thinking Can Save the World?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Dancing with Denial and Despair</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[kenhomer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Discussions and Actions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If you’ve been on OGM calls with me, you’ve heard me mention Joanna Macy - a highly influential teacher for me back in the 1990s. I recently came across this interview with her conducted by Krista Tippet. This short excerpt encapsulates for me an important aspect of how to be effective in the world:</p>
<p>“…The kind of apathy and closed-down denial, our difficulty in looking at what we’re doing to our world stems not from callous indifference or ignorance so much as it stems from fear of pain. That was a big learning for me as I was organizing around nuclear power and around at the time of Three Mile Island catastrophe and around Chernobyl.</p>
<p>It relates to everything. It relates to what’s in our food, and it relates to the clear-cuts of our forests. It relates to the contamination of our rivers and oceans. So that became, actually, perhaps the most pivotal point in — I don’t know — the landscape of my life: that dance with despair, to see how we are called to not run from the discomfort and not run from the grief or the feelings of outrage or even fear — and that, if we can be fearless, to be with our pain, it turns. It doesn’t stay static. It only doesn’t change if we refuse to look at it. But when we look at it, when we take it in our hands, when we can just be with it and keep breathing, then it turns. It turns to reveal its other face, and the other face of our pain for the world is our love for the world, our absolutely inseparable connectedness with all life.”</p>
<p>Here’s the full interview:</p>
<p>[<a href="https://onbeing.org/programs/joanna-macy-a-wild-love-for-the-world/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://onbeing.org/programs/joanna-macy-a-wild-love-for-the-world/</a>]</p>
<p>As we enter the second year of the Covid pandemic, I invite anyone who is interested, to look within to see what pain and grief you might be denying when you look at the world and consider how to hold that pain and grief and dance out of denial so that the face of your love for the world is revealed.</p>
<p>If there is interest, I’d be happy to convene a zoom call to talk about this.</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/dancing-with-denial-and-despair/513">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/dancing-with-denial-and-despair/513</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 04:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-513</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/dancing-with-denial-and-despair/513.rss">Dancing with Denial and Despair</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Introduction to Music Theory (notes, intervals, scales, chords)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Knowledge Areas</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>YouTube culture – and thoughtful, well-organized, well-spoken experts – have given us amazing educational resources.  This forum topic will focus on the fundamentals of music theory, which can be – has been – a thorny, difficult subject to approach.</p>
<p>But really, it’s fun!</p>
<p>Here are a couple very good “Music Theory 101” suggestions, each running ~30 minutes.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rgaTLrZGlk0">Learn music theory in half an hour.</a> (Andrew Huang)</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_eKTOMhpy2w">Music Theory in 16 Minutes</a> (Guy Michelmore)</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=heAcV-kqKrQ">Music Theory Everyone SHOULD KNOW | Chords, Progressions and Keys</a> (Rick Beato)</li>
</ul>
<p>And Music Theory 201 suggestions:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eRkgK4jfi6M">Musician Explains One Concept in 5 Levels of Difficulty</a> (Jacob Collier, Herbie Hancock, et al., WIRED)</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VR3o45Pwx9Y">What is a chord?</a> (Adam Neely)</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kr3quGh7pJA">Music Theory and White Supremacy</a> (Adam Neely)</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=49alQj7c5ps">Why you should learn music theory (Prescriptivism vs Descriptivism)</a> (Adam Neely)</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-to-music-theory-notes-intervals-scales-chords/512">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-to-music-theory-notes-intervals-scales-chords/512</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 22:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-512</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-to-music-theory-notes-intervals-scales-chords/512.rss">Introduction to Music Theory (notes, intervals, scales, chords)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Systems Design / Systems Thinking Resources from Twitter</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Systems Thinking</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Here’s a thread on Twitter with systems design / systems thinking resources:</p>
<aside class="onebox twitterstatus">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/uxKim/status/1344761241357586432" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/e9ebc20485e98f79bd69b542909cdf1ede4b79f2.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/uxKim/status/1344761241357586432" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kim lenox (uxKim)</a></h4>

<div class="tweet"> What would you consider to be the best content to learn systems design? (not design systems, but systems thinking)</div>

<div class="date">
  <a href="https://twitter.com/uxKim/status/1344761241357586432" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1:43 PM - 31 Dec 2020</a>
    <span class="like">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 512 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M462.3 62.6C407.5 15.9 326 24.3 275.7 76.2L256 96.5l-19.7-20.3C186.1 24.3 104.5 15.9 49.7 62.6c-62.8 53.6-66.1 149.8-9.9 207.9l193.5 199.8c12.5 12.9 32.8 12.9 45.3 0l193.5-199.8c56.3-58.1 53-154.3-9.8-207.9z"></path>
      </svg> 216
    </span>
    <span class="retweet">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 640 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M629.657 343.598L528.971 444.284c-9.373 9.372-24.568 9.372-33.941 0L394.343 343.598c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941l10.823-10.823c9.562-9.562 25.133-9.34 34.419.492L480 342.118V160H292.451a24.005 24.005 0 0 1-16.971-7.029l-16-16C244.361 121.851 255.069 96 276.451 96H520c13.255 0 24 10.745 24 24v222.118l40.416-42.792c9.285-9.831 24.856-10.054 34.419-.492l10.823 10.823c9.372 9.372 9.372 24.569-.001 33.941zm-265.138 15.431A23.999 23.999 0 0 0 347.548 352H160V169.881l40.416 42.792c9.286 9.831 24.856 10.054 34.419.491l10.822-10.822c9.373-9.373 9.373-24.569 0-33.941L144.971 67.716c-9.373-9.373-24.569-9.373-33.941 0L10.343 168.402c-9.373 9.373-9.373 24.569 0 33.941l10.822 10.822c9.562 9.562 25.133 9.34 34.419-.491L96 169.881V392c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h243.549c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-16.001-16z"></path>
      </svg> 23
    </span>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>For convenience, here are some of the links from the thread (auto-extracted):</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OqEeIG8aPPk">If Russ Ackoff had given a TED Talk… - YouTube</a><br>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCutCcajxhR33k9UR-DdLsAQ">Systems Innovation - YouTube</a><br>
<a href="https://www.systemsinnovation.io/">Systems Innovation Platform</a><br>
<a href="https://www.springer.com/gp/book/9784431556381">Systemic Design - Theory, Methods, and Practice | Peter Jones | Springer</a><br>
<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3828902-thinking-in-systems">Thinking in Systems: A Primer by Donella H. Meadows</a><br>
<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/255127.The_Fifth_Discipline">The Fifth Discipline: The Art &amp; Practice of The Learning Organization by Peter M. Senge</a><br>
<a href="https://www.amazon.in/Thinking-Systems-Donella-H-Meadows/dp/1603580557">Buy Thinking in Systems: A Primer Book Online at Low Prices in India | Thinking in Systems: A Primer Reviews &amp; Ratings - Amazon.in</a><br>
<a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Systems-Practice-Climate-Change-Climate-Change/dp/1849961247">Systems Practice: How to Act in a Climate Change World: How to Act in a Climate-Change World: Amazon.co.uk: Ison, Ray: 9781849961240: Books</a><br>
<a href="https://thesystemsthinker.com/author/">The Systems Thinker – Authors - The Systems Thinker</a><br>
<a href="https://systemic-design.net/publications/">Publications « Systemic Design Association</a><br>
<a href="https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/sloan-school-of-management/15-988-system-dynamics-self-study-fall-1998-spring-1999/">System Dynamics Self Study | Sloan School of Management | MIT OpenCourseWare</a><br>
<a href="https://namahn.com/tools/systemic-design-toolkit/">Systemic design toolkit – Namahn</a><br>
<a href="https://fs.blog/mental-models/">Mental Models: The Best Way to Make Intelligent Decisions (109 Models Explained)</a><br>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jay_Wright_Forrester">Jay Wright Forrester - Wikipedia</a><br>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Futures_wheel">Futures wheel - Wikipedia</a></p>
<p>and the text from many/most of the replies (n.b., there’s at least one useful photo you should visit twitter for):</p>
<p>“What would you consider to be the best content to learn systems design? (not design systems, but systems thinking)”<br>
“The Systems Thinker is another gold!”<br>
“Thinking in Systems: A Primer by Donella Meadows <a href="https://t.co/NLhEMYspHu">https://t.co/NLhEMYspHu</a> via <span class="mention">@amazonIN</span>”<br>
“<span class="mention">@killerswan</span> Fiction novel writing, biology and medicine history of discovery and errors, history of beginnings of airplanes/ space flight, people’s oriented history of events books, meteorology and weather prediction”<br>
“Reading Philosophy, specially thinkers that analyze structures and systems I.e Hegel, Marx, Deleuze, Foucault”<br>
“I’m working through Ray Ison’s Systems Practice (part of a Masters ) <a href="https://t.co/vBdX8DdoWD">https://t.co/vBdX8DdoWD</a> . Has the concepts that everyone else in the thread has mentioned.”<br>
“I’m listening to Team of Teams - this morning I made a note to read up more deliberately on <span class="hashtag">#systemsthinking</span> - very timely, thank you <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/pray.png?v=9" title=":pray:" class="emoji" alt=":pray:">”<br>
“Donella meadows dancing with systems.”<br>
“End of Average, Todd Rose is a great primer”<br>
“Can’t see a mention of Patricia Shaw in here anywhere &amp; she’s really interesting - takes stuff in a different direction. Also found Werner Ulrich useful when it comes to using systems thinking inside hierarchical organisations.”<br>
“Was Forrester mentioned? <a href="https://t.co/Jkqz4qDmHV">https://t.co/Jkqz4qDmHV</a>”<br>
“Lots of great suggestions! Also really important to consider consequences over time. I really like the futures wheel.\nhttps://t.co/EkOEYq3C7m”<br>
“Any content on category theory”<br>
“Take a look at the explanation of a “paradigm shift” in the novel Ham on Rye … anyone who reads that will always have a greater understanding of systems thinking”<br>
“<a href="https://t.co/31uK7B4sOR">https://t.co/31uK7B4sOR</a> is a gold mine, look for “systems” under mental models.”<br>
“1/2 Idealized Design by Ackoff for this particular question. I highly recommend NOT to start with 5th Discipline as it conflate broader concept of systmes thinking with system dynamics.”<br>
“Not just content but also a great community - <a href="https://t.co/QPyGfqOQVB">https://t.co/QPyGfqOQVB</a> with local chapters, organizing events, wokrshops and providing support to new system thinkers <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/wink.png?v=9" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:">”<br>
“+1 Meadows \nI also find Systems Innovation on YouTube useful: <a href="https://t.co/QZNbtO9QUr%5CnAnd">https://t.co/QZNbtO9QUr\nAnd</a> <span class="mention">@Sys_innovation</span> is  worth a follow”<br>
““System Design” and “Systems Thinking” are not the same thing.  But you can apply Systems Thinking to system design.  I can recommend “Systems Thinkers” (OU) as a good intro.  I would then first read “General System Theory” before diving into the different schools of thought.”<br>
“I was introduced to the subject by Meadows’ “Thinking in Systems” and I loved it.\n\nLater I realized that Factorio (video game) is a great way to represent a system in motion.”<br>
“Biology”<br>
“A lot has been shared here. Also check this and follow the links <a href="https://t.co/WtSvzJEhZy">https://t.co/WtSvzJEhZy</a>”<br>
“Thinking in Systems is the book that got me into system thinking. I have written a couple of Medium articles of this and UX, I’d be interested to find out what people think. <a href="https://t.co/PUb5XBhYbb">https://t.co/PUb5XBhYbb</a>”<br>
“this book defines product innovation as a complex adaptive system and introduces a framework for collaborative system thinking in the product field <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/point_down/2.png?v=9" title=":point_down:t2:" class="emoji" alt=":point_down:t2:">\n\nhttps://t.co/VoKpAlm3eP”<br>
“Would recommend this free course as well\nhttps://t.co/Y67FQnRacZ”<br>
“Semi related … \n\nScale by West\nhttps://t.co/6Lp1WCxZaM\n\nBook of Why\nhttps://t.co/34AUCiou1n\n\nHidden life of trees \nhttps://t.co/0sGp8WD4yv”<br>
“The Fifth Discipline, by Peter Senge <a href="https://t.co/DzAYdKFGS8">https://t.co/DzAYdKFGS8</a>”<br>
“<span class="mention">@ruthmalan</span> Systems Architecting - Creating &amp; Building Complex Systems by Eberhardt Rechtin, 1991”<br>
“Besides the usual:\n\n- The Systems View of Life (Fritjof Capra)\n- Strategic Modelling and Business Dynamics (John D. W. Morecroft)”<br>
“No Ackoff yet…  Start at minute 1:30; just 10 minutes… \nhttps://t.co/wknz8wpZle”<br>
“<span class="mention">@ruthmalan</span> I’m fairly new to this, but I’ve learned a lot from these books:\n- Thinking in Systems (Meadows)\n- The Fifth Discipline (Senge)\n- Design Unbound (Pendleton-Jullian &amp; Brown)\n- Drift into Failure (Dekker)\n\nAlso highly recommend “How Complex Systems Fail” <a href="https://t.co/rYY25VBHgx">https://t.co/rYY25VBHgx</a>”<br>
“Visual vocabulary of systems: <a href="https://t.co/afzoy08E7N">https://t.co/afzoy08E7N</a>”<br>
“I teach systems for interaction designers at CCA. I use chapters from all these books and my students read all of the Donella Meadows Thinking In Systems. There are tons of resources online from the Systems Thinker and Systems And Us sites. <a href="https://t.co/Xx7f68RQX3">https://t.co/Xx7f68RQX3</a>”<br>
“<span class="mention">@ruthmalan</span> “Dynamics in Action” by Alicia Juarrero is a great book on how minds can be understood as complex adaptive systems. It’s not about design, but it’s full of insight into complex systems. <a href="https://t.co/RnJdEsTHue">https://t.co/RnJdEsTHue</a>”<br>
“Hugh Dubberly’s blog has a lot of good content and links out to plenty of resources. <a href="https://t.co/yz5wH4ti0k">https://t.co/yz5wH4ti0k</a>”<br>
“<span class="mention">@ruthmalan</span> I would also suggest Pegasus Communications books like Study Notes in SD, <span class="mention">@tomfid</span>’s blog, MIT’s course <a href="https://t.co/MJZlh7kMnY">https://t.co/MJZlh7kMnY</a> and  Gene Bellinger’s resources <a href="https://t.co/iCgyOjHdON">https://t.co/iCgyOjHdON</a>”<br>
“<span class="mention">@ruthmalan</span> Please consider the work of <span class="mention">@NoraBateson</span>, <span class="hashtag">#Symmathesy</span>, <span class="hashtag">#WarmData</span>, putting the context back into Systems Thinking.\nIt’s not all boxes and arrows, after all.\nI hope that helps, it took me some years to begin to understand.”<br>
“I approach systems thinking through storytelling. Shows like The Wire (criminal justice system), Borgen (Danish politics system), and The Expanse (fictional future technological/political systems) are some good places to start.”<br>
“+1 on Meadows’s “Systems Thinking” primer. For a more actionable book, see “Growing Wings on the Way” by Rosalind Armson. This PDF is also useful: <a href="https://t.co/c9exyk5QyZ">https://t.co/c9exyk5QyZ</a>”<br>
“<span class="mention">@ruthmalan</span> To date I’ve preferred the older “book” units…as they conveniently integrate with the existing “shelf” systems I already have in place ;)”<br>
“I’d recommend a look at this book edited by <span class="mention">@redesign</span> et al: \n\nhttps://t.co/nGltNVhlTr\n\nAlso, see the proceedings of the RSD conferences.\nhttps://t.co/5AnAh8szOH\n\nLastly, everything by <span class="mention">@josinavink</span> and <span class="mention">@ManuelaAguirreU</span> is ace.”<br>
“Have you checked out the Systemic Design community &amp; events? <a href="https://t.co/PmJu3aP40F">https://t.co/PmJu3aP40F</a> Folks like <span class="mention">@DrAlexRyan</span> been working at that intersection for a long time. Also, <span class="mention">@snowded</span> and Cynefin, <span class="mention">@cyetain</span> &amp; whatever he’s riffing today, <span class="mention">@Terry_Irwin</span> <span class="mention">@camerontw</span> and work on transition design”<br>
“<a href="https://t.co/MtaDJD1cLR">https://t.co/MtaDJD1cLR</a>”<br>
“Donella H. Meadows, Leverage Points: Places to Intervene in a System (1997)\n\nJodi Forlizzi and Katja Battarbee, Understanding Experience in Interactive Systems (2004)”<br>
“<span class="mention">@jarango</span> might have ideas here”<br>
“And <span class="mention">@boonych</span> will have some good tips”<br>
“This is interesting and useful too: <a href="https://t.co/DCiXVU6sE3">https://t.co/DCiXVU6sE3</a>”<br>
“Watching eagerly for different recommendations than the usual. \n\nUsual suspects include ‘Thinking in systems’ \nhttps://t.co/CIO5V8OFGS or ‘the Fifth Discipline’ <a href="https://t.co/d2rV668TSY">https://t.co/d2rV668TSY</a>”<br>
“Really recommend this book. <a href="https://t.co/ktWQXz7JSe">https://t.co/ktWQXz7JSe</a>”</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/systems-design-systems-thinking-resources-from-twitter/511">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/systems-design-systems-thinking-resources-from-twitter/511</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 19:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-511</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/systems-design-systems-thinking-resources-from-twitter/511.rss">Systems Design / Systems Thinking Resources from Twitter</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Flotilla Project is Working on Directories</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/arena">@Arena</a> and I would like to low-key announce two things:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><a href="https://flotillaproject.xyz/project/flotilla-project/">Flotilla Project</a>, which will be doing some experiments around, and building working prototypes of, project, association, and people directories for OGM and other communities over the next few months.  The working name for these experiments is <a href="https://flotillaproject.xyz/">Flotilla</a>.  (That current website is a simple, hand-built placeholder, which just lists the two things we’re announcing - one of our first experiments.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://flotillaproject.xyz/association/tools-for-connectors-association/">Tools for Connectors Association</a>, which is a special interest group for makers, designers, and other people interested in tools and processes that help connect people, such as directories and matchmaking.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>We’re starting small – just Vincent and me.  We’d love to have other people join us, though!</p>
<p>After the 2020 holidays, we’re planning to have a weekly virtual open house, with a couple of hours of discussion and work, with everybody invited.</p>
<p>Keep in touch! Either in <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/flotilla-project-is-working-on-directories/503">OGM Forum/Flotilla Project is Working on Directories</a> or <a href="https://chat.collectivesensecommons.org/agora/channels/tools-for-connectors">CSC Mattermost/Tools for Connectors</a>.</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/flotilla-project-is-working-on-directories/503">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/flotilla-project-is-working-on-directories/503</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 04:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-503</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/flotilla-project-is-working-on-directories/503.rss">Flotilla Project is Working on Directories</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Making finance personal, or how is everyone doing?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[scottmoehring]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Discussions and Actions</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I have a couple goals with this post:</p>
<ul>
<li>Learn more about the diverse ways that others in our OGM community are supporting themselves.</li>
<li>See who might really be struggling, to help tune my radar for opportunities to help.</li>
<li><em>This is NOT intended as a post about “how OGM can make me money”. It’s about opening up a space to better understand, empathize, and support each other. Maybe that will involve direct OGM activity, but maybe not.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>On our Zoom calls I catch tidbits about everyone’s various projects and initiatives. I regularly wonder if OGMers are out in the world getting consulting or per-project fees, or retainers, or have salaried jobs, or hourly freelance rates, or grants, Patreon, blog ad income, book or other product sales, SAAS, retired, or maybe even are just unemployed and suffering.</p>
<p>I’ve only ever had financial success in the corporate grind. I lost a 13-year corporate middle-manager job in summer 2019. It was a job but not an identity, so I had no emotional distress. I was very fortunate to get a severance. After a long and unsuccessful job hunt, I woke up one morning this Spring and asked myself “if you thought you would never be offered another corporate job again, what would you do?”</p>
<p>I have never directly made money with my thinking. It brought me joy, but frankly, always got me in trouble. I would help other company departments facilitate ideation or process improvement. I was helping the company, but not staying in my lane or focusing on my assigned work, so it wasn’t encouraged. So, I formed small lunch learning groups, or taught useful skills to the children of friends. After decades of this, I had “learned” two lessons: 1) I will never stop building and sharing useful tools because it’s who I am, and 2) I won’t ever actually get paid for it, so I’d better find an income using my resume skills instead. Hey, not all lessons you learn are correct. <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>So, I finally decided to see if I could make a go on my own. It’s never worked before, but maybe I’m different now. I’m doing freelance graphic design and production art. I build art for retail signs, pinball restoration products, and some logos and websites. I’m now trying to develop some learning products I can maybe sell online.</p>
<p>We cut our expenses way back, but live pretty simply so we don’t feel like we are giving up anything important. A posture of gratitude goes a long way, because c’mon - in the long and challenging history of humanity, we’re lucky, and we know it. My “days until broke” spreadsheet has been awesome. Once a month I divide our Total Cash by our Average Daily Spend for the last 30 days. That gives us a single number - “Days Until Broke”. As long as it stays the same or nudges up each month, we’re good. Every check we get adds days to end. It kinda makes a game of it, and why not?</p>
<p>So, if you feel like sharing, how do you support yourself? I’m sincerely interested in whatever you feel comfortable sharing, with a particular curiosity about the different multi-stream recipes you’ve all found or built. Even more importantly, are you all ok?</p>
<p>– Scott</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/making-finance-personal-or-how-is-everyone-doing/501">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/making-finance-personal-or-how-is-everyone-doing/501</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 18:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-501</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/making-finance-personal-or-how-is-everyone-doing/501.rss">Making finance personal, or how is everyone doing?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Inside the Beltway</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[RobOK]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Knowledge Areas</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>As many of you know, I work in and around the Federal government, so I will try to post news and things of interest here.</p>
<p>Probably the most impactful and least understood process is the Budget, I myself am only a novice after 25 years!</p>
<p>While the President’s office makes a budget, it is more advisory and Congress takes it for input. There are different committees in the House and Senate that work on different aspects.</p>
<p>Here is one good resource:<br>
<a href="https://www.usa.gov/budget">Budget of the U.S. Government | USAGov</a></p>
<p>Different parts of the government are funded under different laws and they always have “interesting” names. The Defense budget is the <em>National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA) for FY2021</em>. Of course the Federal Fiscal Year for 2021 started in Oct 2020, so how is that possible that the government is running without a passed budget? They pass “Continuing Resolutions”. There was one that ran out Dec 11. Then they passed a 7 day which went to Dec 18 (Friday). Then they passed a two day to Sunday and another one day through today.</p>
<p>All the headlines were about the details of the $900 Billion relief package but no one even looks at the $1.4 Trillion budget, totally <strong>$2.3 Trillion</strong>.</p>
<p>It seems OGM could solve health, soil, and social justice with 2.3 Trillion USD!!</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inside-the-beltway/500">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inside-the-beltway/500</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 01:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-500</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inside-the-beltway/500.rss">Inside the Beltway</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>CyberSecurity hacks of note</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[RobOK]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Knowledge Areas</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>Subject: Cyber Security</strong></p>
<p>FireEye is a well known cyber security firm that got hacked pretty bad. They are the company that usually investigates and helps prevent attacks.</p>
<p>FireEye hack: Cybersecurity firm says nation-state stole attacking tools - CNET <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/fireeye-hack-cybersecurity-firm-says-nation-state-stole-attacking-tools">https://www.cnet.com/news/fireeye-hack-cybersecurity-firm-says-nation-state-stole-attacking-tools</a></p>
<p>Not so long after, FireEye detected another huge cyber attack via a Network Security tools company, SolarWinds. It is the wild west out there!!<br>
This is a highly technical write up of SolarWinds, there are less technical articles out there too<br>
</p><aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      
      <a href="https://www.fireeye.com/blog/threat-research/2020/12/evasive-attacker-leverages-solarwinds-supply-chain-compromises-with-sunburst-backdoor.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FireEye</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/42d93914e8301a8d84794b8a5ad0c2937ce31422.png" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h3><a href="https://www.fireeye.com/blog/threat-research/2020/12/evasive-attacker-leverages-solarwinds-supply-chain-compromises-with-sunburst-backdoor.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Highly Evasive Attacker Leverages SolarWinds Supply Chain to...</a></h3>

<p>We have discovered a global intrusion campaign, and we are tracking the actors behind this campaign as UNC2452.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            <p><small>2 posts - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/cybersecurity-hacks-of-note/494">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/cybersecurity-hacks-of-note/494</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 17:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-494</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/cybersecurity-hacks-of-note/494.rss">CyberSecurity hacks of note</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
