<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Giant Wholeness Egg, Redux</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/giant-wholeness-egg-redux/497</link>
    <description>Continuing the discussion from [Potential quests](https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492/2):

This is an experiment to see if using the template that we used in the OGM workshop is useful for describing quests, also.  (Thanks to @skreutzer for sparking this idea.) 

**1. Core Purpose:** The purpose of this project is to understand the context of OGM: and similarly, to contextualise the elements of this context relative to each other.
**2. Defining Characteristics:** The project uses the idea of wholeness, and, more specifically, the idea of *wholeness eggs* developed by Konomi Munakati and Takashi Iba, as a light-weight way to work with design pattern concepts. 
**3. Values:** Wholeness and also a non-hierarchical way of relating (e.g., OGM is just one of many &quot;centres&quot; that are relevant to the context in which OGM works).
**4. Scope of Work:** It&#39;s proposed that we write a paper for PLoP — which is another relevant part of the context — before July 12th, and that we then waive the copyright so that the work can be contributed to the Peeragogy Handbook and otherwise used as widely as possible.
**5. Participants:** Participants in the OGM Group 1 workshop have already contributed to the OGM egg. I&#39;ll reach out to the Peeragogy project members to ask them to work on the Peeragogy portion. We might reach out to Konomi &amp; Takashi to make a contribution; and so on, across other relevant parts of OGM&#39;s context.
**6. Strategic Objectives:** The process of contextualization is potentially un-ending, so figuring out what a good &quot;stopping condition&quot; is will be a key objective.  Another good question is whether the template (used here!) is the right one for other projects.
**7. Key Operating Principles and Practices:** Contributors should be willing to sign the CC Zero waive, write in the spirit of gift culture, and think critically and constructively about design pattern methods.
**8. Sustainability Model:** To meet the goal of presenting at PLoP, the paper-writing process needs to be sustained through to submission; someone will have to attend the conference (which costs money and may require travel, depending on various factors). That said, many contributors will only need to spend ≈1 day working on the paper (assuming a similar workshop format to the one we did with Group 1).  The results should be of significant benefit to OGM — in terms of understanding the context in which they are operating.  As such, writing the paper could contribute to OGM&#39;s https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/sustainability-model/421</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 11:48:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Designing the System</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/giant-wholeness-egg-redux/497.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Giant Wholeness Egg, Redux</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492/2">Potential quests</a>:</p>
<p>This is an experiment to see if using the template that we used in the OGM workshop is useful for describing quests, also.  (Thanks to <a class="mention" href="/u/skreutzer">@skreutzer</a> for sparking this idea.)</p>
<p><strong>1. Core Purpose:</strong> The purpose of this project is to understand the context of OGM: and similarly, to contextualise the elements of this context relative to each other.<br>
<strong>2. Defining Characteristics:</strong> The project uses the idea of wholeness, and, more specifically, the idea of <em>wholeness eggs</em> developed by Konomi Munakati and Takashi Iba, as a light-weight way to work with design pattern concepts.<br>
<strong>3. Values:</strong> Wholeness and also a non-hierarchical way of relating (e.g., OGM is just one of many “centres” that are relevant to the context in which OGM works).<br>
<strong>4. Scope of Work:</strong> It’s proposed that we write a paper for PLoP — which is another relevant part of the context — before July 12th, and that we then waive the copyright so that the work can be contributed to the Peeragogy Handbook and otherwise used as widely as possible.<br>
<strong>5. Participants:</strong> Participants in the OGM Group 1 workshop have already contributed to the OGM egg. I’ll reach out to the Peeragogy project members to ask them to work on the Peeragogy portion. We might reach out to Konomi &amp; Takashi to make a contribution; and so on, across other relevant parts of OGM’s context.<br>
<strong>6. Strategic Objectives:</strong> The process of contextualization is potentially un-ending, so figuring out what a good “stopping condition” is will be a key objective.  Another good question is whether the template (used here!) is the right one for other projects.<br>
<strong>7. Key Operating Principles and Practices:</strong> Contributors should be willing to sign the CC Zero waive, write in the spirit of gift culture, and think critically and constructively about design pattern methods.<br>
<strong>8. Sustainability Model:</strong> To meet the goal of presenting at PLoP, the paper-writing process needs to be sustained through to submission; someone will have to attend the conference (which costs money and may require travel, depending on various factors). That said, many contributors will only need to spend ≈1 day working on the paper (assuming a similar workshop format to the one we did with Group 1).  The results should be of significant benefit to OGM — in terms of understanding the context in which they are operating.  As such, writing the paper could contribute to OGM’s <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/sustainability-model/421" class="inline-onebox">Sustainability Model</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/giant-wholeness-egg-redux/497/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/giant-wholeness-egg-redux/497/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 01:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-497-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/giant-wholeness-egg-redux/497.rss">Giant Wholeness Egg, Redux</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
