<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction: Hank Nelson</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-hank-nelson/77</link>
    <description>* **Where on the globe are you?** Moving soon to Boston, MA
* **What is your main gig?** Solution Design Partner at Collective Next (https://collectivenext.com/)
* **LinkedIn link:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/bradley-h-nelson/ (it&#39;s a little outdated)
* **What is your connection to OGM? What part interests you most?** I met Jerry back in March and the rest is history! I like that OGM provides a place for people who to think, learn, and grow. I just find it so thrilling that the conversations can go from philosophy to somatics to education within 5 minutes. I&#39;m most interested in exploring my own passions and interests alongside others doing the same. Something good has to come out of that.
*  **What are your superpowers?** Personally, I&#39;m still figuring that out. I am a deep thinker, good listener, and do things very intentionally. I think that leads to a simple faith in success that I can tap into. I can get enthusiastic about almost anything (within moral boundaries, of course). f you have an idea you want to pursue and you really believe in it, I will do everything I can to make that happen. I try to always look at things from multiple perspectives and have little patience for willful ignorance. To speak tactically, I have a lot of experience designing user flows, developing business cases, coordinating global teams, and the business side of software delivery. As such, I have written my fair share of compelling feature narratives to illustrate the importance of moving a pop-up window :slightly_smiling_face: (though I&#39;ve done some more exciting things too).</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 03:21:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Introductions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-hank-nelson/77.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Introduction: Hank Nelson</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Howdy, Hank! <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-hank-nelson/77/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-hank-nelson/77/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 03:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-77-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-hank-nelson/77.rss">Introduction: Hank Nelson</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Introduction: Hank Nelson</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[bhnelson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <ul>
<li>
<strong>Where on the globe are you?</strong> Moving soon to Boston, MA</li>
<li>
<strong>What is your main gig?</strong> Solution Design Partner at Collective Next (<a href="https://collectivenext.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://collectivenext.com/</a>)</li>
<li>
<strong>LinkedIn link:</strong> <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/bradley-h-nelson/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.linkedin.com/in/bradley-h-nelson/</a> (it’s a little outdated)</li>
<li>
<strong>What is your connection to OGM? What part interests you most?</strong> I met Jerry back in March and the rest is history! I like that OGM provides a place for people who to think, learn, and grow. I just find it so thrilling that the conversations can go from philosophy to somatics to education within 5 minutes. I’m most interested in exploring my own passions and interests alongside others doing the same. Something good has to come out of that.</li>
<li>
<strong>What are your superpowers?</strong> Personally, I’m still figuring that out. I am a deep thinker, good listener, and do things very intentionally. I think that leads to a simple faith in success that I can tap into. I can get enthusiastic about almost anything (within moral boundaries, of course). f you have an idea you want to pursue and you really believe in it, I will do everything I can to make that happen. I try to always look at things from multiple perspectives and have little patience for willful ignorance. To speak tactically, I have a lot of experience designing user flows, developing business cases, coordinating global teams, and the business side of software delivery. As such, I have written my fair share of compelling feature narratives to illustrate the importance of moving a pop-up window <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/slightly_smiling_face.png?v=9" title=":slightly_smiling_face:" class="emoji" alt=":slightly_smiling_face:"> (though I’ve done some more exciting things too).</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-hank-nelson/77/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-hank-nelson/77/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 22:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-77-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/introduction-hank-nelson/77.rss">Introduction: Hank Nelson</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
