<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Designing the System - Open Global Mind Forum</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/designing-the-system/9</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Designing the System&#39; category We’re designing and building OGM as we fly it. This is where we do that.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:41:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/designing-the-system/9.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>engelbart-burroughs tenuous connection</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[lovolution]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System_Development_Corporation?wprov=sfti1" rel="nofollow noopener">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/System_Development_Corporation?wprov=sfti1</a> here because of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Augmentation_Research_Center?wprov=sfti1" rel="nofollow noopener">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Augmentation_Research_Center?wprov=sfti1</a> catching my attention also as i grew up in santa monica i see they were acquired initially by burroughs corp (80-86) … which connects them to william burroughs although he didn’t share in those profits …<br>
thought <a class="mention" href="/u/holtzermann17">@holtzermann17</a> <a class="mention" href="/u/skreutzer">@skreutzer</a>. et al may appreciate</p>
<p>third mind indeed, maybe there’s something of a clue here in Designing the System</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/engelbart-burroughs-tenuous-connection/554">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/engelbart-burroughs-tenuous-connection/554</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-554</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/engelbart-burroughs-tenuous-connection/554.rss">engelbart-burroughs tenuous connection</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Beam Manifeso</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[jackpark]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Tools</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://getonbeam.medium.com/beam-bright-paper-1ca4ae41ae0b" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" title="11:26AM - 22 October 2020">Medium – 22 Oct 20</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/338;"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/7e6b399a000263c678d8d6128ef19de8f64e0dfc_2_690x338.png" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="338" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/7e6b399a000263c678d8d6128ef19de8f64e0dfc_2_690x338.png, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/7e6b399a000263c678d8d6128ef19de8f64e0dfc_2_1035x507.png 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/7e6b399a000263c678d8d6128ef19de8f64e0dfc.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/7e6b399a000263c678d8d6128ef19de8f64e0dfc_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://getonbeam.medium.com/beam-bright-paper-1ca4ae41ae0b" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Beam: bright Paper</a></h3>

<p>We believe in tools, and the people who use them. We believe in tools that foster autonomy, encourage inquisitiveness, strengthen personal…</p>

  <p><span class="label1">Reading time: 2 min read</span>
    </p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            <p><small>7 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/beam-manifeso/549">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/beam-manifeso/549</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 16:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-549</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/beam-manifeso/549.rss">Beam Manifeso</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The High-Level Goal of OGM?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tony]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Organizing OGM</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all:</p>
<p>I am creating activity diagrams on what OGM does.  I seek feedback.   I have heard that the high-level goal of OGM is to solve the worlds major problems.</p>
<p>Agree?   What is the approach?</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-high-level-goal-of-ogm/547">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-high-level-goal-of-ogm/547</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 13:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-547</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-high-level-goal-of-ogm/547.rss">The High-Level Goal of OGM?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Activity (and other) Diagrams of OGM</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey, so if you want to see a little bit of sausage-making, <a class="mention" href="/u/tony">@Tony</a> and I have a small project/quest to create activity diagrams of OGM (or at least, parts of it).</p>
<p>Tony is the Activity Diagrammer.</p>
<p>I have been a Subject Matter Expert in OGM and some of its activities, tools, and processes.</p>
<p>We’ve had two zoom calls this week, sharing diagrams, drawings, tables, and of course, talking through things.  We don’t have recordings of the talking, but there are digital artifacts which do persist.  I’ll share them as the imperfect, in-process, and incomplete tracks and traces through the forest we’ve taken that they are.  At some future point, we may end up with more finished activity diagrams, we’ll see.</p>
            <p><small>14 posts - 7 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/activity-and-other-diagrams-of-ogm/540">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/activity-and-other-diagrams-of-ogm/540</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 20:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-540</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/activity-and-other-diagrams-of-ogm/540.rss">Activity (and other) Diagrams of OGM</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>&#39;Peeragogy Quest&#39;, Deluxe</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests-reducks/519/2">Potential quests, reducks</a>:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="holtzermann17" data-post="2" data-topic="519">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/user_avatar/forum.openglobalmind.com/holtzermann17/40/162_2.png" class="avatar"><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests-reducks/519/2">Potential quests, reducks</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Project Name:</strong> The Peeragogy Project<br>
<strong>Envisioned goal:</strong> Sources differ, but one goal would be to create a free, degree granting online university, peeragogy.edu.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>A somewhat thought-through discussion of this goal is on offer in the paper “<a href="https://dlnext.acm.org/doi/abs/10.5555/3124497.3124531" rel="nofollow noopener">Patterns of Peeragogy</a>”. As for why it matters, one go-to source is the NYT article “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/26/opinion/amazon-rainforest-fire.html" rel="nofollow noopener">How to Save the Amazon Without Condescending to Brazil</a>” by  Roberto Mangabeira Unger:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The only system with a chance of saving both the people and the trees is a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/16/opinion/what-do-we-actually-know-about-the-economy-wonkish.html" rel="nofollow noopener">knowledge economy</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That’s not going to magically happen without some effort.  Peeragogy, as a synthesis of peer learning and peer production can help.  BUT the available time is limited, hence a call to action. Obviously there are lots of other calls to action around “ecology”, “citizen action” and so on; Peeragogy — like some of the other efforts around OGM — should ideally help many such efforts work better.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="holtzermann17" data-post="2" data-topic="519">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/user_avatar/forum.openglobalmind.com/holtzermann17/40/162_2.png" class="avatar"><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests-reducks/519/2">Potential quests, reducks</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Other potential outcomes:</strong> Short of creating a new university, we can still create great online learning environments and activities; in particular we document how other people do this, and amass a catalogue of “good practice”. Historically we’ve done this in the Peeragogy Handbook (<a href="https://peeragogy.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">peeragogy.org</a>), with “semi-regular” new editions documenting what we learn.<br>
<strong>Time available:</strong> ∞ or 5 years, depending on who you ask<br>
<strong>Accountability structure among participants:</strong> We ask participants to adhere to a set of <a href="https://lists.peeragogy.org/pipermail/peeragogy-handbook/Week-of-Mon-20201130/000001.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Community Guidelines</a>. Contributors to the Peeragogy Handbook need to sign the <a href="https://peeragogy.org/license.html" rel="nofollow noopener">CC0 Waiver</a> which permits unlimited reuse.<br>
<strong>Any associated Mini-Quests:</strong> For the 4th Edition of the Peeragogy Handbook we want to produce a collection of “mini-Handbooks” that can help people solve various practical problems. We need more examples!</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I’ll mention that I’m “live blogging” a plan of revisions for the Peeragogy Handbook v4 via the “Peeragogy-Handbook” mailing list: <a href="https://lists.peeragogy.org/mailman/listinfo/peeragogy-handbook" rel="nofollow noopener">https://lists.peeragogy.org/mailman/listinfo/peeragogy-handbook</a> — in effect, the small “actions” I’m describing there are mini-Handbooks (but for contributors rather than passive readers).  I thank <a class="mention" href="/u/lovolution">@lovolution</a> <a class="mention" href="/u/skreutzer">@skreutzer</a> and others who participated in the MetaCAugs/Augment Reading Group in November 2019 for taking on a significant “editorial” role!</p>
<p>That’s is an important part of the workflow that we only figured out ≈3 years after publishing the latest edition of the Handbook!  Hopefully we can reduce the cycle time for the 4th Ed.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="holtzermann17" data-post="2" data-topic="519">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/user_avatar/forum.openglobalmind.com/holtzermann17/40/162_2.png" class="avatar"><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests-reducks/519/2">Potential quests, reducks</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Next Steps:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Having created this “potential quest” description as an example, I would like to receive any <strong>feedback</strong> on whether or not it works as a call to action. I am not afraid to “fail” publicly so if it doesn’t really work, please give constructive feedback. One of my aims with this example is to help figure out what a good way to describe “quests” (in general) is (although I do not specifically find the terminology 100% applicable, e.g., in the ∞ mode of the Peeragogy project, we dispense with notions like “goals” and look at learning in pure process terms).</li>
<li>Concretely, one way to get your feet wet would be to watch/listen to our upcoming podcast on Data Ethics, to stream January 13th, 1500 UTC (<a href="https://youtu.be/v15f07e0ahQ" rel="nofollow noopener">https://youtu.be/v15f07e0ahQ</a>) — This is our 5th podcast episode and OGM would be an interesting topic for a future one!</li>
<li>And we invite contributions to the Peeragogy Handbook from interested participants</li>
<li>… And we have numerous other activities going on across software, writing, editing, media production, teaching, etc., so if you’re interested, just ask me.</li>
<li>One additional interesting thing about Peeragogy is that we’re currently revitalising our method of using “design patterns” to manage next steps.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I hope that some people will take me up on my request for feedback/critique. It would be nice to have a cohort of quest-level “peers” so that we could learn from each other at the project level. Is OGM itself a quest? Are there others?</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="holtzermann17" data-post="2" data-topic="519">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/user_avatar/forum.openglobalmind.com/holtzermann17/40/162_2.png" class="avatar"><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests-reducks/519/2">Potential quests, reducks</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>How the world was before and what sparked the journey (why this matters):</strong> Before peeragogy, there was a prototype, “paragogy”: and before paragogy, there was no identified practical theory of online peer produced peer learning. (There was Benkler’s admirable theory of peer production, which served as inspiration, and Knowles’s theory of “andragogy” which served as a kind of interlocutor.) This meant that organizations that were doing peer learning were trying “whatever” and efforts to build and share good practices were limited. This matters because, while we have great state-sanctioned resources like <em>the public domain</em> , these don’t come with instructions! Furthermore, in terms of a “need” the world has many giant problems (too many to list here) that are going to require adaptation and learning at a collective level.<br>
<strong>What the great challenge was/is (what it is):</strong> Creating the Handbook is an example that has served to get the process started. Increasingly, the Handbook is now accompanied by software and other media, which will help us make the material accessible and applicable to as many people as possible. But, the scaling up process is still a bit “stuck”: e.g., we haven’t yet used the Handbook as a textbook in a formal course. Furthermore finding contributors who want to engage with this process can be difficult, even though it <em>should (perhaps) be</em> easy. Create a thriving global collaboration based on “sharing” and “learning” — these Kindergarten concepts — is certainly possible! But doing this in a timely fashion could use the help/input of more people.<br>
<strong>What attracted the powerful collaboration (who’s involved and the pieces they bring):</strong> Some of the most involved participants have been Charlie Danoff, Howard Rheingold, Charlotte Pierce, Paola Ricaurte, and Lisa Snow McDonald. Over 30 people have signed the waiver, and many more have joined discussions. Stephan Kreutzer has been taking the lead on software support in the sense of a “neutral data department”. We also have support from the Oregon State University Open Source Lab.<br>
<strong>What is the world we envision after (outcomes):</strong> Considered as a “question”, it goes something like this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>would it be possible for everyone in the world to have access to high-quality learning support, so that we could do away with the old exclusive models of education, and help everyone find meaningful work, that is, moreover, in harmony with nature?</em></p>
</blockquote>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Any ideas about who are the “problem holders” here?  I suppose I could reach out to R.M. Unger… his Nesta Whitepaper also seems relevant: <a href="https://www.nesta.org.uk/report/imagination-unleashed/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.nesta.org.uk/report/imagination-unleashed/</a></p>
<p>An obvious point of critique is that something on a ≈5 year scale needs to be broken down into smaller bite-sized pieces to become more actionable.  Are these also quests, or are they merely “tasks”?  Either way, part of the breakdown should also be some attention towards making them meaningful/valuable — so far, “learning” has been the main incentive in focus, but some of my other efforts also try to engage with peer production as an economic force: that’s described at <a href="https://hyperreal.enterprises/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://hyperreal.enterprises/</a> with ongoing work appearing at <a href="https://exp2exp.github.io/index.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://exp2exp.github.io/index.html</a> and brief updates at <a href="https://exp2exp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="nofollow noopener">https://exp2exp.github.io/feed.xml</a>.</p>
<p>I want to emphasise that as a “call to action” there are many options here: reading, reflection, discourse, writing, viewing, criticising…</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-quest-deluxe/534">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-quest-deluxe/534</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 09:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-534</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-quest-deluxe/534.rss">&#39;Peeragogy Quest&#39;, Deluxe</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Why isn&#39;t there a long line at the library?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[scottmoehring]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The library gives away high value things every day. For free. Access to more useful information on virtually any subject than one can consume in a lifetime. So why isn’t there a line out the door?</p>
<p>Because you have to do the work. The books don’t read themselves, and there’s no shortcut.</p>
<p>Because the time between the effort and the return is often delayed and nonlinear.</p>
<p>Because you don’t get “credit” for education outside of institutions, in the sense of a degree or certification.</p>
<p>Feel free to swap “library” with “YouTube”, “MIT Open Courseware”, “Wikipedia”, “Jerry’s Brain” or any other freely accessible, roam-able, educational resource.</p>
<p>I think this is something to consider as we build information platforms. Is the problem the access, repository, the information? Or is it something bigger, like the mindset of potential patrons?</p>
            <p><small>15 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/why-isnt-there-a-long-line-at-the-library/530">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/why-isnt-there-a-long-line-at-the-library/530</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 19:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-530</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/why-isnt-there-a-long-line-at-the-library/530.rss">Why isn&#39;t there a long line at the library?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Potential quests, reducks</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492/16">Potential quests</a>:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="holtzermann17" data-post="1" data-topic="492">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/user_avatar/forum.openglobalmind.com/holtzermann17/40/162_2.png" class="avatar"><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492/1">Potential quests</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Project Name:</strong><br>
<strong>Envisioned goal:</strong><br>
<strong>Other potential outcomes:</strong><br>
<strong>Time available:</strong><br>
<strong>Accountability structure among participants:</strong><br>
<strong>Any associated Mini-Quests:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Next Steps:</strong></p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="JayGolden" data-post="16" data-topic="492">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/j/46a35a/40.png" class="avatar"><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492/16">Potential quests</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>How the world was before and what sparked the journey (why this matters):</strong><br>
<strong>What the great challenge was/is (what it is):</strong><br>
<strong>What attracted the powerful collaboration (who’s involved and the pieces they bring):</strong><br>
<strong>What is the world we envision after (outcomes):</strong></p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/b60b9d234cf96b3a4485025cbd4af6af0a7a6849.jpeg" data-download-href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/b60b9d234cf96b3a4485025cbd4af6af0a7a6849" title="Eurasian_Cranes_migrating_to_Meyghan_Salt_Lake"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/b60b9d234cf96b3a4485025cbd4af6af0a7a6849_2_666x500.jpeg" alt="Eurasian_Cranes_migrating_to_Meyghan_Salt_Lake" data-base62-sha1="pYrMusaf57DXVQ1EGX9KQn3w7Vf" width="666" height="500" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/b60b9d234cf96b3a4485025cbd4af6af0a7a6849_2_666x500.jpeg, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/b60b9d234cf96b3a4485025cbd4af6af0a7a6849_2_999x750.jpeg 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/b60b9d234cf96b3a4485025cbd4af6af0a7a6849.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/b60b9d234cf96b3a4485025cbd4af6af0a7a6849_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Eurasian_Cranes_migrating_to_Meyghan_Salt_Lake</span><span class="informations">1024×768 291 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div><br>
(These are cranes.)</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests-reducks/519">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests-reducks/519</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 16:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-519</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests-reducks/519.rss">Potential quests, reducks</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Clubhouse - the &quot;hot&quot; voice chat social media platform</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[RobOK]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Tools</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Seems to be big in tech and entertainment communities, growing crypto too.</p>
<p>Invite only, but they have been rapidly scaling.</p>
<p>I could see OGM disucssions held on there and opening up to many new comers to ask questions etc.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/05/20/clubhouse-app-is-where-mc-hammer-and-jared-leto-chat-with-vcs.html">Clubhouse: Buzzy Silicon Valley social media app worth $100 million (cnbc.com)</a></p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/clubhouse-the-hot-voice-chat-social-media-platform/516">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/clubhouse-the-hot-voice-chat-social-media-platform/516</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 23:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-516</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/clubhouse-the-hot-voice-chat-social-media-platform/516.rss">Clubhouse - the &quot;hot&quot; voice chat social media platform</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Maybe OGM is a budding &quot;Network City&quot;</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[RobOK]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Organizing OGM</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Balaji describes a new form of country emerging. An example that made me think…</p>
<p>Amazon and some other companies have power to negotiate with existing localities to negotiate rules and exceptions (no taxes, special treatment). What if 1000 or 10,000 people formed a consortium with governance and expectations and committed resources (likely crypto currency in a smart contract), could they negotiate new rules too. Could this evolve into being new “countries” (using quotes as they would be something else not in existence yet).</p>
<p>I am totally butchering this, but hopefully you get the idea. From this podcast episode…</p>
<p><a href="http://podcast.banklesshq.com/41-crypto-civilization-balaji-srinivasan">Bankless: 41 - Crypto-Civilization | Balaji Srinivasan (banklesshq.com)</a></p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/maybe-ogm-is-a-budding-network-city/515">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/maybe-ogm-is-a-budding-network-city/515</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 19:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-515</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/maybe-ogm-is-a-budding-network-city/515.rss">Maybe OGM is a budding &quot;Network City&quot;</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Workflowy launches Mirror Topics</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Tools</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><em>(I wonder, a little, if this will be the next “backlinks like Roam” thing…)</em></p>
<p><a href="https://workflowy.com/feature/mirrors/">Say Hello to Mirror Bullets</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>We’re excited to announce a brand new feature in WorkFlowy called  <strong>Mirrors</strong> ! With mirrors you can create  <strong>live copies</strong>  of any bullet and put them anywhere you like, and any change you make to a mirror will be automatically updated across any other mirror you have.</p>
</blockquote>
            <p><small>5 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/workflowy-launches-mirror-topics/514">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/workflowy-launches-mirror-topics/514</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 18:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-514</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/workflowy-launches-mirror-topics/514.rss">Workflowy launches Mirror Topics</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>History of Web Annotation</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Tools</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I wanted to start a resource topic about the history of web annotation.</p>
<p>Back in the day, I hung out with some of the people (centered around Ka-Ping Yee) doing Crit/CritSuite, but much info of which has link-rotted away:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://foresight.org/WebEnhance/">Enhancing the World Wide Web</a></li>
<li><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20010421051642/http://crit.org/~ping/ht98.html">CritLink: Better Hyperlinks for the WWW</a></li>
</ul>
<p>A little later, there was Third Voice:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.doc.ic.ac.uk/~ids/dotdot/misc/research_related/AnnotatingTheWeb/locally_hosted_annotations/CritSuite_got_there_before_Third_Voice.html">CritSuite got there before Third Voice!</a></li>
</ul>
<p>I remember using Third Voice a little, too.</p>
<p>Nowadays, there is Hypothesis:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://web.hypothes.is/">Hypothesis</a></li>
</ul>
<p>One of the wonderments of the WWW for me is that web annotation has never become first class.</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/history-of-web-annotation/508">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/history-of-web-annotation/508</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 17:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-508</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/history-of-web-annotation/508.rss">History of Web Annotation</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Inviting an OGM chapter for Peeragogy Handbook v4</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492/14">Potential quests</a>:</p>
<p>We are starting to get a bit serious about revisions of <a href="http://peeragogy.org" rel="nofollow noopener">PHv3</a>. One of the questions in play is what contributions for v4 will look like.</p>
<p>An early outline and list of requests is here: <a href="https://github.com/PeeragogyLabs/PeeragogyORG/blob/main/peeragogy_handbook_v4.org" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/PeeragogyLabs/PeeragogyORG/blob/main/peeragogy_handbook_v4.org</a></p>
<p>It would be nice to have an “OGM chapter”, conceiving of OGM as an early-stage peeragogical community that may have some use for the existing patterns and/or may go its own way (or both).  Perhaps most likely it would fit as a Case Study, without too many restrictions on the form.</p>
<p>Since late 2019 one of the ideas has been to “patternize” the Handbook (i.e., more patterns), so <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/ogm-workshop-group-1-output/413">new OGM patterns</a> could  (also) be included.  Another thing we’re keen to do is to include “mini-Handbooks” — so for example a short guide on how-to-OGM would be interesting to include!  Contributed chapters probably won’t be “due” until half-way into 2021, but draft material can already be workshopped (fortnightly writers workshop meetings to start early next year, details will follow once that’s scheduled). Another way to source some preliminary draft material could be via a guest interview on the Peeragogy in Action podcast!  So, lots of optinons &amp; support available for those who might like to undertake this mission.</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inviting-an-ogm-chapter-for-peeragogy-handbook-v4/507">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inviting-an-ogm-chapter-for-peeragogy-handbook-v4/507</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 12:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-507</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/inviting-an-ogm-chapter-for-peeragogy-handbook-v4/507.rss">Inviting an OGM chapter for Peeragogy Handbook v4</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Giant Wholeness Egg, Redux</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492/2">Potential quests</a>:</p>
<p>This is an experiment to see if using the template that we used in the OGM workshop is useful for describing quests, also.  (Thanks to <a class="mention" href="/u/skreutzer">@skreutzer</a> for sparking this idea.)</p>
<p><strong>1. Core Purpose:</strong> The purpose of this project is to understand the context of OGM: and similarly, to contextualise the elements of this context relative to each other.<br>
<strong>2. Defining Characteristics:</strong> The project uses the idea of wholeness, and, more specifically, the idea of <em>wholeness eggs</em> developed by Konomi Munakati and Takashi Iba, as a light-weight way to work with design pattern concepts.<br>
<strong>3. Values:</strong> Wholeness and also a non-hierarchical way of relating (e.g., OGM is just one of many “centres” that are relevant to the context in which OGM works).<br>
<strong>4. Scope of Work:</strong> It’s proposed that we write a paper for PLoP — which is another relevant part of the context — before July 12th, and that we then waive the copyright so that the work can be contributed to the Peeragogy Handbook and otherwise used as widely as possible.<br>
<strong>5. Participants:</strong> Participants in the OGM Group 1 workshop have already contributed to the OGM egg. I’ll reach out to the Peeragogy project members to ask them to work on the Peeragogy portion. We might reach out to Konomi &amp; Takashi to make a contribution; and so on, across other relevant parts of OGM’s context.<br>
<strong>6. Strategic Objectives:</strong> The process of contextualization is potentially un-ending, so figuring out what a good “stopping condition” is will be a key objective.  Another good question is whether the template (used here!) is the right one for other projects.<br>
<strong>7. Key Operating Principles and Practices:</strong> Contributors should be willing to sign the CC Zero waive, write in the spirit of gift culture, and think critically and constructively about design pattern methods.<br>
<strong>8. Sustainability Model:</strong> To meet the goal of presenting at PLoP, the paper-writing process needs to be sustained through to submission; someone will have to attend the conference (which costs money and may require travel, depending on various factors). That said, many contributors will only need to spend ≈1 day working on the paper (assuming a similar workshop format to the one we did with Group 1).  The results should be of significant benefit to OGM — in terms of understanding the context in which they are operating.  As such, writing the paper could contribute to OGM’s <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/sustainability-model/421" class="inline-onebox">Sustainability Model</a></p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/giant-wholeness-egg-redux/497">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/giant-wholeness-egg-redux/497</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 01:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-497</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/giant-wholeness-egg-redux/497.rss">Giant Wholeness Egg, Redux</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Potential quests</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/designing-quests/491">Designing Quests</a>:</p>
<p>Turing the remarks from <a class="mention" href="/u/jerry">@Jerry</a> into a template:</p>
<p><strong>Project Name:</strong><br>
<strong>Envisioned goal:</strong><br>
<strong>Other potential outcomes:</strong><br>
<strong>Time available:</strong><br>
<strong>Accountability structure among participants:</strong><br>
<strong>Any associated Mini-Quests:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Next Steps:</strong></p>
            <p><small>19 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 13:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-492</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/potential-quests/492.rss">Potential quests</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Designing Quests</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>An OGM Quest is a project that has an envisioned goal. Quests are time-bounded, and require closer participation and more internal accountability.</p>
<p>Most Quests are external, meaning they cause change in the broader world, but some are internal, such as Free Jerry’s Brain and our choices of conversational platforms.</p>
<p>Quests may contain mini-Quests (which may not be the best name). For example, a Quest called Regenerating the Food System might include sub-Quests on hacking social support networks for farmers wanting to go regenerative, and hardware specs for open-source Soil Organic Matter meters.</p>
<p>Guilds, in contrast, are longstanding trades and crafts. Guild members participate in Quests, as they are moved to.</p>
<p>Really fruitful Quests may turn into new lines of business, new bodies of open-source code or big dents in world problems. That’s the goal.</p>
<p>Quests can choose how they prefer to communicate, but they are bound to report back to the main body of OGM with progress, as well as pointers to their conversations, so that others may join.</p>
<p>To this end, Quests run independently, setting up their own calls and tasks.</p>
            <p><small>13 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/designing-quests/491">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/designing-quests/491</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 06:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-491</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/designing-quests/491.rss">Designing Quests</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Lessons learned on collaborative rich text editor dev</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[jackpark]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/4ec8a5eee10be37d37e44912d21960b81b87c00d.png" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://ckeditor.com/blog/Lessons-learned-from-creating-a-rich-text-editor-with-real-time-collaboration/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">ckeditor.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/388;"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/251c635ebabb5791e89e412b7680a58fa1e45f7d_2_690x388.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="388" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/251c635ebabb5791e89e412b7680a58fa1e45f7d_2_690x388.jpeg, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/251c635ebabb5791e89e412b7680a58fa1e45f7d_2_1035x582.jpeg 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/251c635ebabb5791e89e412b7680a58fa1e45f7d_2_1380x776.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/251c635ebabb5791e89e412b7680a58fa1e45f7d_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://ckeditor.com/blog/Lessons-learned-from-creating-a-rich-text-editor-with-real-time-collaboration/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Lessons learned from creating a rich-text editor with real-time collaboration</a></h3>

<p>Real-time collaboration is a feature we wanted to introduce since the inception of CKEditor 5. The research that we made back in 2012 and some failed attempts that we observed all around showed us that full support for collaborative editing for...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>This article describes how real-time collaborative editing was implemented in CKEditor 5. The terms “collaboration” and “real-time collaborative editing” are used interchangeably throughout the document to refer to “real real-time collaboration” as implemented by CKEditor 5.</p>
<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25394609" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25394609</a></p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/lessons-learned-on-collaborative-rich-text-editor-dev/488">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/lessons-learned-on-collaborative-rich-text-editor-dev/488</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 20:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-488</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/lessons-learned-on-collaborative-rich-text-editor-dev/488.rss">Lessons learned on collaborative rich text editor dev</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Needs and Tendencies — &quot;What people are trying to do&quot;</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/core-purpose/414/3">Core purpose</a>:</p>
<p>From:</p>
<p>Alexander, C., &amp; Poyner, B. (1970). The atoms of environmental structure. In G. Moore (Ed.), <em>Emerging Methods in Environmental Design and Planning</em> (p. 308–321). MIT Press. Archived scan: <a href="http://metameso.org/~joe/docs/Atoms.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">http://metameso.org/~joe/docs/Atoms.pdf</a></p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/dc1ec2035c12f6ef3da539cde513b5b1ea387121.png" data-download-href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/dc1ec2035c12f6ef3da539cde513b5b1ea387121" title="Screenshot from 2020-12-08 18-09-56"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dc1ec2035c12f6ef3da539cde513b5b1ea387121_2_690x238.png" alt="Screenshot from 2020-12-08 18-09-56" data-base62-sha1="vpgWoJqEBohllIiY1oIsVZAgHS1" width="690" height="238" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dc1ec2035c12f6ef3da539cde513b5b1ea387121_2_690x238.png, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/dc1ec2035c12f6ef3da539cde513b5b1ea387121.png 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/dc1ec2035c12f6ef3da539cde513b5b1ea387121.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dc1ec2035c12f6ef3da539cde513b5b1ea387121_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Screenshot from 2020-12-08 18-09-56</span><span class="informations">953×329 306 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div></p>
<p>This relates to the issue of “purpose”.  This has to do with why I think it’s a good idea to try and understand what people are actually doing, in connection with OGM, and build up from this empirical stuff towards structures.  We now have some tentative structures available as a scaffolding — but the scaffolding is highly adaptable based on the empirics.</p>
<p>This theme relates to “Customer Development” per <a class="mention" href="/u/mila">@Mila</a>.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/needs-and-tendencies-what-people-are-trying-to-do/472">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/needs-and-tendencies-what-people-are-trying-to-do/472</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 18:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-472</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/needs-and-tendencies-what-people-are-trying-to-do/472.rss">Needs and Tendencies — &quot;What people are trying to do&quot;</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Source Document</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Technoshaman]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Organizing OGM</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>For designing ourselves into being as a thriving and anti-fragile community/movement, I suggest we develop a source document, a next-stage, not-ossified, living “constitution,” defined as follows. It was developed by a friend of mine and used in my community-building work, over the last 30 years in many settings.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>What Is a Source Document?</strong></p>
<p>SOURCE: “that from which something arises; a wellspring.”  Source refers to the basic elements from which something emerges.  It applies to those things that are continually emergent, that have lives of their own, that generate their own shape and identity.  To see the source of something, we need to understand <strong>the basic elements and their interplay, their dynamic relationships, which are key to its current identity and to what it might become.</strong></p>
<p>DOCUMENT: “any text that can be referred to by a community independent of its originators in time and space.”  It is therefore available as a record of origin and, at the same time, as the source of dialogue and interpretation that are continually evolving.  It enables us to relate current circumstances and current development to original intentions.  This provides us with <strong>a connection to the history and identity of our institutions while not locking us into rigid rules of fixed interpretations of earlier times.</strong></p>
<p>A well-formed source document provides a structure of interpretation that demands continued engagement, intelligence and independent interpretation in the face of the varying circumstances of life.</p>
<p>Source: Mike McMaster’s  talk on “EMERGENCE, SELF-ORGANISATION AND FREEDOM: the sources of innovation” at the Complexity &amp; Innovation conference, London 1997</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This topic also relates to <a class="mention" href="/u/bhnelson">@bhnelson</a>’s  <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/draft-vision-document/156">Draft Vision Document</a>.</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/source-document/469">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/source-document/469</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 07:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-469</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/source-document/469.rss">Source Document</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Trust, its dimensions, types, and scaling</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Technoshaman]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Human Side</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/gyuri">@Gyuri</a> <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/ogm-as-an-innovation-architecture-ecosystem/316/7">posted</a> an informative and thought-full comment about trust, a subject that I thought deserves its own topic. So, I’m responding here.</p>
<p>Trust is not a binary concept; it has many types, dimensions, criteria, which sociologists studied for decades. A friend of mine has even written her PhD  dissertation about the subject. I have dozens of files in my research library about the same, which I will make public once my personal digigarden goes public.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, my take on the “scaling of trust” problem/opportunity is that one-to-one trust can scale, to some extent, in the form of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swift_trust_theory" rel="nofollow noopener">swift trust</a> and “transferred trust”, e.g.: A trust B. C trusts A. When A introduces C to B, there’s some chance that C will also trusts B.</p>
<p>But scaling one-to-multitudes is an issue of different type of transfer that, in best case happens one to community, then community to community. Note easily “scriptable…”</p>
            <p><small>9 posts - 7 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/trust-its-dimensions-types-and-scaling/465">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/trust-its-dimensions-types-and-scaling/465</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 12:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-465</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/trust-its-dimensions-types-and-scaling/465.rss">Trust, its dimensions, types, and scaling</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Peeragogy: master copy, and formatting Org vs Markdown</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Human Side</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-dev-december-2020/455/2">Peeragogy dev (December 2020)</a>:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="skreutzer" data-post="2" data-topic="455">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/user_avatar/forum.openglobalmind.com/skreutzer/40/7_2.png" class="avatar"><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-dev-december-2020/455/2">Peeragogy dev (December 2020)</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Which repository? The one of the Peeragogy Handbook v3/v4? If so, what would be point of the migration be? Isn’t the master copy in Markdown, with the reationale/reasoning that GitHub/HackMD has rendering for it as a default? Is that also the case for Org-format?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>So, this is the master copy: <a href="https://github.com/Peeragogy/Peeragogy.github.io" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/Peeragogy/Peeragogy.github.io</a> (v3)</p>
<p>This is the experimental Org Mode setup that will replace it: <a href="https://github.com/PeeragogyLabs/PeeragogyORG" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/PeeragogyLabs/PeeragogyORG</a></p>
<p>Yes, Github renders Org, e.g., <a href="https://github.com/PeeragogyLabs/PeeragogyORG/blob/main/coworking.org" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/PeeragogyLabs/PeeragogyORG/blob/main/coworking.org</a></p>
<p>But the plan is to move to Firn for rendering, e.g., <a href="https://peeragogylabs.github.io/PeeragogyORG/coworking" rel="nofollow noopener">https://peeragogylabs.github.io/PeeragogyORG/coworking</a></p>
<p>Firn can be set up as a one-for-one replacement of Github Pages/Jekyll, but I’d actually like to go one step further and remove the dependency on Github entirely, moving hosting to a free software solution.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="skreutzer" data-post="2" data-topic="455">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/user_avatar/forum.openglobalmind.com/skreutzer/40/7_2.png" class="avatar"><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-dev-december-2020/455/2">Peeragogy dev (December 2020)</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p>At the same time, aren’t both Markdown and Org-format (and Wikitext and many others) without support for semantic bootstrappping, so what would be the point of switching, one arbitrary primitive syntax vs. another?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>So, in Org it’s possible to define custom blocks: <a href="https://alhassy.github.io/org-special-block-extras/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://alhassy.github.io/org-special-block-extras/</a></p>
<p>This means for example if we want to use the Tufte margin, we could add</p>
<pre><code>#+BEGIN_SIDENOTE
This is a "mini-Handbook" introducing Org mode:
https://orgmode.org/quickstart.html
#+END_SIDENOTE
</code></pre>
<p>and that will then be formatted (subject to writing the correct instructions) correctly in both HTML and PDF downstream formats.  It would be possible to hack this sort of thing into Markdown, I’d say, but it’s well supported in Org.  More <a href="https://orgmode.org/manual/Structure-of-Code-Blocks.html" rel="nofollow noopener">semantics can be added</a> as well.</p>
<p>(I’m glossing over the fact that Firn and Org Mode itself have separate rendering strategies; this will all be sorted out eventually!)</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-master-copy-and-formatting-org-vs-markdown/456">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-master-copy-and-formatting-org-vs-markdown/456</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 13:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-456</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-master-copy-and-formatting-org-vs-markdown/456.rss">Peeragogy: master copy, and formatting Org vs Markdown</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Peeragogy dev (December 2020)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Human Side</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/forming-a-moderation-team/399/6">Forming a Moderation Team</a> + <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/improvements-to-openglobalmind-com/449/5">Improvements to OpenGlobalMind.com</a>:</p>
<p>(Splicing my follow-up: that’s a fun move.)</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/lovolution">@lovolution</a> and <a class="mention" href="/u/skreutzer">@skreutzer</a> had mentioned that CSC is online now!  I think I’ll hold off signing up until the end of December. I can come for a visit in the new year!  Hopefully I can announce completion of these Peeragogy migration tasks, preparatory to building version 4 of the Handbook.</p>
<ul>
<li>(1—DONE) Google Groups → Oregon State University Open Source Lab (OSU OSL)-hosted  <strong>GNU Mailman</strong>  list (opt-in: <a href="https://lists.peeragogy.org/mailman/listinfo/peeragogy-handbook" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>).</li>
<li>(2) Master copy → Migrate to Org format as in  <strong>PeeragogyORG</strong>  repository.</li>
<li>(3) <code>peeragogy.org</code> → Migrate to  <strong>Firn</strong>  and to new hosting provided by OSU OSL.</li>
<li>(4) Editing → Prefer  <strong>Logseq</strong>  and  <strong>Org Roam</strong>  in Emacs (these should be interoperable, some setup required).</li>
<li>(5) LaTeX/PDF → Migrate to  <strong>Tufte</strong>  style.</li>
<li>(6) Google Chat → Close down in preference to  <strong>Zulip</strong>  so that all discussions are in one place and properly archived.</li>
</ul>
<p>Once that’s ready I’d likely have energy to do some work on the OGM website; though, maybe what’s really wanted is someone with front-end and design skills.  At the level of network plumbing, we could look into networking the Peeragogy Zulip together with the CSC Agora, and others, into another location, via Matterbridge, to create a shared feed of key announcements (should that be useful).  Maybe this could create a nice feed to put on OGM for example.  I know that <a class="mention" href="/u/robert.best">@robert.best</a> has worked with Matterbridge before.</p>
<p>Regarding the tech stack outlined above and the Peeragogy Handbook <strong>v4</strong>:</p>
<ol>
<li>The changes outlined will mean we have a fully free software setup, which is something I’ve been wanting for a while.</li>
<li>When people are up to speed, it should also help to remove me as a bottleneck for the project, which is another major longstanding and un-dealt-with objective.</li>
<li>We also have major plans for content updates (not covered above).</li>
</ol>
<p>If people are willing to look ahead to <strong>v5</strong> of the Handbook, I have in mind a more ambitious data-modelling approach that can make sense of lots of snippets from disparate sources.  I’m currently thinking to build it using <a href="https://github.com/juxt/crux" rel="nofollow noopener">Crux</a>, having learned from another project Kosa that I was trying to help as a volunteer (but didn’t get very far because I got overwhelmed with other things). It might be interesting with regard to the knowledge management tasks that OGM will have on the horizon. E.g., perhaps a successor or add-on to the Semantic MediaWiki.</p>
<p><strong>tl;dr</strong>: I foresee solidifying a lot of tech related to Clojure in the next year or two, and I’d love it if others happen to get interested in some of this as time goes by.  But, for now, I think we still need to work a lot more on the overall system design.  I filed this under “The Human Side” because I’d appreciate dialogue about the design aspects (subject to overlapping interest!).</p>
            <p><small>18 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-dev-december-2020/455">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-dev-december-2020/455</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 10:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-455</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/peeragogy-dev-december-2020/455.rss">Peeragogy dev (December 2020)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>K.Gardeners Circle</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Technoshaman]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Organizing OGM</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I noticed that we have a number of topics in which the purpose of OGM is discussed, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/ogm-workshop-group-1-output/413/6" class="inline-onebox">OGM Workshop Group 1 output</a></li>
<li><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/core-purpose/414" class="inline-onebox">Core purpose</a></li>
<li><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/so-exactly-why-are-we-here-what-is-it-that-most-needs-being-done/127" class="inline-onebox">So, exactly WHY are we here? What is it that most needs being done?</a></li>
</ul>
<p>No, I didn’t open this topic as yet another space to address it, just the opposite — to call our attention to the fact that when the same subject is addressed in different containers, it increases the likelihood that:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>People, who don’t notice or can’t follow all the conversations about the  same at different places, will miss some valuable contributions, get confused about where to post their own contribution, and get disconnected from the flow of productive engagement.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Collective sensemaking, self-reflection, memory, and intelligence are becoming increasingly difficult to nourish, due to the balkanization of the discussion about the same subject.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>That situation is unavoidable in every virtual community without proper facilitation and knowledge gardening. It’s not really an issue in socmedia groups, where cultivating collective sensemaking, self-reflection, memory and intelligence is not part of the group’s aspirations and culture. The situation is  exacerbated when:</p>
<ul>
<li>The same group of people are using different platforms with quasi-identical affordances (e.g. Discourse and Mattermost) for conversing about poorly differentiated subjects (e.g. <a href="https://chat.collectivesensecommons.org/agora/channels/tools--technology" rel="nofollow noopener">Tools on Mattermost</a>  and <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/designing-the-system/tools/10">Tools on Discourse</a> ).</li>
<li>New topics are opening without a well-defined reason for being posted in the topic opener.</li>
<li>New topics are opening without a host helping the convo to go somewhere vs. endless meandering.</li>
</ul>
<p>Hoping that some order will emerge from the looming crisis of our collective epistemology (that “roughly, refers to the study of the epistemological properties of groups and the significance of group knowledge production and acquisition” (<a href="https://ndpr.nd.edu/news/essays-in-collective-epistemology/" rel="nofollow noopener">source</a> )?</p>
<p>Me too, <em>and</em> I also think that we may even be able to prevent the crisis. In fact, that’s why I’m opening this “Knowledge Gardeners Circle” topic with the intended purpose to attract enough people to a productive conversation about forming a community of knowledge gardeners dedicated to cultivating the collective intelligence of the OGM initiative.</p>
<p>Disclaimer: I do not offer to be the leader/coordinator of the suggested circle. I will be happy to be a member of KGC and act as a coach to it if the need that it is intended to serve gets enough traction and at least 3-5 people want to participate in it. I also offer to facilitate this topic until the circle is formally established and or the lack of sufficient support for it becomes evident.</p>
            <p><small>24 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/k-gardeners-circle/454">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/k-gardeners-circle/454</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 10:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-454</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/k-gardeners-circle/454.rss">K.Gardeners Circle</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>DWeb Ecosystem, December 2020: 12 Lightning Talks</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Tools</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/holtzermann17">@holtzermann17</a>, sort of posting this for you; I already posted it to the mailing list and to CSC Agora, but I don’t think you’re on either of those right now.  And some of this event might appeal to you.</p>
<p>Also for anyone else, of course!</p>
<p><strong>Good virtual event for the tech folks, organized by DWeb Meetup SF. Thursday 5pm PST, 8pm EST, 2am CET.</strong> (Time was specifically chosen for this event to be Asia-friendly; sorry Europe!) <strong>Free/donate registration through Eventbrite required.</strong></p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/2d0195e8881be5d4b437654748a94f10589051bd.png" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/dweb-meetup-december-2020-the-latest-in-the-dweb-ecosystem-tickets-130047907793" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eventbrite</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/345;"><img src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F118626647%2F154460368634%2F1%2Foriginal.20201124-212935?w=1000&amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;q=75&amp;sharp=10&amp;rect=0%2C0%2C2160%2C1080&amp;s=d720c6581fd9fb3bd241a2a329cb77db" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="345"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/dweb-meetup-december-2020-the-latest-in-the-dweb-ecosystem-tickets-130047907793" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dweb Meetup December 2020 — The Latest in the DWeb Ecosystem</a></h3>

<p>At our next DWeb Meetup, we hear from a dozen projects about their breakthroughs, challenges, and roadmaps for the coming year.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>Hear from 12 Projects: challenges, milestones &amp; lessons learned</p>
<p>Even amidst the COVID lockdown, builders of the Decentralized Web have hit new milestones. At our next DWeb Meetup, we will hear from a dozen projects about their breakthroughs, challenges, and roadmaps for the coming year. As with all of our DWeb Meetups, these lightning talks will provide an opportunity to learn from others and explore potential partnerships and collaboration. (We ask for less “product pitch” and more sharing important lessons.)</p>
<p>Join us for lightning rounds of 5 minute talks with 2 minutes of Q&amp;A in Zoom. Afterwards we will head to Gather.town for socializing and networking.</p>
<p>Here are some of the 12 Presenters:</p>
<p>Mauve Signweaver, Founder, Agregore</p>
<p>Agregore: Local-First Web Of Everything</p>
<p>Agregore is a local-first web browser which aims to simplify application development across different peer-to-peer protocols while staying as minimal and customizable as possible.</p>
<p>Twitter: <span class="mention">@RangerMauve</span></p>
<p>Tom Trowbridge, Founder, Fluence Labs</p>
<p>Fluence Labs was established in 2017 by 3 founders, Dmitry Kurinskiy, Tom Trowbridge and Evgeny Ponomarev. Fluence Labs has developed an open application platform that leverages blockchain to enable new software business models. Applications share data and users and are radically easier to create, allowing developers to build on each other and be rewarded as their services and applications are used.</p>
<p>Twitter: <span class="mention">@Fluence_Project</span></p>
<p>Maria Bustillos, Co-Founder, Brick House Co-operative</p>
<p>Megaplatforms from Amazon to Facebook to Penguin Random House have flattened and centralized the human imagination. The Brick House Cooperative, launching December 8th, is addressing this problem as writers and artists, ‘from the other side’. They’re looking to join forces with technologists and others interested in decorporatizing media. Maria will also share how her previous experience with Civil, a blockchain-based media platform that aimed to fund journalism, will inform her work with The Brick House.</p>
<p>Twitter: <span class="mention">@mariabustillos</span></p>
<p>Dietrich Ayala, Ecosystem Lead, IPFS</p>
<p>Big is Small is Big: IPFS Usage, Users and Use-cases in 2020</p>
<p>As adoption and availability of IPFS grew in 2020, we saw it used across a broad spectrum of applications, varying widely in industry category, use-case, architecture and more. IPFS ecosystem lead Dietrich Ayala will speedrun through a sampling of these, sharing what was learned and how our users are guiding the IPFS project into 2021.</p>
<p>Twitter: <span class="mention">@dietrich</span></p>
<p>Karissa McKelvey, Researcher, Simply Secure</p>
<p>Decentralization Off The Shelf: Patterns x Decentralized Applications</p>
<p>It’s hard to get started building a decentralized application. Even if you’ve been building them for years, it’s hard to get them adopted. Decentralized applications operate differently than centralized ones — and we need new tools that developers and designers can use to understand how to build applications. Simply Secure is now producing a library of resources, assets, and patterns to support the design and development of better user-facing applications that are backed by decentralized architecture.</p>
<p>Twitter: <span class="mention">@okdistribute</span></p>
<p>Adam Souzis, One Commons</p>
<p>“At the DWeb Camp in 2019, I led a brainstorming session on how we can build a cloud providing the same openness and freedoms to users and developers as open source. One year and a pandemic later, I’m excited to finally release the first step in pursuit of that vision: “ensembles,” git repositories that package open cloud services. They are designed to be the building blocks of an open and decentralized cloud infrastructure: reproducible, relocatable and shareable. Decentralization is obtained via a notion of a persistent identity that is defined not by a network location but rather a reproducible state.”</p>
<p><span class="mention">@onecommons</span></p>
<p>Travis Vachon – ItMe.company (The first Co-op Data union built on top of SOLID)</p>
<p>Centralized tech monopolies and other large corporations capture the vast majority of the value of the world’s data in 2020. In order to create the conditions necessary to return this value to the world’s users, we need new politico-technical-social institutions that give users the ability to provide and retract informed consent over the ways their data is used. itme is building the world’s first cooperatively owned and operated data union built on Tim Berners-Lee’s new Solid web standard to let users reassemble their digital bodies and capture the value of the data they create.</p>
<p><a href="https://itme.company" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://itme.company</a></p>
<p><span class="mention">@itmepress</span></p>
<p>Brandon Wallace, &amp; Drew O’Meara, PLAN Systems</p>
<p>PLAN Systems is a technology 501©(3) founded in 2018 by two U.S. veterans in Austin TX. Their development effort centers on building a framework of open protocols and universally accessible interfaces designed for privacy, real time collaboration, data visualization, and secure data storage &amp; portability. November was a critical milestone, demonstrating PLAN (pre-alpha) running on 4 major platforms across desktop and mobile devices.</p>
<p>Github: <a href="https://github.com/plan-systems">https://github.com/plan-systems</a></p>
<p>Paul Frazee, Founder, Beaker Browser</p>
<p>Beaker Browser 1.0: Share P2P Websites</p>
<p>Unless there was a disaster between now and Thursday, then Beaker Browser 1.0 will be available! Join us for a quick overview of building and sharing peer-to-peer Websites with this newest release.</p>
<p><span class="mention">@pfrazee</span> <a href="https://beakerbrowser.com">https://beakerbrowser.com</a></p>
<p>Mark Nadal, Founder, Gun.eco</p>
<p>Founded in 2014, GUN is an open source cybersecurity protocol for synchronizing graph data in decentralized mesh networks. It is as easy as Firebase yet supports end-to-end encryption and uses “CRDT” algorithms instead of a Blockchain.</p>
<p>In 2020, GUN hit 200M+ downloads with 30M monthly active users. The project is powered by 2 full time staff, 10 part-time volunteers, and 100+ contributors.</p>
<p>Twitter: <span class="mention">@marknadal</span></p>
<p>Yisi Liu, Founder, DWeb Meetup Shanghai</p>
<p>The DWeb Shanghai group co-hosted a workshop on mesh network building. We joined with the Institute of Network Society at China Academy of Art as a special workshop of its fifth annual conference. I will share an overview of this mesh networking workshop and what we learned.</p>
<p>Twitter: <span class="mention">@TheYisiLiu</span></p>
<p>SCHEDULE:</p>
<p>San Francisco: 5:00 PM / Austin: 7:00 PM / Boston-New York: 8:00 PM / Buenos Aires-São Paulo: 10:00 PM / Shanghai: 9:00 AM next day / Sydney: 12:00 PM next day / Auckland: 2:00 PM next day / London: 1:00 AM next day / Prague-Berlin: 2:00 AM next day / Perm: 6:00 AM next day</p>
<p>Please note that we organized this DWeb Meetup at a different time to make it easier for people in the Asia Pacific region to join us.</p>
<p>The following times are in Pacific Time:</p>
<p>5:00 PM - Welcome &amp; Announcements</p>
<p>5:15 PM - Lightning Talks Begin</p>
<p>6:45 PM - Closing Remarks</p>
<p>7:00 PM - Post-Event Socializing on Gather.town</p>
<p>Questions?</p>
<p>Write to <a href="mailto:dweb@archive.org">dweb@archive.org</a> with questions, to volunteer, or more.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/dweb-ecosystem-december-2020-12-lightning-talks/452">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/dweb-ecosystem-december-2020-12-lightning-talks/452</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 06:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-452</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/dweb-ecosystem-december-2020-12-lightning-talks/452.rss">DWeb Ecosystem, December 2020: 12 Lightning Talks</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Roles, redux</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Organizing OGM</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’d like to run through the Roles described on the <a href="https://www.openglobalmind.com/about/team/roles" rel="nofollow noopener">OGM webpage</a> and see how they match the nascent pattern language that is <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/ogm-workshop-group-1-output/413">OGM Workshop Group 1 output</a>.</p>
<p><strong>A. Sensors</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Sensors fulfill the primary research function of OGM. The primary responsibility of a sensor is to grow our knowledge base. Consider them similar to <strong>market research analysts</strong> responsible for key subject areas. They scan the environment and the world, searching for new thoughts, ideas, and insights to bring into the system.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This seems related to <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/defining-characteristics/415"><strong>Defining Characteristics</strong> : <em>Maps of the landscape</em></a> — insofar as sensors are also like “scouts” or “surveyors”; and furthermore, the map-making project influences the “view” of the landscape.</p>
<p><strong>B. Protectors</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Owners of how OGM interfaces with the outside world. Their responsibilities include API’s, IP, access controls, cyber security, membership, etc.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Although the quote above is mostly technically worded, it sounds a lot like <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/scope-of-work/417"> <strong>Scope of Work</strong> : <em>Debug individual and joint activities</em></a>, insofar as the “scope” of work defines a <em>boundary</em> and the boundary helps protect the organisation (I’m thinking of Stafford Beer’s model of the firm, and Ronald Coase’s).  It’s interesting to think of the “debugging” process as a form of immune system, as well, of which the boundary is only one part.</p>
<p><strong>C. Fellows</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investors, leaders, and thought-provokers. To be a Fellow suggests a <strong>deeper level of partnership</strong> with OGM. These individuals (or organizations) grow and advance the fundamental mechanisms that support OGM. They help provide or procure funding for the pursuit of new projects and help guide thought leadership.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now this sounds a bit like <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/values/416"> <strong>Values</strong> : <em>Practices of stewardship</em></a>.  The “deeper level” of partnership sounds like it may well involve a “stewardship” role. Or, put otherwise, these roles might feed into and sustain the “values” of the organization itself. One keeps in mind that “funding” and “Financial Capital” is only one of seven Community Captials!  The “thought leadership” might be along any of the other dimensions. This <a href="https://jods.mitpress.mit.edu/pub/resisting-reduction/release/17" rel="nofollow noopener">essay</a> by Joi Ito might be worth reading in connection with these themes.</p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/dcc85acbb9a08a20f33064c2dde4b17cf27c4279.jpeg" data-download-href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/dcc85acbb9a08a20f33064c2dde4b17cf27c4279" title="Screenshot from 2020-12-02 22-36-23"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dcc85acbb9a08a20f33064c2dde4b17cf27c4279_2_690x339.jpeg" alt="Screenshot from 2020-12-02 22-36-23" data-base62-sha1="vv8iGAvNGtERmCbp7Y9vdEqVu5P" width="690" height="339" srcset="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dcc85acbb9a08a20f33064c2dde4b17cf27c4279_2_690x339.jpeg, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dcc85acbb9a08a20f33064c2dde4b17cf27c4279_2_1035x508.jpeg 1.5x, https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dcc85acbb9a08a20f33064c2dde4b17cf27c4279_2_1380x678.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/dcc85acbb9a08a20f33064c2dde4b17cf27c4279_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Screenshot from 2020-12-02 22-36-23</span><span class="informations">1716×844 296 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div></p>
<p><strong>D. Makers (Builders)</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The primary function of the “Makers”, or “Creators” is to create – or shepherd the creation of – tools and services.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Although the link is a bit lose, I wonder if this is connected with <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/strategic-objectives/419"><strong>Strategic Objectives</strong> : <em>Ongoing learning (w/ a shared memory artifact) and unlearning</em></a>, since the strategic objectives contribute to an articulation of the project, and as such are “tools for thought.”  Another thing that the makers <em>make</em> is memory.  Am I reaching too much here…?</p>
<p><em>We are the music makers,</em><br>
&nbsp;    <em>And we are the dreamers of dreams,</em><br>
<em>Wandering by lone sea-breakers,</em><br>
&nbsp;    <em>And sitting by desolate streams;—</em><br>
<em>World-losers and world-forsakers,</em><br>
&nbsp;    <em>On whom the pale moon gleams:</em><br>
<em>Yet we are the movers and shakers</em><br>
&nbsp;    <em>Of the world for ever, it seems.</em></p>
<p><strong>E. StoryThreaders</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The story-tellers of the group seek to make connections across multiple narratives, nodes, ideas, or strings of thought. They find creative ways to introduce these new stories to the global consciousness.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This seems related to <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/sustainability-model/421"> <strong>Sustainability Model</strong> : <em>Develop collective wisdom</em></a> — as I understand it.  (Thanks to <a class="mention" href="/u/kenhomer">@kenhomer</a>, <a class="mention" href="/u/jerry">@Jerry</a>, and <a class="mention" href="/u/mila">@Mila</a> for explaining to me what they mean by “story”.)  What I’m piecing together is that stories are “sustaining” because they are a kind of ground for mindfulness and discernment.  It was also interesting to learn that <a class="mention" href="/u/maparent">@maparent</a> that he recently read “After Buddhism” — a book that’s built mostly out of stories.</p>
<p><strong>F. Participants</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Users of OGM platform who may be makers, story threaders, protectors, or sensors in their own rights.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is an exact match for <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/participants/418"> <strong>Participants</strong> : <em>Maintain sufficient cohesion to generate value</em></a>. I emphasised the need for “cohesion” and pulling together different resources (similar to the multiple capitals theory mentioned above, or the metaphor of a kombucha-like functionality of the map-makers/scouts mentioned above under <strong>Sensors</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>G. Sponsors</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Members who support OGM in the form of grants, scholarships, sponsorships, time, etc.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This seems related to <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/core-purpose/414"><strong>Core Purpose</strong> : <em>Connect the connectors to what they need to thrive</em></a> as I understood it.  People would “sponsor” the project by providing these needed resources.</p>
<p><strong>H. Advisors</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Members who offer guidance or advice to OGM. Perhaps more of a steering committee.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I wonder if the steering committee might take charge of the <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/ogm-workshop-group-1-output/413"><strong>Key Operating Principles and Practices</strong> : <em>Online with intention, and in the world with compassion</em></a> — after all, if they are going to “steer” or “operate” the project, they will need access to such a control system!</p>
<p><strong>Guild Members</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Membership in a guild <strong>distinguishes those that can be leveraged</strong> for guidance, advice, or inventive solutions in a given discipline or practice from other participants. An all-encompassing role, Guild Members are master practitioners of OGM capabilities. They are builders of the product, solution designers, and engagement seekers. Think of Guild Members as <strong>SME</strong>’s. For example, a developer with extensive experience developing API’s might be a guild member of an API-related guild. Similarly, a story-threader may be a member of a related guild. Furthermore, guild membership is not mutually exclusive. That is to say, a story-threader can belong to a “Builder” guild or a “Story-Threader” guild.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Personally, I’m a bit less charmed by this “guild” language and have suggested  “<a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/guilds-which-ones/65/9">working groups</a>” as a more down-to-earth alternative term. That said, maybe the guild term means something important that I’m not grasping (as was the case with “story” until it was explained to me).  However, the other point to make at this juncture is that I have run out of link targets.  So, in the words of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pierre-Simon_Laplace" rel="nofollow noopener">Pierre-Simon Laplace</a>: <em>je n’avais pas besoin de cette hypothèse.</em></p>
            <p><small>15 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/roles-redux/450">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/roles-redux/450</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-450</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/roles-redux/450.rss">Roles, redux</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Projects of Impatience</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[holtzermann17]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Designing the System</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Here Peter Sloterdijk talks about speed and slowness.<br>
Maybe interesting to discuss!<br>
</p><div class="onebox lazyYT lazyYT-container" data-youtube-id="9_fsFwf0juk" data-youtube-title="Peter Sloterdijk - &quot;nobody has time for an entire generation any more&quot;" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque">
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9_fsFwf0juk" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">
    <img class="ytp-thumbnail-image" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/64cd4a9c3ff78b26a74d7bfc19000f693d56cc79.jpeg" title="Peter Sloterdijk - &quot;nobody has time for an entire generation any more&quot;" width="480" height="360">
  </a>
</div>

            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/projects-of-impatience/448">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/projects-of-impatience/448</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 20:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-448</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/projects-of-impatience/448.rss">Projects of Impatience</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
