<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>CORN IS A PLATFORM</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575</link>
    <description>I wanted to post one of my favorite rants, from December 2018.  It&#39;s related to US capitalism, finance, real estate, and &quot;farming&quot;.

In the following, &quot;corn,&quot; &quot;maize,&quot; and &quot;soybeans&quot; refer to the industrial varieties which humans don&#39;t eat, but which make up most of what the US grows.  Think industrial feedstocks; not popcorn, corn on the cob, or edamame.

SwiftOnSecurity started:

https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1074856487514726400

(scroll up and down that thread for enough examples to make you sick)

And Dr. Taber picked up from there:

https://twitter.com/SarahTaber_bww/status/1074882589079597056

&gt; Corn is a platform with both limitless purposes, and one purpose:
&gt;
&gt; to turn rural land into a dependable &amp; infinitely fungible financial asset.
&gt;
&gt; If you want to understand US agriculture, you gotta understand one thing.
&gt;
&gt; It&#39;s not even about making food.
&gt;
&gt; It&#39;s a real estate hustle.
&gt;
&gt; Can I be honest for a second, as an ag person who&#39;s done most of their work in CA &amp; the South?
&gt;
&gt; Land in the Midwest ... isn&#39;t really good for much. Sure, the soil&#39;s real nice, but the growing season is too short for most globally-traded cash crops.
&gt;
&gt; Coffee.
&gt;
&gt; Sugar.
&gt;
&gt; Chocolate.
&gt;
&gt; Cotton.
&gt;
&gt; Tobacco.
&gt;
&gt; Rice.
&gt;
&gt; Palm oil.
&gt;
&gt; The Midwest is exactly the kind of giant wet low-population area you&#39;d want for cash crops. Except most of the big-money ones are tropical, &amp; Midwest has a 3-6 month growing season. You&#39;re stuck with annual crops.
&gt;
&gt; &quot;Well what&#39;s wrong w wheat, flax, oats, rye, hemp, &amp; other short-season cash crops?&quot;
&gt;
&gt; 1) Hemp ain&#39;t been legal
&gt;
&gt; 2) We can&#39;t use an entire Midwest&#39;s worth of oats &amp; rye
&gt;
&gt; 3) Wheat &amp; flax grow nearly everywhere, including huge areas of arid US west. Too much competition to rely on.
&gt;
&gt; Enter maize &amp; soybeans. Here&#39;s what they bring to table:
&gt;
&gt; 1) Short-lived enough to make use of Midwest growing season
&gt;
&gt; 2) Need lots of water- that cuts out competition from the US West
&gt;
&gt; 3) Humans can&#39;t eat them, but that&#39;s ok, they&#39;re just infinitely fungible starch &amp; protein.
&gt;
&gt; If you&#39;re just growing raw sources of starch &amp; protein, you can just handle market gluts by inventing a new use. That&#39;s harder to do with crops that make something less malleable like fiber, or (in case of wheat, oats, rye, &amp; most grains) a mid-yield mix of starch &amp; protein.
&gt;
&gt; And boy do we get our market gluts on. Because for 3-6 months every year, the Midwest turns into a giant hot wet basin of plant growing power.
&gt;
&gt; But: without a platform like corn &amp; soybeans, hot wet plains are just hot wet plains. They&#39;re not a financial powerhouse. You couldn&#39;t, say, include farmland as a securitized asset in investment funds.
&gt;
&gt; https://www.cnbc.com/2016/01/21/getting-your-plot-of-american-farmland-.html
&gt;
&gt; The Food Discourse(TM) really fixates on how corn is used after it&#39;s grown. &quot;Oh my God! It&#39;s in everything!&quot;
&gt;
&gt; I&#39;m more interested in what that means for those who possess the land to grow it &amp; what *that* means for our society. And @SwiftOnSecurity hit the nail on the head.
&gt;
&gt; Part of the Food Discourse (TM)&#39;s fascination with food manufacturing is that it&#39;s fairly recent. It feels new &amp; foreign. And, you can *see* the size of the facilities and visualize the money that it takes to build and run them.
&gt;
&gt; It&#39;s a fairly new way to accumulate wealth. It&#39;s visible. And it fits with our &quot;wealth is capital is manufacturing &amp; Wall Street&quot; mentality. So we fixate on it.
&gt;
&gt; Meanwhile, most folks have no idea what the value of farmland is. Or that subsidies don&#39;t go to the people growing the corn- they go to the people who *own the land it grows on.*
&gt;
&gt; Most folks have no idea that the big hustle in food isn&#39;t food. It&#39;s real estate.
&gt;
&gt; That doesn&#39;t fit with our image of how wealth works in a capitalist society.
&gt;
&gt; Capitalism is supposed to mean new, modern, and scary! Farmland is ancient and wholesome! Farming is our one connection to more wholesome times!
&gt;
&gt; Bullshit.
&gt;
&gt; Farm landlords were grinding people to death for thousands of years before capitalism was ever invented.
&gt;
&gt; Real estate&#39;s always been the ideal asset. Can be used for food, minerals, or development- and you can collect rents pretty much infinitely w zero work.
&gt;
&gt; But thanks to our focus on &quot;bad stuff in our economy = modern = capitalism = industry&quot; &amp; &quot;agriculture = old = good,&quot; we rarely see farmland as being an asset that can be traded globally.
&gt;
&gt; AND 👏 THAT&#39;S 👏 EXACTLY 👏 HOW 👏 THE 👏 GOD 👏 DAMN 👏 LANDLORDS 👏 WANT 👏 IT
&gt;
&gt; We&#39;re busy fretting about agribusiness and food processing, meanwhile real live land barons are out here collecting rent &amp; subsidy checks on millions of acres and using it as low-risk ballast for their portfolios.
&gt;
&gt; To be clear: Wall Street is part of this.
&gt;
&gt; So are good ol&#39; boys.
&gt;
&gt; Most rural counties are run by 2-3 families that quietly own a huge slice of the land. You want to know why rural areas are so fucked up? It ain&#39;t the coastal elites. It&#39;s the landlords right there in the county.
&gt;
&gt; Rural landlords might collect their rent checks directly from their serfs, I mean neighbors in the county instead of a hedge fund office in Manhattan. But they&#39;ve got the same job. Own land, futz around all day, profit.
&gt;
&gt; Ever notice how most proposals to solve farm-related problems- not enough food, too much food, soil conservation, wildlife conservation, water shortages-
&gt;
&gt; all seem to boil down to &quot;throw money at land owners&quot;?
&gt;
&gt; Isn&#39;t that weird?
&gt;
&gt; The philosophy behind conservation payments is sometimes people own farmland that&#39;s too fragile to farm.
&gt;
&gt; But not farming loses money! Therefore, we must pay them not to farm it!
&gt;
&gt; Is anybody asking why own &quot;farmland&quot; that can&#39;t be farmed in the first place?
&gt;
&gt; This is a problem that could be solved a lot of different ways. Trusts, land buybacks, tax writeoffs for donating to conservation, etc. These are all used to some extent.
&gt;
&gt; But the big federal programs are all built around sending landowners a reliable subsidy check every year.
&gt;
&gt; So ... yeah. Sometimes rural land ownership is just an instrument for rich people to extort bribes from taxpayers. &quot;Pay me or I&#39;ll ruin your water.&quot;
&gt;
&gt; And sometimes you just monetize it on the corn platform.
&gt;
&gt; Either way, it&#39;s a huge asset class. In many ways it&#39;s more influential &amp; politically powerful than the &quot;industrial food&quot; sector we&#39;ve been taught to fear. But it&#39;s invisible, distant, and quiet, monetizing the earth in ways few of us understand.
&gt;
&gt; welp my soundcloud is at https://soundcloud.com/farm-to-taber-podcast &amp; you can support grumpy, sciencey, intersectional, independent farm journalism at https://www.patreon.com/user?u=5610560

Bonus links, a musical cartoon, &quot;Chudesnitsa&quot;, praising the virtues of corn in agriculture, from Nikita Khrushchev&#39;s USSR:

https://twitter.com/sovietvisuals/status/762223983139749889

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YTMu_FNvBAA

[Чудесница (мультфильм)](https://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/Чудесница_(мультфильм)) (Russian Wikipedia)

Pete</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 17:12:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Knowledge Areas</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>CORN IS A PLATFORM</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="kenhomer" data-post="2" data-topic="575">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/user_avatar/forum.openglobalmind.com/kenhomer/40/270_2.png" class="avatar"> kenhomer:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I am hopeful, but far from confident, that the Biden Administration might begin to make some significant changes to this</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I would love that, but I didn’t even know that it might be on the table to hope for!  My guess was that US politics had just solidified around CORN AS A PLATFORM, like other big, thorny problems that don’t seem like they’ll ever budge.</p>
<p>Might it really be on the table?</p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 17:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-575-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575.rss">CORN IS A PLATFORM</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>CORN IS A PLATFORM</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[kenhomer]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks for posting this Pete! The Farm Bill is one of the biggest and most important bills that Congress passes and it receives far too little attention on the part of the general public. I am hopeful, but far from confident, that the Biden Administration might begin to make some significant changes to this and begin to dismantle corn as a platform. But the entrenched interests are powerful and have long and deep relationships with the politicians whose campaigns they contribute to, It’ll be an uphill battle for sure…</p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 16:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-575-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575.rss">CORN IS A PLATFORM</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>CORN IS A PLATFORM</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I wanted to post one of my favorite rants, from December 2018.  It’s related to US capitalism, finance, real estate, and “farming”.</p>
<p>In the following, “corn,” “maize,” and “soybeans” refer to the industrial varieties which humans don’t eat, but which make up most of what the US grows.  Think industrial feedstocks; not popcorn, corn on the cob, or edamame.</p>
<p>SwiftOnSecurity started:</p>
<aside class="onebox twitterstatus">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1074856487514726400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/1d1a0c9f3340fa28fb08f685c5c7d4b180320af9.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1074856487514726400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SwiftOnSecurity (SwiftOnSecurity)</a></h4>

<div class="tweet"> You live in a society whose every production industry is based around a government-subsidized chemical feedstock.

Corn is not a _food_.
Corn is a _platform_.<div class="quoted">
<a class="quoted-link" href="https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/972631797375950849" rel="noopener"><p class="quoted-title">SwiftOnSecurity <span>@SwiftOnSecurity</span></p></a><div>You’ve got government market subsidy, political weight of low-population states, energy insecurity, environmental issues, agribusiness consolidation, hyper-productivity despite decreasing labor, food basket dynamics in world wars, 20th century chemical revolution, obesity, etc</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="date">
  <a href="https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1074856487514726400" target="_blank" rel="noopener">3:59 PM - 17 Dec 2018</a>
    <span class="like">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 512 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M462.3 62.6C407.5 15.9 326 24.3 275.7 76.2L256 96.5l-19.7-20.3C186.1 24.3 104.5 15.9 49.7 62.6c-62.8 53.6-66.1 149.8-9.9 207.9l193.5 199.8c12.5 12.9 32.8 12.9 45.3 0l193.5-199.8c56.3-58.1 53-154.3-9.8-207.9z"></path>
      </svg> 7.2K
    </span>
    <span class="retweet">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 640 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M629.657 343.598L528.971 444.284c-9.373 9.372-24.568 9.372-33.941 0L394.343 343.598c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941l10.823-10.823c9.562-9.562 25.133-9.34 34.419.492L480 342.118V160H292.451a24.005 24.005 0 0 1-16.971-7.029l-16-16C244.361 121.851 255.069 96 276.451 96H520c13.255 0 24 10.745 24 24v222.118l40.416-42.792c9.285-9.831 24.856-10.054 34.419-.492l10.823 10.823c9.372 9.372 9.372 24.569-.001 33.941zm-265.138 15.431A23.999 23.999 0 0 0 347.548 352H160V169.881l40.416 42.792c9.286 9.831 24.856 10.054 34.419.491l10.822-10.822c9.373-9.373 9.373-24.569 0-33.941L144.971 67.716c-9.373-9.373-24.569-9.373-33.941 0L10.343 168.402c-9.373 9.373-9.373 24.569 0 33.941l10.822 10.822c9.562 9.562 25.133 9.34 34.419-.491L96 169.881V392c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h243.549c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-16.001-16z"></path>
      </svg> 2.2K
    </span>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>(scroll up and down that thread for enough examples to make you sick)</p>
<p>And Dr. Taber picked up from there:</p>
<aside class="onebox twitterstatus">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/SarahTaber_bww/status/1074882589079597056" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/9ccc7e8e455bd194b9a97c3ff9ca0dd49b0af08e.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="624" height="351">

<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/SarahTaber_bww/status/1074882589079597056" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr Sarah Taber (SarahTaber_bww)</a></h4>

<div class="tweet"> Enter maize &amp; soybeans. Here's what they bring to table:

1) Short-lived enough to make use of Midwest growing season

2) Need lots of water- that cuts out competition from the US West

3) Humans can't eat them, but that's ok, they're just infinitely fungible starch &amp; protein. https://t.co/Gk4bemgYzJ<div class="quoted">
<a class="quoted-link" href="https://twitter.com/SarahTaber_bww/status/1074864735143804928" rel="noopener"><p class="quoted-title">Dr Sarah Taber <span>@SarahTaber_bww</span></p></a><div>GOD YES

SOMEONE FINALLY EXPLAINED IT https://twitter.com/SwiftOnSecurity/status/1074856487514726400&nbsp;…</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="date">
  <a href="https://twitter.com/SarahTaber_bww/status/1074882589079597056" target="_blank" rel="noopener">8:22 PM - 17 Dec 2018</a>
    <span class="like">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 512 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M462.3 62.6C407.5 15.9 326 24.3 275.7 76.2L256 96.5l-19.7-20.3C186.1 24.3 104.5 15.9 49.7 62.6c-62.8 53.6-66.1 149.8-9.9 207.9l193.5 199.8c12.5 12.9 32.8 12.9 45.3 0l193.5-199.8c56.3-58.1 53-154.3-9.8-207.9z"></path>
      </svg> 809
    </span>
    <span class="retweet">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 640 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M629.657 343.598L528.971 444.284c-9.373 9.372-24.568 9.372-33.941 0L394.343 343.598c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941l10.823-10.823c9.562-9.562 25.133-9.34 34.419.492L480 342.118V160H292.451a24.005 24.005 0 0 1-16.971-7.029l-16-16C244.361 121.851 255.069 96 276.451 96H520c13.255 0 24 10.745 24 24v222.118l40.416-42.792c9.285-9.831 24.856-10.054 34.419-.492l10.823 10.823c9.372 9.372 9.372 24.569-.001 33.941zm-265.138 15.431A23.999 23.999 0 0 0 347.548 352H160V169.881l40.416 42.792c9.286 9.831 24.856 10.054 34.419.491l10.822-10.822c9.373-9.373 9.373-24.569 0-33.941L144.971 67.716c-9.373-9.373-24.569-9.373-33.941 0L10.343 168.402c-9.373 9.373-9.373 24.569 0 33.941l10.822 10.822c9.562 9.562 25.133 9.34 34.419-.491L96 169.881V392c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h243.549c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-16.001-16z"></path>
      </svg> 120
    </span>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<blockquote>
<p>Corn is a platform with both limitless purposes, and one purpose:</p>
<p>to turn rural land into a dependable &amp; infinitely fungible financial asset.</p>
<p>If you want to understand US agriculture, you gotta understand one thing.</p>
<p>It’s not even about making food.</p>
<p>It’s a real estate hustle.</p>
<p>Can I be honest for a second, as an ag person who’s done most of their work in CA &amp; the South?</p>
<p>Land in the Midwest … isn’t really good for much. Sure, the soil’s real nice, but the growing season is too short for most globally-traded cash crops.</p>
<p>Coffee.</p>
<p>Sugar.</p>
<p>Chocolate.</p>
<p>Cotton.</p>
<p>Tobacco.</p>
<p>Rice.</p>
<p>Palm oil.</p>
<p>The Midwest is exactly the kind of giant wet low-population area you’d want for cash crops. Except most of the big-money ones are tropical, &amp; Midwest has a 3-6 month growing season. You’re stuck with annual crops.</p>
<p>“Well what’s wrong w wheat, flax, oats, rye, hemp, &amp; other short-season cash crops?”</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Hemp ain’t been legal</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We can’t use an entire Midwest’s worth of oats &amp; rye</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Wheat &amp; flax grow nearly everywhere, including huge areas of arid US west. Too much competition to rely on.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Enter maize &amp; soybeans. Here’s what they bring to table:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Short-lived enough to make use of Midwest growing season</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Need lots of water- that cuts out competition from the US West</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Humans can’t eat them, but that’s ok, they’re just infinitely fungible starch &amp; protein.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>If you’re just growing raw sources of starch &amp; protein, you can just handle market gluts by inventing a new use. That’s harder to do with crops that make something less malleable like fiber, or (in case of wheat, oats, rye, &amp; most grains) a mid-yield mix of starch &amp; protein.</p>
<p>And boy do we get our market gluts on. Because for 3-6 months every year, the Midwest turns into a giant hot wet basin of plant growing power.</p>
<p>But: without a platform like corn &amp; soybeans, hot wet plains are just hot wet plains. They’re not a financial powerhouse. You couldn’t, say, include farmland as a securitized asset in investment funds.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2016/01/21/getting-your-plot-of-american-farmland-.html">https://www.cnbc.com/2016/01/21/getting-your-plot-of-american-farmland-.html</a></p>
<p>The Food Discourse™ really fixates on how corn is used after it’s grown. “Oh my God! It’s in everything!”</p>
<p>I’m more interested in what that means for those who possess the land to grow it &amp; what <em>that</em> means for our society. And <span class="mention">@SwiftOnSecurity</span> hit the nail on the head.</p>
<p>Part of the Food Discourse ™’s fascination with food manufacturing is that it’s fairly recent. It feels new &amp; foreign. And, you can <em>see</em> the size of the facilities and visualize the money that it takes to build and run them.</p>
<p>It’s a fairly new way to accumulate wealth. It’s visible. And it fits with our “wealth is capital is manufacturing &amp; Wall Street” mentality. So we fixate on it.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, most folks have no idea what the value of farmland is. Or that subsidies don’t go to the people growing the corn- they go to the people who <em>own the land it grows on.</em></p>
<p>Most folks have no idea that the big hustle in food isn’t food. It’s real estate.</p>
<p>That doesn’t fit with our image of how wealth works in a capitalist society.</p>
<p>Capitalism is supposed to mean new, modern, and scary! Farmland is ancient and wholesome! Farming is our one connection to more wholesome times!</p>
<p>Bullshit.</p>
<p>Farm landlords were grinding people to death for thousands of years before capitalism was ever invented.</p>
<p>Real estate’s always been the ideal asset. Can be used for food, minerals, or development- and you can collect rents pretty much infinitely w zero work.</p>
<p>But thanks to our focus on “bad stuff in our economy = modern = capitalism = industry” &amp; “agriculture = old = good,” we rarely see farmland as being an asset that can be traded globally.</p>
<p>AND <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> THAT’S <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> EXACTLY <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> HOW <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> THE <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> GOD <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> DAMN <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> LANDLORDS <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> WANT <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/clap.png?v=9" title=":clap:" class="emoji" alt=":clap:"> IT</p>
<p>We’re busy fretting about agribusiness and food processing, meanwhile real live land barons are out here collecting rent &amp; subsidy checks on millions of acres and using it as low-risk ballast for their portfolios.</p>
<p>To be clear: Wall Street is part of this.</p>
<p>So are good ol’ boys.</p>
<p>Most rural counties are run by 2-3 families that quietly own a huge slice of the land. You want to know why rural areas are so fucked up? It ain’t the coastal elites. It’s the landlords right there in the county.</p>
<p>Rural landlords might collect their rent checks directly from their serfs, I mean neighbors in the county instead of a hedge fund office in Manhattan. But they’ve got the same job. Own land, futz around all day, profit.</p>
<p>Ever notice how most proposals to solve farm-related problems- not enough food, too much food, soil conservation, wildlife conservation, water shortages-</p>
<p>all seem to boil down to “throw money at land owners”?</p>
<p>Isn’t that weird?</p>
<p>The philosophy behind conservation payments is sometimes people own farmland that’s too fragile to farm.</p>
<p>But not farming loses money! Therefore, we must pay them not to farm it!</p>
<p>Is anybody asking why own “farmland” that can’t be farmed in the first place?</p>
<p>This is a problem that could be solved a lot of different ways. Trusts, land buybacks, tax writeoffs for donating to conservation, etc. These are all used to some extent.</p>
<p>But the big federal programs are all built around sending landowners a reliable subsidy check every year.</p>
<p>So … yeah. Sometimes rural land ownership is just an instrument for rich people to extort bribes from taxpayers. “Pay me or I’ll ruin your water.”</p>
<p>And sometimes you just monetize it on the corn platform.</p>
<p>Either way, it’s a huge asset class. In many ways it’s more influential &amp; politically powerful than the “industrial food” sector we’ve been taught to fear. But it’s invisible, distant, and quiet, monetizing the earth in ways few of us understand.</p>
<p>welp my soundcloud is at <a href="https://soundcloud.com/farm-to-taber-podcast">https://soundcloud.com/farm-to-taber-podcast</a> &amp; you can support grumpy, sciencey, intersectional, independent farm journalism at <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=5610560">https://www.patreon.com/user?u=5610560</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Bonus links, a musical cartoon, “Chudesnitsa”, praising the virtues of corn in agriculture, from Nikita Khrushchev’s USSR:</p>
<aside class="onebox twitterstatus">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/sovietvisuals/status/762223983139749889" target="_blank" rel="noopener">twitter.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/aa0ae9b6ac9366cd4b2b4001e77890f99ea1a9a6.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="450" height="360">

<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/sovietvisuals/status/762223983139749889" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Soviet Visuals (sovietvisuals)</a></h4>

<div class="tweet"> 1955: massive corn campaign led by Nikita Khrushchev. 1957: this cartoon about corn comes out. ("Chudesnitsa") https://t.co/mO3IEjZblY</div>

<div class="date">
  <a href="https://twitter.com/sovietvisuals/status/762223983139749889" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2:48 AM - 7 Aug 2016</a>
    <span class="like">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 512 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M462.3 62.6C407.5 15.9 326 24.3 275.7 76.2L256 96.5l-19.7-20.3C186.1 24.3 104.5 15.9 49.7 62.6c-62.8 53.6-66.1 149.8-9.9 207.9l193.5 199.8c12.5 12.9 32.8 12.9 45.3 0l193.5-199.8c56.3-58.1 53-154.3-9.8-207.9z"></path>
      </svg> 1.9K
    </span>
    <span class="retweet">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 640 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M629.657 343.598L528.971 444.284c-9.373 9.372-24.568 9.372-33.941 0L394.343 343.598c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941l10.823-10.823c9.562-9.562 25.133-9.34 34.419.492L480 342.118V160H292.451a24.005 24.005 0 0 1-16.971-7.029l-16-16C244.361 121.851 255.069 96 276.451 96H520c13.255 0 24 10.745 24 24v222.118l40.416-42.792c9.285-9.831 24.856-10.054 34.419-.492l10.823 10.823c9.372 9.372 9.372 24.569-.001 33.941zm-265.138 15.431A23.999 23.999 0 0 0 347.548 352H160V169.881l40.416 42.792c9.286 9.831 24.856 10.054 34.419.491l10.822-10.822c9.373-9.373 9.373-24.569 0-33.941L144.971 67.716c-9.373-9.373-24.569-9.373-33.941 0L10.343 168.402c-9.373 9.373-9.373 24.569 0 33.941l10.822 10.822c9.562 9.562 25.133 9.34 34.419-.491L96 169.881V392c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h243.549c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-16.001-16z"></path>
      </svg> 873
    </span>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<div class="onebox lazyYT lazyYT-container" data-youtube-id="YTMu_FNvBAA" data-youtube-title="Чудесница (1957)" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque">
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YTMu_FNvBAA" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <img class="ytp-thumbnail-image" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/30c123c03e23d670b1ce880f085d2476bc8fae9a.jpeg" title="Чудесница (1957)" width="480" height="360">
  </a>
</div>

<p><a href="https://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D0%A7%D1%83%D0%B4%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D0%B8%D1%86%D0%B0_(%D0%BC%D1%83%D0%BB%D1%8C%D1%82%D1%84%D0%B8%D0%BB%D1%8C%D0%BC)">Чудесница (мультфильм)</a> (Russian Wikipedia)</p>
<p>Pete</p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 19:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-575-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/corn-is-a-platform/575.rss">CORN IS A PLATFORM</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
