<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The coming land rush in space</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-coming-land-rush-in-space/556</link>
    <description># The coming land rush in space

excerpted from the [Axios Space newsletter](https://www.axios.com/newsletters/axios-space-7c204c56-0dd0-4bae-867c-fedeb53dd63f.html), who writes, &quot;please send your tips, questions and deeds for lunar homes to [miriam.kramer@axios.com](mailto:miriam.kramer@axios.com).&quot;

**Space is the new Wild West.** Nations and space companies are racing to come to a consensus on what they can own, mine and take possession of in outer space before competitors stake ground first.

**Why it matters:** Private companies are building their businesses on sending spacecraft to the Moon, asteroids and other objects in the coming years to extract resources that will be used or sold.

- While countries and companies are still years away from being able to effectively mine the Moon for resources, the lack of clear regulation creates uncertainty for them — and threatens projections that the space industry will become a trillion-dollar industry by 2040.

**What&#39;s happening:** In an [economics report](https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/ERP-2021/pdf/ERP-2021-chapter8.pdf) released just before the Biden administration took office, the Trump administration warned that working out space property rights will be key to the space industry&#39;s growth.

**The big picture:** Right now, the [UN&#39;s Outer Space Treaty](https://www.unoosa.org/oosa/en/ourwork/spacelaw/treaties/outerspacetreaty.html) effectively governs property rights in space, but it&#39;s very much open to interpretation, particularly when it comes to space companies, experts say.

- Countries and companies cannot own land on cosmic bodies, but countries have effectively been allowed to own what they can extract in space — like dirt from the Moon.
- The big question now is centered around what companies might be able to own and sell eventually — like water they extract from the Moon or heavy metals from asteroids — without owning property.

**The intrigue:** Today, many in the space industry are advocating for a framework governing property rights that isn&#39;t based on a &quot;first-come, first-served&quot; mentality.

- Instead of seeing space as a place that should be exploited for gains by one nation, many are starting to think the focus should be on preservation and fairness among many.
- &quot;We can find ways to both develop and use resources, and do so in a responsible way,&quot; Jessy Kate Schingler of the Open Lunar Foundation told me.

**NASA is working** to sign a variety of nations onto its [Artemis Accords](https://www.axios.com/artemis-accords-moon-nasa-space-resources-9023d727-2e85-4fc0-a0a3-ca8c7769ee66.html), in part, as a way to standardize how nations are looking at resource extraction and development in space.

- While NASA wants to help create a sustainable environment for private development of space, the most important thing for the space agency today is to focus on a robust framework for using resources extracted in space — called ISRU, or in-situ resource utilization — and scientific sampling, according to NASA&#39;s Mike Gold.
- NASA has plans to [buy cached Moon dirt](https://www.space.com/nasa-will-buy-moon-dirt-masten-ispace-lunar-outpost) from four private companies that are expected to launch to the lunar surface in the coming years.

**Yes, but:** Aside from the U.S., China is arguably the nation closest to being able to extract resources from cosmic bodies, and Beijing hasn&#39;t yet signed on to the Artemis Accords.

- NASA is unable to enter into bilateral agreements with China without congressional approval, so getting on the same page will likely be difficult for both nations.

**What&#39;s next:** The space industry is now looking to the Biden administration to see what comes next for space property rights.

- Some predict the new administration will slow down efforts to get people back to the Moon by 2024, opting for a later date instead.
- That could lead to companies like Blue Origin and SpaceX, which are already working on building spacecraft to land humans on the Moon, jumping ahead of NASA — and potentially driving the direction of new rules.
- &quot;So having a regulatory or policy framework that responds to that is going to be even more important,&quot; Schingler said.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:14:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>#random</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-coming-land-rush-in-space/556.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The coming land rush in space</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[GlennMII]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If it’s first-come, first-served, the only ones with space property will be corporations, nations and the very rich. That will only increase the wealth gap.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-coming-land-rush-in-space/556/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-coming-land-rush-in-space/556/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-556-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-coming-land-rush-in-space/556.rss">The coming land rush in space</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The coming land rush in space</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>The coming land rush in space</h1>
<p>excerpted from the <a href="https://www.axios.com/newsletters/axios-space-7c204c56-0dd0-4bae-867c-fedeb53dd63f.html">Axios Space newsletter</a>, who writes, “please send your tips, questions and deeds for lunar homes to <a href="mailto:miriam.kramer@axios.com">miriam.kramer@axios.com</a>.”</p>
<p><strong>Space is the new Wild West.</strong> Nations and space companies are racing to come to a consensus on what they can own, mine and take possession of in outer space before competitors stake ground first.</p>
<p><strong>Why it matters:</strong> Private companies are building their businesses on sending spacecraft to the Moon, asteroids and other objects in the coming years to extract resources that will be used or sold.</p>
<ul>
<li>While countries and companies are still years away from being able to effectively mine the Moon for resources, the lack of clear regulation creates uncertainty for them — and threatens projections that the space industry will become a trillion-dollar industry by 2040.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What’s happening:</strong> In an <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/ERP-2021/pdf/ERP-2021-chapter8.pdf">economics report</a> released just before the Biden administration took office, the Trump administration warned that working out space property rights will be key to the space industry’s growth.</p>
<p><strong>The big picture:</strong> Right now, the <a href="https://www.unoosa.org/oosa/en/ourwork/spacelaw/treaties/outerspacetreaty.html">UN’s Outer Space Treaty</a> effectively governs property rights in space, but it’s very much open to interpretation, particularly when it comes to space companies, experts say.</p>
<ul>
<li>Countries and companies cannot own land on cosmic bodies, but countries have effectively been allowed to own what they can extract in space — like dirt from the Moon.</li>
<li>The big question now is centered around what companies might be able to own and sell eventually — like water they extract from the Moon or heavy metals from asteroids — without owning property.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The intrigue:</strong> Today, many in the space industry are advocating for a framework governing property rights that isn’t based on a “first-come, first-served” mentality.</p>
<ul>
<li>Instead of seeing space as a place that should be exploited for gains by one nation, many are starting to think the focus should be on preservation and fairness among many.</li>
<li>“We can find ways to both develop and use resources, and do so in a responsible way,” Jessy Kate Schingler of the Open Lunar Foundation told me.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>NASA is working</strong> to sign a variety of nations onto its <a href="https://www.axios.com/artemis-accords-moon-nasa-space-resources-9023d727-2e85-4fc0-a0a3-ca8c7769ee66.html">Artemis Accords</a>, in part, as a way to standardize how nations are looking at resource extraction and development in space.</p>
<ul>
<li>While NASA wants to help create a sustainable environment for private development of space, the most important thing for the space agency today is to focus on a robust framework for using resources extracted in space — called ISRU, or in-situ resource utilization — and scientific sampling, according to NASA’s Mike Gold.</li>
<li>NASA has plans to <a href="https://www.space.com/nasa-will-buy-moon-dirt-masten-ispace-lunar-outpost">buy cached Moon dirt</a> from four private companies that are expected to launch to the lunar surface in the coming years.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yes, but:</strong> Aside from the U.S., China is arguably the nation closest to being able to extract resources from cosmic bodies, and Beijing hasn’t yet signed on to the Artemis Accords.</p>
<ul>
<li>NASA is unable to enter into bilateral agreements with China without congressional approval, so getting on the same page will likely be difficult for both nations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What’s next:</strong> The space industry is now looking to the Biden administration to see what comes next for space property rights.</p>
<ul>
<li>Some predict the new administration will slow down efforts to get people back to the Moon by 2024, opting for a later date instead.</li>
<li>That could lead to companies like Blue Origin and SpaceX, which are already working on building spacecraft to land humans on the Moon, jumping ahead of NASA — and potentially driving the direction of new rules.</li>
<li>“So having a regulatory or policy framework that responds to that is going to be even more important,” Schingler said.</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-coming-land-rush-in-space/556/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-coming-land-rush-in-space/556/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 19:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-post-556-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/the-coming-land-rush-in-space/556.rss">The coming land rush in space</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
