<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Action! Doing Things Now - Open Global Mind Forum</title>
    <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/actions-discussions/action-doing-things-now/16</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Action! Doing Things Now&#39; category Many of us have a drive to get things done, now. We’ve been in too many groups that are just thinking and talking, but don’t get stuff done.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 05:31:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/c/actions-discussions/action-doing-things-now/16.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>An OGM Wiki: Preview &amp; Planning</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>For a while now, OGM has needed better shared memory.  I’m going to make a bold assertion and say that a good platform would be a wiki – an OGM Wiki.</p>
<p>I’ve been holding off of even really suggesting such a thing because all the wiki platforms haven’t quite fit our needs.  But together with a few others – Bill, Charles, Vincent, and Jerry – I think we’ve come up with a platform architecture that will serve OGM well.</p>
<p>It’s minimally usable now, but it will become a lot more user-friendly in a month or two.  I don’t want to focus too much on the platform yet (unless you really want to geek out with us to help make it more user-friendly!).</p>
<p>But with the platform coming together, I think it’s a good time to talk start talking about the contents and operation of the wiki itself.  What would we use a wiki for?  What teams of volunteers do we need to make it a community asset?  How would we arrange information and knowledge in a wiki?  How would an OGM wiki interface with other communities’ knowledgebases?</p>
<p>Let’s explore those and any other questions in two pop-up OGM exploration calls I will host this week:</p>
<p>Tuesday 3/16, 10:30am PDT / 1:30pm EDT / 5:30pm UTC / 6:30pm CET<br>
Wednesday 3/17, 8:00am PDT / 11:00am EDT / 3:00pm UTC / 4:00pm CET</p>
<p><a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/j/81369085502">https://us02web.zoom.us/j/81369085502</a></p>
<p>We’ll record and share the meetings.  Don’t worry if you can’t make it this time, these are early explorations, and we’ll continue to do more over the coming weeks and months.</p>
            <p><small>11 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/an-ogm-wiki-preview-planning/607">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/an-ogm-wiki-preview-planning/607</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 05:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-607</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/an-ogm-wiki-preview-planning/607.rss">An OGM Wiki: Preview &amp; Planning</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>A Good Surface Sanitizer/Cleaner: Hypochlorous Acid</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey, so I recently discovered a great cleaning product, hypochlorous acid (HOCl).  You don’t know about it because A) it’s a generic, so there’s no brand name marketing behind it, and B) it dissociates pretty quickly into water and a tiny bit of salt, so classically it’s an industrial cleaner made on site.</p>
<p>(Or maybe you know about it already, and I am only now catching up. :-))</p>
<p>Anyway, this is not a marketing pitch, nor is it professional public health and safety advice, just a pointer.</p>
<p>It’s mainly for hard, non-porous surfaces, and it’s for sanitizing/disinfecting, and for cutting light grease or things like soap film/soap scum or the pink biofilm in the shower.  It is not particularly useful for heavily soiled / bulk debris; you should rinse/wipe/wash off soil/debris, first, then use the HOCl.</p>
<p>It smells like chlorine when you spray it, but not offensively so.  (My wife and I both like it; it smells “clean.”)  It’s related to bleach (hypochlorite), but it’s different (and better for disinfecting/sanitizing).</p>
<p>It’s mostly water, and reasonably safe around people and pets.  You wouldn’t drink it or indiscriminately soak your skin in it, but it’s actually used in wound care.  It can be used on food and food-contact surfaces as a no-rinse sanitizer.</p>
<p>It is included on the US EPA List N, of sanitizers effective against SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19):</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/01b7a0a131bec15c284387613a3d69d335952615.png" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.epa.gov/pesticide-registration/list-n-advanced-search-page-disinfectants-coronavirus-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener" title="06:03PM - 13 August 2020">US EPA – 13 Aug 20</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/89fb3cb8d9a4523beaf2c238efd0d761d9b4c34c.png" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h3><a href="https://www.epa.gov/pesticide-registration/list-n-advanced-search-page-disinfectants-coronavirus-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">List N Advanced Search Page: Disinfectants for Coronavirus (COVID-19) | US EPA</a></h3>

<p>Search EPA’s list n legacy search page of registered disinfectants for use against SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes the novel coronavirus (COVID-19).&nbsp;</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>To kill SARS-CoV-2 on a surface, you spray it on the surface (even food prep or fruit/vegetable surfaces) and leave it wet for 10 minutes.</p>
<p>(I believe that public health consensus is that surface sanitization is not particularly necessary with COVID-19, because it’s mostly airborne, and you should just wash your hands more often.  We still spray all our groceries when they’re delivered.  Partly, I think, it’s just a way of feeling like we have a little control in our uncertain times.  YMMV.)</p>
<p>You can buy it pre-made, or because it dissociates over time, you can buy a “generator” that makes it via electrolysis out of water and a tiny bit of salt and distilled vinegar.  (The acetic acid is for pH control; if the solution is acidic, you get hypochlorous acid; if the solution is basic, you get hypochlorite, which is more dangerous and not as effective.)</p>
<p>I started with a two-pack of spray bottles (happened to be CleanSmart brand), and then bought a small generator (Force of Nature).</p>
<p>I found three kinds of home generators (as opposed to industrial):</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The ~$300 kind, which I did not explore.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The ~$90-$120 fairly generic kind from Chinese manufacturers; I think these are probably pretty much the same as <span class="hashtag">#1</span>, with different packaging, manuals, and customer support.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Force of Nature, ~$50 + ~$1 per 12oz of HOCl.  They’re a US consumer-oriented company, and obtained an EPA registration for the hypochlorous acid their generator produces.  Partly because of the EPA registration and the need for precise formulation, or perhaps partly as a razor/razor blade model, they sell small ampoules of salt+vinegar that you use, 1 ampoule per 12 oz of solution.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>I was pretty close to buying a <span class="hashtag">#2</span> machine, but to do it right, you need to buy chlorine and pH test strips, which turns out to be sort of an ongoing expense like FoN’s ampoules.  Plus, you have to measure your salt and control the pH, and the base machine costs more than FoN… long story short, I appreciate FoN’s US consumer-oriented approach, and don’t find their supply cost onerous compared to the convenience.</p>
<p>Don’t buy FoN at Amazon, it’s expensive there.  Rather, if you buy one, buy direct from their website, and make sure you get a 15% or 20% coupon code. <a href="https://www.forceofnatureclean.com/">https://www.forceofnatureclean.com/</a></p>
<p>Again, not a marketing pitch, and not professional health and safety advice.  Do your own research, and/or contact your public health and safety officials.</p>
<p>This post is licensed under CC0/is public domain; please feel free to distribute as you wish.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-good-surface-sanitizer-cleaner-hypochlorous-acid/596">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-good-surface-sanitizer-cleaner-hypochlorous-acid/596</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 16:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-596</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-good-surface-sanitizer-cleaner-hypochlorous-acid/596.rss">A Good Surface Sanitizer/Cleaner: Hypochlorous Acid</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How to Start Doing Things NOW</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tony]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In order to make sense of complicated events (activities) we first need to understand what is meant by “complexity” .   For activity based systems (and any system that is goal oriented is activity based), complexity means tight coupling between the activities.  That is that there are so many inputs/outputs between the activities that we can not figure out what is going on.</p>
<p>In order to make sense of complex activities, we need to reduce the coupling between activities.   This can be done by repartitioning the activities based on following the natural flow which, if done correctly, greatly reduces the inputs/outputs between activities.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-start-doing-things-now/581">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-start-doing-things-now/581</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 14:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-581</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/how-to-start-doing-things-now/581.rss">How to Start Doing Things NOW</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Emergent Event Sensemaking</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>A proto-guild is forming on mattermost around sensemaking of complicated emergent events, I think particularly where there are complex system dynamics and information overload:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://chat.collectivesensecommons.org/agora/channels/emergent-event-sensemaking">Emergent Event Sensemaking</a></li>
</ul>
<p>We’re focusing on the <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/r-wallstreetbets-vs-hedge-funds-gme/558">GameStop short squeeze</a> as a first exercise, but other examples might include 9/11, the 2008 mortage crash, Fukushima, COVID-19 responses, etc.</p>
<p>Stephan Kreutzer first proposed this in the Off-Topic channel, and he describes the idea well:</p>
<p>“there could be a systemic and continual approach, to quickly condense the flood of information/feeds into approximating working models for overview/navigating.”</p>
<p>So far the tools we are considering include:</p>
<ul>
<li>static 2D diagramming / flowcharts</li>
<li>interactive system dynamics modeling, with e.g. Insight Maker</li>
</ul>
<p>The efforts to guild-form may or may not go anywhere, we’ll see.  Everybody has busy lives, and we may not actually get the spark of the idea off the ground; but, you’re welcome to join in if it sounds interesting to see where it goes.</p>
            <p><small>19 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/emergent-event-sensemaking/567">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/emergent-event-sensemaking/567</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 15:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-567</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/emergent-event-sensemaking/567.rss">Emergent Event Sensemaking</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>CAUTION: Variants Ahead - B117 and other variants will explode soon in the US</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>(crossposted from my <a href="https://petescovid19.substack.com/p/caution-variants-ahead">COVID-19 newsletter</a>)</p>
<p>I wrote about <a href="https://petescovid19.substack.com/p/b117">B.1.1.7, the “UK variant” of SARS-CoV-2</a>, back in December, hoping that it wouldn’t end up being bad news.</p>
<p>Well, now we know, it is bad news — it is more infectious, on the order of 50% - 70% more.</p>
<p>“More infectious” just means that it spreads better, meaning more cases faster, meaning healthcare systems getting strained more quickly, and ultimately meaning, long-term damage to more bodies and more deaths.</p>
<p>Researchers are tracking the emergence of other meaningful variants. For all the variants, the questions are:</p>
<ul>
<li>does it spread better?</li>
<li>will the vaccines have reduced effectiveness, and might we need additional kinds of vaccines to respond?</li>
<li>will the symptoms and health outcomes it causes be worse?</li>
</ul>
<p>There is a possible “yes,” at least to some extent, for each of these questions, for different variants. For a few, we know for sure that they spread better.</p>
<p>That wouldn’t be a big deal for a small number of infections… but the problem is that this deal will be exponential.</p>
<p>Sometimes people just mean “bigger” when they say “exponential,” but the technical, mathematical definition of “exponential” means not only bigger, but getting bigger <em>as</em> it gets bigger.</p>
<p>IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT TO TAKE THESE NEW VARIANTS SERIOUSLY.</p>
<p>I could say a lot more, but I don’t think I can say it more clearly than that. So I’ll leave you with that, and some of the best reading I’ve come across on the subject, below.</p>
<p>We can meet the challenge of the new variants, but it will require doing all the things we’ve been doing, AND better than we have been. Masks, distance, hand hygiene, bubbles, travel restrictions, vaccine production, vaccine distribution, and actually getting a shot when it’s available to you.</p>
<p>IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT TO TAKE THESE NEW VARIANTS SERIOUSLY.</p>
<p>Okay, read some of these:</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/europe/uk-variant-covid-denmark/2021/01/22/ddfaf420-5453-11eb-acc5-92d2819a1ccb_story.html">Denmark’s coronavirus sequencing shows U.K. variant cases exploding</a></strong> (The Washington Post, 2021-01-22)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In a long Facebook post this month, Prime Minister Mette Frederiksen told people to imagine sitting in the top row of Copenhagen’s Parken Stadium, a soccer arena with a capacity of 38,000 people. A dripping tap is filling it up, one drop the first minute, two drops the second, four drops the third. At that rate, Frederiksen said, the park will be filled in 44 minutes. But it will seem almost empty for the first 42 minutes, she said.</p>
<p>“The point is, you only realize that the water has risen when it’s almost too late,” she wrote.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2021/01/27/double-mask-variants-guidance/">Time to double mask or upgrade masks as coronavirus variants emerge, experts say</a></strong> (The Washington Post, 2021-01-28)</p>
<p>(A lot of this article talks about expert confusion — should we recommend a medical-grade mask or not? Should we recommend double-masking? Countries in Europe are less wishy-washy, perhaps because they’re closer and more aware of how hard B117 hit the UK. Again, take the variants seriously, it’s time to have better masks when you’re around other people. Along with N95, you should research KN95, KF94, and FFP2.)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/19/well/live/covid-b117-variant-advice.html">What You Can Do to Avoid the New Coronavirus Variant Right Now</a></strong> (The New York Times, 2021-01-19)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/ezraklein/status/1354830708515037186">“This is the part of the horror film where safety seems in sight, but it is obvious, to those paying attention, that the monster is not dead, and that the worst may be yet to come. We cannot let ourselves be taken by surprise.”</a></strong> (Ezra Klein, 2021-01-28)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/DrEricDing/status/1354646619174678529">“WORRISOME MATH—#B117 variant is so crazy: what happens if there are just 10 cases now, &amp; new UK #B117 has 50% greater transmissibility?”</a></strong> (Eric Feigl-Ding, 2021-01-27)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2020/12/virus-mutation-catastrophe/617531/">The Mutated Virus Is a Ticking Time Bomb</a></strong> (The Atlantic, 2020-12-31)</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/more/science-and-research/scientific-brief-emerging-variants.html">Emerging SARS-CoV-2 Variants</a></strong> (CDC, last updated 2021-01-28)</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/caution-variants-ahead-b117-and-other-variants-will-explode-soon-in-the-us/562">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/caution-variants-ahead-b117-and-other-variants-will-explode-soon-in-the-us/562</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 16:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-562</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/caution-variants-ahead-b117-and-other-variants-will-explode-soon-in-the-us/562.rss">CAUTION: Variants Ahead - B117 and other variants will explode soon in the US</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>A project to fight misinformation and model critical thinking: Gulli Bot</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[BentleyDavis]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’ve been working on misinformation for almost 10 years and I ask for your help on this as a project and some quests. My current plan is to create an online character that models and documents critical thinking on contentious issues named <a href="https://GulliBot.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Gulli Bot</a>.</p>
<p>Gulli is just a character powered by humans (no artificial intelligence or machine learning) but it does have a way of representing a debate in a very transparent and thorough way so people can quickly and easily understand the scope of all the claims about the issue.</p>
<p>The first topic is “<a href="https://gullibot.com/covid-vaccine/" rel="nofollow noopener">Should you take the COVID-19 vaccine?</a>” and I could use help is choosing popular issues to analyze and researching them.</p>
<p>Let me know if you would like more info or be interested in helping with this project.</p>
            <p><small>17 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-project-to-fight-misinformation-and-model-critical-thinking-gulli-bot/559">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-project-to-fight-misinformation-and-model-critical-thinking-gulli-bot/559</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 15:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-559</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/a-project-to-fight-misinformation-and-model-critical-thinking-gulli-bot/559.rss">A project to fight misinformation and model critical thinking: Gulli Bot</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>&quot;Underestimating the Challenges of Avoiding a Ghastly Future&quot;</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Clarion call roundup of where we are and where we’re going with climate change.  Sort of an Inconvenient Truth for 2021.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We report three major and confronting environmental issues that have received little attention and require urgent action. First, we review the evidence that future environmental conditions will be far more dangerous than currently believed. The scale of the threats to the biosphere and all its lifeforms—including humanity—is in fact so great that it is difficult to grasp for even well-informed experts. Second, we ask what political or economic system, or leadership, is prepared to handle the predicted disasters, or even capable of such action. Third, this dire situation places an extraordinary responsibility on scientists to speak out candidly and accurately when engaging with government, business, and the public. We especially draw attention to the lack of appreciation of the enormous challenges to creating a sustainable future.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Article for the general public:</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/585fee1a8040b36bda6a7356c78d13f3b31ff028.png" class="site-icon" width="192" height="192">
      <a href="https://theconversation.com/worried-about-earths-future-well-the-outlook-is-worse-than-even-scientists-can-grasp-153091" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Conversation</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/339;"><img src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/378461/original/file-20210113-21-rwemte.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;rect=8%2C491%2C5551%2C2775&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="339"></div>

<h3><a href="https://theconversation.com/worried-about-earths-future-well-the-outlook-is-worse-than-even-scientists-can-grasp-153091" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Worried about Earth's future? Well, the outlook is worse than even scientists...</a></h3>

<p>Humanity is destroying Earth’s ability to support complex life. But coming to grips with the magnitude of the problem is hard, even for experts.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>The report itself:</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://3718aeafc638f96f5bd6-d4a9ca15fc46ba40e71f94dec0aad28c.ssl.cf1.rackcdn.com/favicon_16x16.ico" class="site-icon" width="48" height="48">
      <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fcosc.2020.615419/full" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Frontiers</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:400/331;"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/18a01568ec49e1347a550e76fcdbeba09ca469de.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="400" height="331"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fcosc.2020.615419/full" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Underestimating the Challenges of Avoiding a Ghastly Future</a></h3>

<p>We report three major and confronting environmental issues that have received little attention and require urgent action. First, we review the evidence that future environmental conditions will be far more dangerous than currently believed. The scale...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/underestimating-the-challenges-of-avoiding-a-ghastly-future/539">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/underestimating-the-challenges-of-avoiding-a-ghastly-future/539</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 16:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-539</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/underestimating-the-challenges-of-avoiding-a-ghastly-future/539.rss">&quot;Underestimating the Challenges of Avoiding a Ghastly Future&quot;</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Flotilla Project is Working on Directories</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/arena">@Arena</a> and I would like to low-key announce two things:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><a href="https://flotillaproject.xyz/project/flotilla-project/">Flotilla Project</a>, which will be doing some experiments around, and building working prototypes of, project, association, and people directories for OGM and other communities over the next few months.  The working name for these experiments is <a href="https://flotillaproject.xyz/">Flotilla</a>.  (That current website is a simple, hand-built placeholder, which just lists the two things we’re announcing - one of our first experiments.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The <a href="https://flotillaproject.xyz/association/tools-for-connectors-association/">Tools for Connectors Association</a>, which is a special interest group for makers, designers, and other people interested in tools and processes that help connect people, such as directories and matchmaking.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>We’re starting small – just Vincent and me.  We’d love to have other people join us, though!</p>
<p>After the 2020 holidays, we’re planning to have a weekly virtual open house, with a couple of hours of discussion and work, with everybody invited.</p>
<p>Keep in touch! Either in <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/flotilla-project-is-working-on-directories/503">OGM Forum/Flotilla Project is Working on Directories</a> or <a href="https://chat.collectivesensecommons.org/agora/channels/tools-for-connectors">CSC Mattermost/Tools for Connectors</a>.</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/flotilla-project-is-working-on-directories/503">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/flotilla-project-is-working-on-directories/503</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 04:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-503</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/flotilla-project-is-working-on-directories/503.rss">Flotilla Project is Working on Directories</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Why it is so difficult to persuade people</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[dougtao0]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>We hope that logic and fact will persuade people to good policies and actions. But the problem is, they enter into conversations looking for something that feels like them, that develops and protects their relationship to a group. Most of our attempt to persuade threaten to pull the ;listener  out of the group they are in and not offering a congenial new group. If you listen to most attempts to persuade the persuader wants to change the listeners ideas but not to invite them in to their own group.</p>
<p>This suggests that it won’t work to try to persuade someone with better beliefs that they ought to believe in your belief .  The listener won’t move unless they gain some sense of belonging from doing so. This is why identity politics gets in the way of fact-based politics. Showing you are part of a tribe is more important than the facts.</p>
<p>Empires, civilizations, communities are structured around belief systems, ways of understanding that give us the sense that we are right, that we belong, that we are ok in contrast to the others.</p>
<p>Democracy, the state, capital; these are not facts, they are closely-held belief systems that will not change, unless change leads to a new feeling of belonging and security – a strong tribal identity.</p>
<p>So many red-state Trump supporters can’t be persuaded by facts. They feel that giving up support for Trump leaves them without a meaningful group identity, and it is just plain scary, a step into the unknown. We must empathize with the strength of their desire to belong, and the fear of being alone.</p>
<p>This problem is supported by the increasing lack of community, as corporations have worked hard to be a substitute, and to tear apart community belonging, creating a world of belonging for those inside the corporations and marginalizing those outside.</p>
<p>The Internet connects everyone, but as isolated nodes in the network. What puts us together is also separating us into little ungovernable atoms of intensity.</p>
<p>To add some background, the word “truth” comes from “troth,” as in the wedding vows.</p>
<p>It used to mean faith, as in faith with another, but has moved from the interpersonal “faith with” to the impersonal “fact about.”</p>
<p>Humans world-wide yearn for relationships and are mostly offered market choices.</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/why-it-is-so-difficult-to-persuade-people/490">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/why-it-is-so-difficult-to-persuade-people/490</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 22:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-490</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/why-it-is-so-difficult-to-persuade-people/490.rss">Why it is so difficult to persuade people</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Opening conversations with Others</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There’s a massive cultural divide in the US. Bridging or crossing that divide is difficult. Proselytizing doesn’t really work. Straight-up arguments are lousy ways to open a trusted conversation.</p>
<p><a href="https://the.ink/p/michigancity">This interview</a> offers great advice on building trust and making progress.</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/opening-conversations-with-others/485">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/opening-conversations-with-others/485</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 06:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-485</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/opening-conversations-with-others/485.rss">Opening conversations with Others</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>SymmaSys — Wiser Together</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Technoshaman]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Yesterday, I had a lovely meeting with my friends from CICOlab, where I had a chance to present, for the first time, the concept of the platform project that I’m working on as a candidate for <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/hashverse-hashbins-sandbox/314">hashbin</a>. We decided to continue the conversation here so that other OGMers, too, can bring their reflections and questions to the project. SymmaSys, the current name of the project is explained <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/symmasys-a-platform-for-mutual-learning-among-people-organizations-communities-and-social-systems/325/9">here</a>.</p>
<p>Presently, the project is stewarded by <a href="https://futurehow.site/" rel="nofollow noopener">Future HOW</a> and I’m using this post for opening a conversation with CICOlab and other OGMers interested to learn more about and, eventually, participate in it.</p>
<p>In a broad sense, I can say that this is a project that I’ve been working on in the better part of my adult life, but in a more specific sense, only the last few months.</p>
<p><strong>1. NEED</strong></p>
<p>My projects don’t start with customer need analysis but with <em>my</em> compelling reason for doing them. I’m discovering that by sensing into what is a mission-critical need on humankind’s evolutionary journey, which I have any capability to contribute to addressing. Typically, I’m getting there, by asking such questions as: What time is it in the world? What is the need that this project can uniquely meet?<br>
What does the world need this project to be?</p>
<p>In this first section, I describe the need in the world that SymmaSys is aimed at addressing.</p>
<p>When the old world is dying and the new is yet to come, the complexity of the shift, at the scale of our planetary civilization, is inconceivable. It is so overwhelming that when we try to sense and make meaning of it, the most that even some of our best minds can do is to “build bridges into the fog,” as Tomas Björkman <a href="http://www.whatisemerging.com/opinions/building-bridges-into-the-fog" rel="nofollow noopener">wrote</a> on the “What Is Emerging?” website.<br>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/ab7e0c85d40c99820d8f231adf164f415e0a9954.jpeg" data-download-href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/ab7e0c85d40c99820d8f231adf164f415e0a9954" title="Screenshot 2020-11-03 at 13.17.02"><img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/ab7e0c85d40c99820d8f231adf164f415e0a9954.jpeg" alt="Screenshot 2020-11-03 at 13.17.02" data-base62-sha1="ot5HLT1b1gMRsboRpNRXCR1KsN6" width="690" height="462" data-small-upload="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/optimized/1X/ab7e0c85d40c99820d8f231adf164f415e0a9954_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Screenshot 2020-11-03 at 13.17.02</span><span class="informations">887×595 119 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div></p>
<p>Once we accept that our individual mind’s capacity is orders of magnitude smaller than what is required to sense what is really happening in these tumultuous times, then what?</p>
<p>Most people throw up their hands, saying, we can’t figure this out, whatever will be, will be. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xZbKHDPPrrc" rel="nofollow noopener">Que sera sera</a>. Have you ever listened to that song which was very popular, worldwide, when I was a teenager?</p>
<p>The three verses of the song progress through the life of the narrator—from childhood, through young adulthood and falling in love, to parenthood—and each asks “What will I be?” or “What lies ahead?” The chorus repeats the answer: “What will be, will be.”</p>
<p>Unfortunately, that answer wouldn’t let humankind pass its evolutionary test. I addressed why it is so in <a href="https://technoshaman.medium.com/generative-action-research-for-influencing-intentional-evolution-149169e69504" rel="nofollow noopener">Towards a Generative Action Research for Influencing Intentional Evolution</a>, where I wrote:</p>
<p>“Spontaneous, unguided social evolution can keep developing powerful forces of science and technology, but not a just social system, where all can benefit from their fruits… In fact, the one-sided development of those forces… is raising the risk of systems-wide cataclysms due to the galloping complexity of our intertwining, global messes. Our global <a href="https://www.lexico.com/definition/problematique" rel="nofollow noopener">problematique</a> is simply unmanageable at the level of social organization and consciousness that created them.”</p>
<p>Think of blind evolution that brought us so far as humanity’s childhood. For leaving its childhood and becoming a young adult, humanity needs to develop new neural pathways in the global mind.</p>
<p>I’m talking neural pathways for self-organizing, <a href="https://www.academia.edu/507278/Designing_for_the_Emergence_of_a_Global_scale_Collective_Intelligence_Invitation_to_a_Research_Collaboration" rel="nofollow noopener">global-scale collective intelligence</a>, that needs to be supported by an adequate infrastructure that I call an “innovation ecosystem.” That’s the need that the SymmaSys will respond to.</p>
<p>As you can see in my conference paper of 2001, referenced above, and in my related writings, until now my reflections about meeting that need were purely conceptual. I’m thrilled that finally, thanks to the emergence of new software components that can go the MindLinking platform, i can articulate the project with a strong R&amp;D component.</p>
<p>In the next section I will introduce the core idea of the project, in terms of its WHAT and HOW, but before that, let’s stay with the WHY that I described here, for a week or so. How does it land with you all? Does it resonate? What needs to be clarified or challenged?</p>
            <p><small>16 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/symmasys-wiser-together/325">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/symmasys-wiser-together/325</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 14:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-325</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/symmasys-wiser-together/325.rss">SymmaSys — Wiser Together</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Following Murmurations</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m following <a href="https://murmurations.network/">Murmurations – Making Movements Visible</a>, because it seems like their work might be related to work I’ve seen, and work I want to do.</p>
<p>I wanted to observe that their website (which is fancy and high production value) makes it look like Murmurations is a very simple data “application” – mapping organizations, even though it says “The Murmurations protocol…”</p>
<p>This thread, <a href="https://murmurations.flarum.cloud/d/8-developing-murmurations-v1">Developing Murmurations V1</a> - Murmurations Forum, makes it more clear that they are working on a <strong>protocol</strong>, and that the initial “application” was not meant as anything but a prototype that sat on the protocol.</p>
<p>More as it unfolds…</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/following-murmurations/245">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/following-murmurations/245</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 17:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-245</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/following-murmurations/245.rss">Following Murmurations</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Experimenting with real-time machine transcription</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[peterkaminski]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I present here some experimentation with the real-time speech-to-text transcription tools from Amazon and Google.  A short video demo:</p>
<div class="onebox lazyYT lazyYT-container" data-youtube-id="oikUJVFW_3Q" data-youtube-title="Experimenting with real-time machine transcription, 2020-09-14" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque">
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oikUJVFW_3Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <img class="ytp-thumbnail-image" src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/uploads/default/original/1X/0a6ae72964f5dd48635091848264e444ed6b98de.jpeg" title="Experimenting with real-time machine transcription, 2020-09-14" width="480" height="360">
  </a>
</div>

<p>Transcription results from both streaming and batch processes, along with a clean, human-corrected transcript are attached here as text files:</p>
<p><a class="attachment" href="/uploads/short-url/A6jQmlgiHSWRdMBffvHLbMVv7vi.txt">Transcription Experiment - OGM call 2020-09-10 - Human-corrected Transcription.txt</a> (1.4 KB)<br>
<a class="attachment" href="/uploads/short-url/werV1MLznwkzwbAfZHVv3luH6uY.txt">Transcription Experiment - OGM call 2020-09-10 - AWS Transcribe Streaming.txt</a> (1.3 KB)<br>
<a class="attachment" href="/uploads/short-url/aUOLMgNNjDADIcNlyBY51weQfRy.txt">Transcription Experiment - OGM call 2020-09-10 - Google Speech-to-Text Streaming.txt</a> (1.3 KB)<br>
<a class="attachment" href="/uploads/short-url/r9kRfOPsEgXRfvsI4OrqzcRQuUX.txt">Transcription Experiment - OGM call 2020-09-10 - AWS Transcribe Batch.txt</a> (1.5 KB)<br>
<a class="attachment" href="/uploads/short-url/iHZog5WUYC9Q57NgthXIJaFKKWh.txt">Transcription Experiment - OGM call 2020-09-10 - Google Speech-to-Text Batch.txt</a> (1.2 KB)<br>
<a class="attachment" href="/uploads/short-url/9huKtplj4hGMKEvm4OfcqVEFVo2.txt">Transcription Experiment - OGM call 2020-09-10 - Google Speech-to-Text Batch with Punctuation.txt</a> (1.2 KB)</p>
<p>(Some data are left out, such as timing and alternative, lesser-confidence alternative transcriptions.)</p>
<p>Along with the practical rewards of transcribing OGM and similar calls, I think there are potential business opportunities here, and I am thinking about exploring them more seriously.</p>
<ul>
<li>The underlying machine transcription technology is “good enough” (while not yet perfect, which means there is opportunity).</li>
<li>There are not many vendors offering productized versions of the technologies (biggest are probably <a href="https://otter.ai/">Otter</a> and <a href="https://www.descript.com/">Descript</a>).</li>
<li>There are a number of potential models for productization that haven’t been explored.</li>
</ul>
<p>Some potential products or services:</p>
<ul>
<li>Transcribe virtual calls or physical meetings (the latter subject to pandemic precautions).</li>
<li>Real-time machine transcription into a collaborative text editor, where one or more humans could clean up and improve the transcription.  The result could be near-live and near-perfect transcription.</li>
<li>Offer the above as a product, or offer the above as a service.</li>
<li>Use the cleaned-up near-live transcription as input for graphic facilitators, narrative facilitators, or highlight facilitators, who would feed images, narrative structure, or highlights back into the meeting.</li>
<li>Use the above to offer the ability for someone to attend to multiple calls simultaneously, as they multitask but keep up on each call’s written transcript.</li>
<li>Use machine transcription to recognize key phrases, then have a bot look up those phrase in Google, Jerry’s Brain, etc., as Jerry suggested recently on the OGM mailing list.</li>
</ul>
<p>Anyway, for this experiment, I played <a href="https://youtu.be/_WJ5hjEIH8Y?t=1631">my check-in from the most recent OGM check-in call from YouTube</a>, simulating a live Zoom call, and ran the audio into both Amazon and Google transcription in streaming (real-time) mode.  I also ran the whole call through batch transcription with both Amazon and Google.</p>
<p>The transcription starts with the end of Tony’s check-in, then Jerry switching over to me, then my check-in, then Jerry switching over to Avril.  My voice and speech quality is okay but not great - volume varies, and there are a number of filler words (um, uh) to navigate.</p>
<p>All of the machine transcriptions are good, but not perfect.  Some quick observations:</p>
<ul>
<li>This is a technology demo, of course, not a product yet.  But it still shows great promise.</li>
<li>The Google transcription colors are red for “draft” transcription, and green for a completed chunk.  The distracting duplication of lines is an artifact of the library I’m using, which can handle one draft line of text, but duplicates lines when there is more than one draft line of text.</li>
<li>Google’s streaming latency is really good – almost real-time.  (This is similar to what I see on my Pixel smartphone with Google’s “Live Caption” feature, by the way.)</li>
<li>Amazon’s streaming latency is a little challenging – it sometimes takes seconds to catch up.  I am guessing it’s not the backend, but rather that library I’m using to transfer the audio to the cloud, and it might be possible to get low latency with Amazon streaming, too.</li>
<li>Punctuation is really nice.  The default for Google is “no punctuation”, but you can enable punctuation for Google, which I did with one Google batch sample.  I missed enabling it for the streaming sample.</li>
<li>Less-common words and names are generally harder for the machines to recognize.  This would make it hard to do the auto-look-up bot work without human assistance.</li>
</ul>
<p>I am expecting to continue to play around with these technologies – let me know if you’d like to be involved.</p>
            <p><small>16 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/experimenting-with-real-time-machine-transcription/240">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/experimenting-with-real-time-machine-transcription/240</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 15:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-240</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/experimenting-with-real-time-machine-transcription/240.rss">Experimenting with real-time machine transcription</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Project updates/coordination (2020-09-06)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[skreutzer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So from the recent OGM check-in call I pick up that the plan is to expand the amount of weekly calls focusing on particular topics/domains/projects, and the check-in call for reporting back on progress and pick up reviews/feedback/direction.</p>
<p>Is there somebody willing + able to extract and mine the findings and main topics covered in these? Is there machinery available by now or soon which would allow to get a guide/index into the recording as constructed/computed from the transcript? Could the result of such processing provided to the people in the OGM space? <a class="mention" href="/u/peterkaminski">@peterkaminski</a>  <a class="mention" href="/u/max">@max</a> If the expanded events go on for some time without tool/methodological/curation support, I guess that would lead to some people not being able to attend and stay aware, and with a growing unstructured pile of material, there’s less hope that it might get curated later and still be relevant or connect to the current state of thinking/conversation.</p>
<p>There’s the idea of <a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/storythreading-at-least-a-place-to-store-some-links-or-ideas-for-now">StoryThreading</a> as a facilitation service/role, and OGM already and only increasingly so would urgently need that kind of organization and condensation, to help with navigating and orienting within the growing record and get something useful out of it without requiring an enormous time investment. But it looks like, as such curation/facilitation activities haven’t started much on OGM content already (doogfooding, safe experiments in this sandbox, bootstrapping), the Storythreading discussion might be exclusively designed as a commercial offer, which is fine. So is it then the case that OGM itself ironically might remain without facilitation and curation for its own material?</p>
<p>I also have seen several diagrams and system graph visualizations. Is there anybody around (including those who came up with the drawings/models as well as those who saw them) who would want to make a case for trying to translate them into actual processes, practices and/or tools to be used on/with OGM and other groups and beyond (meta)? And be it an experiment to learn something about these models and how to possibly apply/implement them. The other option is that they’re capturing an observation of flows and relations which already exist, in which case it’s the other way around, having a close look of how to measure/track these, if that’s interesting or of use – and if not, what would be the purpose of having the diagram then? <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> Onboarding would likely be a typical candidate, notifications about certain events maybe too, identifying and establishing connections, starting to make use of pattern languages and roles, and similar.</p>
<p>These things should not be put in place simply because one is used to such instruments and approaches in the workplace, but have their benefit in channeling energy and attention in a beneficial way instead of scattering and burning/wasting them into the void, including your very own! As this is as of now mostly an open peer space, the precise design and mechanisms are all up for discussion, exploration and change, there could even be multiple ones used in parallel for each of the respective purposes.</p>
<p>It’s also interesting to observe that there’s an uptake in the use of the mailing list again, instead of retiring it in favor of this Discourse forum. I think that this most likely comes from the impression that the mailing list is active push-out/broadcast, so people think their messages have a better change to get read, in comparison to posting to the forum that’s of less immediate notification and pull. Does the Website link to the Discourse forum for registration (if that’s even desirable and not counterproductive), or is the Google form onboarding to it? Plus, e-mail messages in many cases might end up in the inbox of the e-mail client together with many other messages, so it’s more convenient to review them there, in comparison to have to log in into a Website and actively look up if there’s something new (sometimes that might not be the case), or for replying. Same likely goes for online calls, as every attendee is spending lots of dedicated time and attention in exchange of receiving a small slot of the same in exchange. For progress of practical work, asynchronous task tracking tends to be far more efficient. Doesn’t exclude discussing results from the operational departments in the context of more social exchanges or conversational formats, especially to accompany and direct iterative developments over longer periods of time.</p>
<p>Haven’t heard some news (no matter which direction, just a lack of clarity which can easily lead to a lot of loss and frustration down the line) regarding the publication and libre-free licensing of any of the material as a growing amount of it gets produced, so I wonder if all of these OGM things are to be considered trapped and stuck legally as well as technically, not much categorically and pratically different from putting it all into TheBrain as far as I’m concerned.</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/project-updates-coordination-2020-09-06/218">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/project-updates-coordination-2020-09-06/218</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-218</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/project-updates-coordination-2020-09-06/218.rss">Project updates/coordination (2020-09-06)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What next - thoughts from the food world</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Klaus]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>A question that comes to mind: what organizational shapes could OGM evolve that meet a premeditated outcome?</p>
<p>Here is one example that just passed through, the ‘<a href="https://www.foodforclimateleague.org" rel="nofollow noopener">Food for Climate League</a>’. It’s a 501c3 non-profit, but clearly they intent to not just self-finance, but also thrive in their endeavor. I love everything about it.</p>
<p>There is quite some energy in the <a href="https://benefitcorp.net/businesses" rel="nofollow noopener">Benefit Corporation</a> space, again pros and cons. Also important to think that multiple such structures could come underneath an umbrella, with a coordinating function in mind.</p>
<p>Endless options; I’m solidly committed to the food space, generally agreed is low hanging fruit. It will be the most logical next battle ground, and any missteps on a macro level would be catastrophic, existential.</p>
            <p><small>13 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/what-next-thoughts-from-the-food-world/196">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/what-next-thoughts-from-the-food-world/196</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 23:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-196</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/what-next-thoughts-from-the-food-world/196.rss">What next - thoughts from the food world</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Invitation: Write and distribute a weekly newsletter of what happened in the online collaboration/conversation space</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[skreutzer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There are many online conversation groups, and to a lesser extend a few who practically collaborate on some project work. This project is about observing what went on with them and briefly summarize such on a weekly basis in order to distribute the compiled result. No particular expectations/obligations for this early experiment, just to get started with the practice/offer.</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-write-and-distribute-a-weekly-newsletter-of-what-happened-in-the-online-collaboration-conversation-space/172">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-write-and-distribute-a-weekly-newsletter-of-what-happened-in-the-online-collaboration-conversation-space/172</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-172</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-write-and-distribute-a-weekly-newsletter-of-what-happened-in-the-online-collaboration-conversation-space/172.rss">Invitation: Write and distribute a weekly newsletter of what happened in the online collaboration/conversation space</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Invitation: Design + build a collection and feed of project invitations/requests</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[skreutzer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This prototype project is supposed to collect project proposals from many sources, and provide them as a feed, so people can “subscribe” and review the offers/invitations and get in touch for working on the projects they’re interested in.</p>
<p>This has a data gathering/curation component, also needs some design (ideally some federation/categorization/tagging too eventually, what kind of service is it - app, mailing list, other?), and then the software development to set it up and get it running.</p>
<p>In terms of content, surely the result should be universal and work for many types of data, but for our OGM purposes, the kind of service we would like to set up and run in this experiment is one to cross-promote small-scale, prototyping, experimental projects on a scale of 1 day to ~3 weeks (which then can branch off into a larger effort), and preferably also pretty inclusive, meaning that participants in different roles would be helpful, not just all-tech or all-conceptualizing or all-content/-curation. Emphasis also on an open invitation to anybody with no prior knowledge/experience, to peer-learn skills and try things in the process.</p>
            <p><small>24 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-design-build-a-collection-and-feed-of-project-invitations-requests/150">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-design-build-a-collection-and-feed-of-project-invitations-requests/150</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 15:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-150</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-design-build-a-collection-and-feed-of-project-invitations-requests/150.rss">Invitation: Design + build a collection and feed of project invitations/requests</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Request: Tool/site/app to compare different Google Search results</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[skreutzer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The request is to build a tool/site/app/plugin which, for a search phrase, displays the Google Search results side by side based on different search configurations, namely (but not limited to) the search for exact matches (in quotation marks) and the similar, broader matches if the search is done without quotation marks around the phrase. The purpose is to become able to show any regular user the differences in the results, especially for learning and teaching tech/tool/media competency, so in schools for example students could gain understanding about how to effectively search for material on the Web and what is to be expected from different approaches.</p>
<p>Could be a very quick, simple prototype hacked together, other than that a browser plugin was suggested, main application would be in a school class.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/request-tool-site-app-to-compare-different-google-search-results/148">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/request-tool-site-app-to-compare-different-google-search-results/148</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 23:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-148</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/request-tool-site-app-to-compare-different-google-search-results/148.rss">Request: Tool/site/app to compare different Google Search results</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Bring Systems Thinking To The Masses</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tony]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The world’s problems are getting bigger all the time.   Systems Thinking is for addressing complex problems.   Yet Systems Thinking remains in the “backwaters”.  Big reason why:  Folks have an incomplete and disjointed understanding of what Systems Thinking is.   Solution:  Create a “Just Barely Complex Enough” model of a hypothetical organization system, and use it to, for the first time, tie together the concepts associated with  DSRP (Distinctions, Systems, Relationships, and Perspectives), systems dynamics, the VMS (Viable Systems Model), etc.</p>
            <p><small>42 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/bring-systems-thinking-to-the-masses/96">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/bring-systems-thinking-to-the-masses/96</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 12:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-96</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/bring-systems-thinking-to-the-masses/96.rss">Bring Systems Thinking To The Masses</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Invitation: Create a list of OGM call participants</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[skreutzer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In this activity, the participants in the OGM calls from now on need to be identified. Where missing, unclear or unknown, a few unique/disambiguatable details about their person need to be researched (usually name should be enough). To aid the former, existing lists of people need to be determined and consulted. Then, unique, technical, internal identifiers would be assigned/issued for each participant in a global, all-time “master” list/directory, which then allows the referencing between the main table and attendees of a particular, single call. The unique technical identifier is supposed to later help with attaching profile data to it, or augment mentions in a transcript/summary.</p>
<p>This list should only include individuals who participated in a call of which the recording was published, if they also said something or “appeared”. Everybody gets a veto right to be excluded, removed, whitelisted. None of the data should be personal or sensible, other than what’s publicly shared or otherwise publicly known anyway. Everybody gets the right to be represented in the way preferred, which can also be pseudonymous or anonymous, as long as it’s within fair, reasonable limits and not abused (for example, to promote products as the “name” of a natural person or attempts of identity hijacking). It can remain the case that some details (like legal given name) are retained internally if necessary/useful for administrative reasons, only held by OGM and not publicly shared, while the publicly shared entry/representation can be something else, and the connection is maintained via the unique technical identifier (resolved via some lookup/mapping).</p>
<p>This should also involve and invite anybody who wants to help designing proper/better handling of privacy/confidentiality and data protection. The experiment and activity are supposed to be very open and transparent about decisions and concept on request, and remain open for later review + change at any time as long as this data compilation remains in use.</p>
<p>OK, this is just a proposal, no need to freak out, can be scrapped/rejected easily, but on the other hand offers a way of exploring these kind of questions practically and for later use cases. No intention at all to hurt or misrepresent anybody, while on the other hand hinting at what’s publicly shared already or voluntarily disclosed to big data gathering + exploitation companies anyway. So before this project actually starts practically, would love to get some opinions, feedback, ideas first, could also be discussed on a more broader, conceptual level, especially how it relates to the names and people Jerry entered and cross-referenced in his brain. <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-create-a-list-of-ogm-call-participants/93">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-create-a-list-of-ogm-call-participants/93</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 09:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-93</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-create-a-list-of-ogm-call-participants/93.rss">Invitation: Create a list of OGM call participants</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Invitation: Creating summarizing transcripts for the OGM calls</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[skreutzer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Made a quick, rough thing for the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VOvw30-mCM4&amp;list=PLreQNsM8LqWA2ib_Yfkde8m30ANi0WtJr" rel="nofollow noopener">current OGM call</a>: a <a href="https://gitlab.com/skreutzer/open-global-mind-data-repository-experimental/-/raw/master/meeting-recordings-1/ogm-call_20200731_summary.csv?inline=false" rel="nofollow noopener">summarizing transcript (CSV)</a>. It’s supposed to offer a fast overview over the topics covered, and invites to dive in deeper, also allowing to skip other parts or noise.</p>
<p>Did it only for the checkin part. There’s the option now to expand it to the remaining portion of the video recording, using any kind of spreadsheet tool like LibreOffice Calc, maybe Gnumeric works too, or a simple plain-text editor. Even if there are some issues with the file format, I would assume that I can clean it up if needed, and in case of doubt, why not start with just a small portion, share that and see if/how it fits? I don’t think we need to over-engineer/-organize right now to avoid having multiple people doing the same section and therefore unnecessarily duplicating the work, just coordinate in this thread and later there could be great tools and interfaces for such a data capture/input activity, as well as organizing the process.</p>
<p>The main idea here is that such a summarized transcript allows the later extraction/mining of all sorts of data feeds from it, as it’s already very apparent and tangible from this little example.</p>
<p>In terms of the content, please correct or suggest corrections, or indicate if you’re not comfortable with being in the summarized transcript at all or if the representation is misleading (also, preferred name, etc.), would like to grant everybody who participated in the call or is otherwise affected a veto for careful consideration. On the other hand, keep in mind that the recording and the statements therein are public. The summarized transcripts might be licensed in a way which hasn’t been determined yet, as the particular expression is property of the author/contributor by default, says the legislator (might also be in part a database work). No need to freak out about the data collection and mining, usually nobody really cares much or finds these or looks into them. <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> Plus, testing how to go about media literacy/competency.</p>
<p>Want to add that the medium of such synchronous online calls is totally terrible (despite feeling good of course), as there’s no technical structures, semantics or tools that can be applied, and if the topics aren’t super-relevant, it’s most of the time barely worth the effort for investing scarce human lifetime to extract what was buried in there after the fact, for no good reason other than using proper tooling in the first place. Philosophical discussion is quite fine, the coordination of practical projects or data/knowledge management however have to be conducted much better, especially for/at scale. Still, inviting to this activity to get started, which can then bootstrap towards a whole range of potential solutions. Note that I didn’t work from the transcript, that’s more useful as input for automatic processing, which we might want to as well, just separately. The argument for the transcript is usually that it helps finding topics by full-text search, fine, but ideally you would want it already filtered, federated, curated, I would guess.</p>
<p>In case of questions or if help is needed, please just post below. <img src="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
            <p><small>31 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-creating-summarizing-transcripts-for-the-ogm-calls/81">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-creating-summarizing-transcripts-for-the-ogm-calls/81</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 12:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-81</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/invitation-creating-summarizing-transcripts-for-the-ogm-calls/81.rss">Invitation: Creating summarizing transcripts for the OGM calls</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Working group around builder role for data/media curation tooling?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[skreutzer]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi there,</p>
<p>as onboarding seems to be at early stages, please apologize the question: is there already a working group around the builder role, namely software developers and data organizers? Specifically with some dedicated capacity invested/investable into the topic that’s very common with all these online groups regarding how to collect, organize, curate, augment records/recordings or other material?</p>
<p>In parallel, Google/YouTube only supports the <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/legalcode" rel="nofollow noopener">Creative Commons BY 3.0</a> to be selected in the interface, while <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode" rel="nofollow noopener">CC BY-SA 4.0</a> (and/or maybe <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/legalcode" rel="nofollow noopener">3.0</a> too for backwards-compatibility/homogenous-licensing with the Wikipedia for example) would be preferable. Does the choice on YouTube reflect the actual licensing as granted/offered by the creators/participants/license holders who contributed to the meeting recordings? Is there a chance that people potentially agreed to CC BY-SA 4.0 (or 3.0)? Other than that, did attendees before, during or after the meeting declare that they consent to the release of the recording under a particular license? Is there a process in place and consent indicated that people don’t mind the publication, in terms of not seeing their moral rights violated?</p>
<p>Copyright licensing doesn’t need to be a big issue here as the CC BY 3.0 is a free (as in digital user rights, liberty, freedom; not as in price) license if it applies or the recordings of the meetings, but it makes a significant difference in terms of how one reasonably might want to go about it.</p>
            <p><small>9 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/working-group-around-builder-role-for-data-media-curation-tooling/41">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/working-group-around-builder-role-for-data-media-curation-tooling/41</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 07:49:02 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-41</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/working-group-around-builder-role-for-data-media-curation-tooling/41.rss">Working group around builder role for data/media curation tooling?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About the Action! Doing Things Now category</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Action! Doing Things Now</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Many of us have a drive to get things done, now. We’ve been in too many groups that are just thinking and talking, but don’t get stuff done.</p>
<p>What can we do together, now?</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/about-the-action-doing-things-now-category/29">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/about-the-action-doing-things-now-category/29</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 05:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forum.openglobalmind.com-topic-29</guid>
          <source url="https://forum.openglobalmind.com/t/about-the-action-doing-things-now-category/29.rss">About the Action! Doing Things Now category</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
